Eri!
Hurry up and ready the next blast.
It will take time to recharge.
In that case, send out our mobile suits.
Ericht!
Answer me, Ericht!
What do I do?
What do I do?!
Suletta!
Ms. Suletta!
Are you okay?
Mr. Guel... everyone...!
Suletta!
Ms. Suletta!
Suletta! Do you read me?
Suletta!
Pretty gruesome...
What... happened to her?
Spread of information
thermological entropy confirmed.
It has reached the level
where her body is under threat.
Ms. Suletta!
Are you in pain?
How is Ericht?
Till and the others
are checking things out.
No! You can't get up yet!
I have to go...
Ericht is...
That blast just now...
It was probably an interplanetary laser
transmission system at high output.
Which means, it will take time
to recharge for the next blast.
In that case...
I'll go make some tea.
What was that?
What happened to Suletta and the others?
You...
Your body...
Hey, we'd better blow this joint.
Nobody move!
Nika! Chuchu!
I'm here too, you know!
President Miorine... it's over.
You know what to do.
Attention Headquarters!
Any further attacks
are in violation of law!
After violating the principles
of peace between the fronts,
the Benerit Group has no leg to stand on.
As defenders of the fronts,
the Space Assembly League
is acting with cause.
How was Ms. Ericht?
She didn't respond...
The drive systems are all damaged.
That might be why.
Give us ten minutes!
We'll shift Aerial's
propulsion controls to the Calibarn!
We may not be as good as Nika,
but we've spent plenty of time
working on Aerial too, you know.
I...
haven't forgiven you people.
Mr. Lauda?
But...
if you don't come home with my brother,
I'll forgive that even less.
Right.
We'll head straight there.
Right!
The Space Assembly League?
At a time like this?
President Jeturk, please return
to Quiet Zero immediately.
Focus on your duties.
Forgive me...
A wireless optical transmission?
Are you sure?
We have no orders to engage them.
Do you want to get caught
in that thing's line of fire?
A laser transmission system?
It's supposed to be
an infrastructure front,
providing power to Lagrange 1.
I'd heard rumors that
it might be co-opted for military use.
I'll say it one more time.
Hand over Aerial.
Otherwise, your lives will end here.
I told you, didn't I?
Suletta cares about you a lot.
She'll come without being told...
Along with Aerial.
Suletta...
We're here.
Mom...
Suletta!
Ms. Miorine, Ms. Nika!
Everyone!
Thank you, Suletta.
If you reconnect the continuity chord,
Eri will reawaken!
Good...
Now, please connect Eri to Quiet Zero.
What's wrong?
No.
I won't...
hand Ericht to you.
Listen to me, Suletta...
Your mom's body will be paralyzed soon.
I've managed to put on a good act,
but my legs have been useless for a while.
Data storm infection?
Still...
I don't care about any of that.
Eri will gain a world woven by GUND,
and her freedom as well.
All of us can find happiness
in their respective places of being.
Suletta!
If you care about Eri,
you can move forward too, right?
You're wrong, Mom.
I don't want to lose you.
I'm sure Ericht doesn't want
to lose you, either.
So...
who needs...
this Quiet Zero thing!
Stop it, Suletta.
You can't handle it.
Are you... in trouble again?
Mr... Elan?
How?
The organoid archive of
the enhanced humans is integrated here.
I guess that means I'm like her.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Elan, it was my fault that you...
I don't regret dueling with you.
On the contrary, I'm sorry...
that I couldn't meet you like I promised.
No...
It's fine!
Let's begin, Suletta Mercury.
Right!
The data storm?
Please, Ericht!
Answer me!
You're so silly, Suletta.
You can choose for yourself.
You have a place where you belong.
And yet... this is what you want?
I'm...
a greedy person.
There's so much I want to do
with Mom and all of you!
Okay.
Is it Quiet Zero?
No. No signs of attack.
What?
Ms. Miorine!
Suletta?
Quiet Zero is being targeted again!
Everyone, please flee!
You too, Mom!
Don't move.
Not another inch--
We just need to rid the League
of their motives, right?
Lagrange 4!
And all citizens in the region!
Can you hear me?
Ms. Miorine?
I'm the President of the Benerit Group...
Whose voice is that? Cut it off!
...Miorine Rembran.
I can't.
But this is the moon!
The Benerit Group has just submitted
its papers of dissolution and liquidation.
What?
As was the case with Grassley,
all of the group's assets
will be sold to or merged with
Earthian corporations,
per mutual agreement.
In addition...
Dissolution?
we've received evidence that...
For real?
the League's High Council colluded
with Grassley Defense Systems...
How? When did that happen?
...and was complicit
in the recent attacks.
The evidence was received, along with
Shaddiq Zenelli's written confession,
and we promise to make it public!
As always...
I could never compete with you.
Alea iacta est.
Was this at his request?
Who knows...
Shall we go?
Miorine... Rembran!
But that's...
What about our assets?
Looks like she sold every last bit.
You're resigning?!
I guess you could say
I've been headhunted...
I've grown tired of being
on the Peil Grade's leash, anyway.
Buh-bye!
It's not over yet.
That weapon of mass destruction
still stands.
The energy recharge is still underway.
Suletta! Run!
No.
I'll stop them!
The laser transmission system
has been overridden.
The firing phase has been shut down.
Incredible.
She actually exceeded... score eight...
Suletta is the only one
capable of raising Eri's score.
That must be it.
Elnora...
Come home to the children.
Nadeem? How?
It's over.
You made us all proud.
But isn't it still too early
for her to come here?
Just come home.
You've done enough, haven't you?
I can't.
I could never forgive myself.
I lost Nadeem,
Dr. Cardo...
all of you!
If I lose Eri too...
I'm proud of you, Mom.
Suletta...
You called everyone here from Aerial,
didn't you?
For Ericht's sake,
you chose the future over revenge.
Even if everyone objects,
if they say that it's wrong,
your choice...
has my support.
What you... you know...
Mom!
I want to stay with Suletta from now on.
With you too, Mom.
I'm so sorry...
Eri...
Suletta...
What's happening?
The Permet is breaking apart
at the particle level.
Please evacuate.
Quiet Zero...
...disappeared?
Ms... Miorine?
Answer me sooner,
you idiot!
3 years later
Nika!
Welcome back!
How was the certification test?
Congratulations!
I expect nothing less
from our ace mechanic.
You'll have to balance
work and school now.
I'll do my best!
Where's Chuchu?
Rouji!
You changed the specs without asking!
You turdish Spacian geek--
That qualifies as verbal harassment...
What did you say?!
She could have at least
written the location...
Why did you lie?
Plant Quetta was one thing,
but Quiet Zero was not your crime.
I'd decided on my own, long ago.
Are you leaving for Quinharbor?
Yes.
Making up for things
will be hard for both of us.
The trial is about to commence.
I'm off, then.
Thank you, Miorine.
Goodbye.
Are you sure?
About what?
You're not honest with yourself.
Shut up!
I wish you'd listen to
your sister-in-law's advice.
You sure remind me of your mother.
I'll be a tester for GUND-ARM Inc.
starting next week.
I want to be at Petra's side.
I can't rely on my big brother forever.
I see. Well, see you soon.
Mr. Ceres...
I'm grateful that
you'd bring me new business, but...
I helped keep Asticassia open, didn't I?
And I helped you find new jobs
for your employees.
Now it's your turn to listen.
Listen to what, exactly?
I'm the one who drew up the documents.
The division of profits
seems awfully stingy.
Well, you want to rebuild
your company, right?
President Jeturk...
The Benerit Group assets we distributed...
They'll just be scooped up by space again.
I wonder if it was the right move.
There are as many "right moves"
as there are individuals.
We all make mistakes at some point.
But we have to keep doing what we can.
In the future, as well.
You're going to make a school here too?
Yes.
I've gradually regained
control of my body,
and my mom likes it here too.
I don't get what's so great
about living in the countryside.
Well, I don't get how you even exist.
It's not like I do, either.
But...
the one who transferred us
from Aerial that day...
was definitely you, Suletta.
It was something that only you could do.
Suletta!
Miorine!
Everyone!
Let's go home.
Right!
I'm feeling hungry.
Me too.
Episode 24
Illustration: mogmog
Thank you very much for watching the show until the end!