Make me a promise.
That you'll become the next president.
That's impossible.
I could never be president...
Oh?
You just said you won't let me
have my way with Suletta anymore.
Have you given up already?
Damn you!
I'll take over your precious Quiet Zero!
Oh, good.
I'm sure your father will be pleased too.
But you'd better promise me that
you won't involve Suletta any further!
Of course.
But please allow Suletta and Aerial
to take part in one more duel.
One more?
That's right. This will be the last.
After that, you can do
with her as you like.
Still, will that girl...
really give up Aerial so meekly?
Episode 17
G-Good... morning!
Were you waiting all this time?
No! I, uh... just got here.
You're not suspended from school anymore?
No!
Yesterday marked one week.
Yeah?
Well...
I said something weird the other day.
About...
Tell me something.
Yes?
If I asked you to get rid of Aerial,
what would you do?
Huh? I, uh...
I wouldn't do it.
Because Aerial is...
family to me.
Ms. Miorine,
it's almost your birthday, right?
I suppose.
How would you like to celebrate?
My wish list includes
celebrating a friend's birthday.
I want to give it a try...
Plus...
When you turn 17, Ms. Miorine...
We...
I'll think about it.
Benerit Group Front
Because you're negotiating
with the kidnappers,
you now think you're
his successor, Shaddiq Zenelli?
In the upcoming presidential race,
I intend to run on behalf of Grassley.
Which is why I'd like to form
a partnership with Peil Technologies.
You're getting ahead of yourself.
What's in it for us?
I'll support Gundams as a new
core business for the Group.
Gundams?!
I'll transfer GUND-ARM, Inc. to you too.
Since you developed Pharact in secret
violation of the Cathedra Agreement,
this can't be a bad deal for you.
Will we get the Aerial, too?
I'll leave the sales plan to you.
You can enjoy the actual benefits.
And how does Sarius feel about this?
That man would never
accept such an about-face.
The Council won't stay silent either.
I'll bear the brunt of the criticism.
After all,
we're Cathedra's biggest investor.
Besides,
isn't participation in the Gundam business
the thing you most desire?
Sarius won't be back.
Isn't that what you mean?
Ms. Mio--
Mr. Elan?
I have a favor to ask.
You can't come in here!
This is Ms. Miorine's--
Won't you give me Aerial?
Aerial?
Please. You can be my savior.
No!
Why?
You like me, don't you?
In that case...
No!
The way you are now, Mr. Elan...
I don't like you!
Elan this, Elan that...
How irritating.
The man you're thinking of isn't here!
Now...
Hand over Aerial to me, immediate--
Elan!
What are you doing to her?
Look who's here.
It's none other than the runaway prince.
I never could figure you out.
What are you afraid of?
Don't go showing off
just because there's a girl here!
Cut it out.
If you ruin this place,
no apology will get you off the hook.
Th-Thank you very much.
So...
I heard you quit school.
Lauda went behind Dad's back
and held off my withdrawal.
So I was able to re-enroll.
A-About your father...
I am really deeply sorry about his loss!
It's alright. I have a purpose now.
Huh?
I want to rebuild the Jeturk company.
It's the only thing left
that ties me to my father.
Have you heard what's happened to us?
Yes.
At least... I've heard it's bad.
I spoke to Lauda and we decided
I'd take over as president.
The company is on the brink.
It's up to us to do something.
I don't want to lose...
any more of the things precious to me.
Precious... things?
As soon as my re-enrollment is complete,
I'll return to the company.
Before that, I wanted to visit
the school one more time.
I wanted to apologize
to everyone in Jeturk House, too.
Why would you tell this
to someone like me?
"Move forward, gain two."
I... finally understand how frightening
it is to move forward.
It's because I was scared that
I kept running away from my father.
But now I can move forward.
You taught me how.
I...
I d-didn't do...
But still... I'm a little glad.
Because I love those words, too...
I guess that was the part of you
I fell for.
B-But before you said
you didn't like me at all!
That was... How can I put it...
I was embarrassed.
I don't get it at all!
Why?! Figure it out!
I don't get it!
Fine. Then I'll say it again.
I'm grateful to you.
You're precious to me.
Thank you very much.
But...
I'm sorry.
I too...
have someone precious to me now.
I see.
It's nice you have someone
you can say that about.
Yes.
Suletta!
Ms. Miorine!
Th-This is, uh... not what it--
I've decided...
what I want for my birthday.
A duel between you and Guel.
Give me the gift of victory.
What?!
What's the big idea?
Explain yourself, Miorine!
I...
am finished with dueling.
I have a proposal.
I'm going to run
for president of the Benerit Group.
I want you and the Jeturk company
to support me.
Wait a second! Where is this going?
Your company...
You want to rebuild it, right?
I'll become your fiancée.
If that happens, the Group is sure
to fully support the Jeturk company.
So you're telling me to win the duel?
I'm the same as you.
I don't want to lose them...
The things precious to me.
Please, Guel Jeturk.
Reclaim your bride...
from Suletta.
Both parties, deposit
your souls on Libra's scales.
The duelists
are Suletta Mercury and Guel Jeturk.
The location will be
the 13th tactical testing sector.
The one-on-one code will apply.
Are there any objections?
No.
Well, sir... you haven't
quit school after all, huh?
Would you like to extend
your record of losing like a dog?
The Jeturk emblem is the lion.
So call me a lion, not a dog.
Suletta Mercury,
what is your stake in this duel?
Well, um...
Will you help stop
the harassment of Earth House?
Harassment?
Ever since the Open Campus,
everyone in Earth House
has been treated like a criminal.
If the students from Jeturk House
would take our side...
I'll agree.
Guel Jeturk,
what is your stake in this duel?
If I win...
Aerial will be mine.
W-Wait a minute!
What do you want with Aerial, Mr. Guel?
Let him try.
Ms. Miorine?
If you win, it doesn't matter.
You can do that, right?
Yes...
Alea jacta est.
The duel is approved.
I'm sorry.
For what?
About Suletta...
you really did like her, didn't you?
I told her how I feel. Plus...
There are more important things right now.
Speaking of her, is it true?
What you said about her mother...
It's true.
Suletta doesn't question
anything her mother says.
She was only sent to this school
to fight duels in Aerial.
I want that girl to be happy.
She needs a world where she can be
free from Gundams or anything else.
There are no worlds like that.
Huh?
I have one thing to ask.
What is it?
Lend me some scissors and clippers.
Are you really gonna duel like this?
It can't be helped.
It was confiscated during our suspension.
And we have no money for repairs.
Damn it! If only Nika were here!
Now that you mention it,
Ms. Miorine's gone missing too.
Sorry about this.
My work schedule was moved up.
No... it's okay.
Look at this!
Ms. Miorine said it would
be a victory charm!
Stay focused. I'm rooting for you.
I've made the preparations.
Don't you feel sorry for her?
She was rather fired up.
I can't believe you're saying that.
When the time comes,
I'll give you the signal.
Please look forward to it.
Mr. Guel?
What happened to your hair?
It was damaged anyway. You don't like it?
Guel!
I did my best to optimize it,
but what about that AI?
I don't care. Leave it in.
Are you sure?
Pride alone won't defeat Suletta Mercury.
Why didn't you tell me about this?
Sorry. We couldn't find the right timing.
And? How far have you gotten with him?
Lauda...
I'm sorry for everything.
Why apologize?
As your older brother,
I've never done a thing for you.
You can still count on my support.
Just like I told you when we first met.
Connection established
with Carrier Gate No. 2.
Whenever you're ready!
Guel!
Mr. Guel!
Brother...
I'm off.
MS container is authorized to launch.
Let me out!
We will now begin the duel.
As always, victory will go
to the first one to break the blade
antenna of their opponent's mobile suit.
The observer shall be me,
Secelia Dote of Burion House.
A duel?
They say it's the last one.
It's Guel.
It's about to start.
Aren't you gonna watch?
I don't want to see any more fighting.
He's just back home
and already so hot-blooded.
Guel hasn't changed a bit.
No, his objective must be...
The restoration of the Jeturk company.
Is this your doing, Miorine?
No objects in vicinity!
Unlocking MS containers!
KP001, Guel Jeturk...
LP041, Suletta Mercury...
Darilbalde...
Aerial...
Moving out!
Taking off!
Aerial is back in action.
Yes.
Enhanced Person Number Five has failed.
Why are you here?
Don't be so rude.
What's this?
So you're here too, huh?
They were worried about you...
your Earthian friends.
It occurred to me during the Rumble Ring.
"The Gundams and Grassley
must be in cahoots," I thought.
And when I snooped around,
I was right on the money!
I'm not welcome at Peil now.
Since we're all fugitives,
let's be friends.
No thank you.
Why not get in a Gundam and die already?
I'd like to live a long life.
Being killed by you
or dying in a Gundam aren't in my plans.
Dying... in a Gundam?
Both parties, face off.
Victory is never decided
by mobile suit performance, alone.
Nor by the skill of the pilot, alone.
The result itself is the only truth.
13th Tactical Testing Sector
Fix release.
Brother!
I know!
First I have to close the range!
A shield?
Got you!
Brother?
Damn you...
Is something wrong with Guel?
Why won't he shoot?
Heck if I know!
What is it, Brother? Trouble of some kind?
It's nothing.
I'll snap out of it right away.
Delling's daughter... was pleased.
Thank you, Bel.
Not at all...
Isn't Mr. Guel feeling well?
Even so...
Everyone!
Mr. Guel!
Go, Suletta!
Brother!
Mr. Guel!
He blocked it?
Wow!
What was that move?!
Mr. Guel!
You can do it!
Guel! Are you okay?
This thing...
Mr. Guel, you're as strong
as I thought. But...
Aerial!
What the... Override?!
Brother!
I promised.
For Miorine's birthday...
I promised I'd win!
I said I'd stay at her side forever.
Now it's my turn to ask her that.
We'll buy rings together
and have a wedding.
And we'll both wear the very best dresses!
So...
Please choose me!
I'm sorry.
Aerial?
He won!
Yeah!
I believed in you... Brother!
Suletta... lost?
It can't be true.
What do I do, Aerial?
Even though it's Ms. Miorine's birthday...
Even though I promised I'd win...
Ms. Miorine!
Ms. Miorine?
I'm so sorry! I... Aerial...
She stopped moving all of a sudden, and...
I know.
Because it was me who did it.
But... why?
I wanted you to lose.
That's a lie...
I told you from the beginning, didn't I?
This was a trade.
You made a good shield.
But then, you can't fulfill
your obligations if you lose.
Wait!
Please wait!
Mr. Guel! Please duel with me again!
Next time... I won't lose!
So--
I'll take that back too.
Thanks for all your hard work.
Goodbye,
my Mercurian country bumpkin.
Episode 18
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam the Witch from Mercury,
"Our Empty Selves."
Illustration: Takuji Kato