She's founded a company?
For Gundams?
It was Ms. Miorine's own idea!
She solicited investment and
bought out some of Peil's and Shin Sei's
development teams on the spot.
I almost fainted.
Rich girls do everything flashier.
She must have an ulterior motive.
Four.
Doubt.
How did you know?!
Ms. Suletta's been having trouble
ever since she transferred here.
You will have trouble
with men in the near future.
What?! That's the last thing I need!
Shouldn't we just let her do as she likes?
It's got nothing to do with me.
It's got plenty to do with you.
Ms. Miorine?
What'd you bring the Princess here for?
I'm setting up the company here.
What?
GUND-ARM, Inc. will be run
by me and everyone here.
That's it. You're welcome.
Huh?
Say what?!
Now the company's launched,
there's a ton of things to do.
D-Don't talk like we've agreed to this!
And why us, any--
You'll be properly paid.
Any other questions? None, right?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I apologize for whatever
Ms. Miorine's doing.
What will your company
be doing with Gundams, anyway?
That's...
what I'm about to figure out.
That Spacian turd!
Chuchu, class is in session.
Are you okay with this, Nika?!
Why do we need to obey her?!
Huh?
Well, if it means
I get to work on Aerial...
And if the company is successful,
it's a chance to prove that
Earthians can do as well as Spacians.
Well, I'm not gonna wait on
some selfish Spacian bimbo!
It's breaking!
Are you okay with this, Nuno?!
Well...
It depends on the salary.
If it's mighty, I won't complain.
If it's meager, I'll slack off.
No, no, no, no!
We're talking Gundams! And witches!
They're all cursed!
You want to learn about business, right?
Isn't this perfect?
It's a perfect disaster!
The group's big shots are--
Martin Upmont!
Yes, sir!
If you can't be quiet, leave!
I'm very sorry!
Count me out.
And what do you think?
Depends on what we'd be doing.
Ms. Aliya! Mr. Till!
Do you have any clue where Ms. Miorine is?
You want to know more about Aerial?
Our company will be handling
Gundams, so I have a lot of questions.
Is Ariel really safe?
Can she be mass-produced?
And why develop her when you
had to hide that she was a Gundam?
I just sent you all of Ariel's past data.
People who want Gundams
will trust numbers
over your words or mine.
Thank you.
Anyway, mass production
is impossible at this point.
We haven't pinned down
the basic elements of the GUND Format,
and aren't ready to accumulate data.
You'll have to begin with analysis.
The Gundam's curse
is a heavier burden than you think.
So that's what he meant.
Um, Mom?
What is it?
Well, um...
Why did you...
say to me...
that Aerial wasn't a Gundam?
Aerial is family to us, right?
She's not really cursed, is she?
Does it frighten you?
No.
It's your arm, Mom. Same as always.
Thank you. But even so,
people can't help being afraid
of the unknown.
And they try to
keep that fear at a distance.
Or even attack it.
Gundams will remain in
people's minds as forbidden machines.
Even so, I wanted to protect you two
from the curse's abominable flame.
Mom...
So that's it.
It was all for us, right?
But of course!
You're my beloved daughters.
I'm sorry for my silly question!
From now on, I'll protect Aerial too.
For your sake, Mom!
Be sure to tell everyone.
It's safe to have Gundams by their side.
Right!
Anyway... Wasn't there something
more important to ask your mother?
Huh?
Like why you're able to pilot Aerial
without suffering any harm.
Now you know she's a Gundam...
aren't you scared?
Not at all!
Aerial and I have always been family!
Have it your way...
Oh, Mercurian Miss.
Did you make up with your mother?
Yes!
In fact, I--
Suletta.
Don't tell that creep a thing.
You're mad again?
You don't want me
getting close to your groom?
You only want to know more about
Aerial for your company's sake.
And what about your company?
You have absolutely no time to sit back.
You managed to make it through there,
but your investors aren't philanthropists.
Depending on your business plan,
you might go back to zero.
What are you trying to say?
Why not let me take over the company?
What?
On what terms?
Marriage to you.
What?! M-M...
Oh, shut up.
M-M-Marriage?!
This ship will now...
Let's discuss this again soon.
...enter a docking course.
Bye now, Mercurian Miss.
Uh... I...
Please be seated and fasten your...
I-I think I get it. It's you, Ms. Miorine!
We will now enter...
...a docking course.
Shaddiq is...
Please fasten your seatbelts.
in l-l-l-love with...
Don't kid yourself.
What?
It's just that he...
was raised in an orphanage
run by the Grassley family.
What?
That guy will do whatever it takes.
Don't let your guard down.
Right...
As President Miorine instructed,
I've organized the disclosure
information for the investors.
You've accepted your fate already?
Putting aside minor registrations,
there are a lot of things
we have to decide.
Like salary, wages, bonuses, and raises.
They're all money matters, huh?
Those things are important too, but...
We have to start
with articles of incorporation.
Articles?
They're documents that establish
the nature of the company.
The company's name, its founders,
the total number of authorized shares...
The specifics will be written
in the company's business plan, but...
We have to decide
the company's mission, right?
Whatever it is,
it should be something profitable.
From what Suletta's mom said,
unless the GUND Format's safety is proven,
we won't be able to manufacture Gundams.
What about Peil's Gundam?
I think they called it...
Pharact.
Did it use technology
different from Aerial's?
We can't say without looking into it.
According to the documents
we received from Peil,
the cost of building one Pharact unit was...
This much.
Are you serious?
How many units of my mobile suit
could you buy with that?
After buying out Shin Sei's and Peil's
development teams,
what are the company's assets?
This much.
Are you serious?
That's not even enough
to feed Giko and the others.
Manufacturing is far beyond
our dreams at this point.
Let's just make a rosy business plan
to raise everyone's expectations.
Then people will come to finance us.
What are we gonna sell, then?
Right...
Normally, selling them as weapons
would seem the most reasonable plan.
Yeah, that would be
the natural thing to do.
Huh?
What? It would make money, wouldn't it?
You're a war orphan, aren't you?
There are tons of kids like me on Earth.
If we're only selling
to Earthians, I'm for it.
But that would mean...
Earth would become a battlefield again.
I don't want that.
Hold on a second.
In the first place, selling only
to Earthians isn't even realistic.
We're a part of the Benerit Group, after all.
What?!
Are you siding with the Spacians?
That's not what I mean.
I didn't come here to build mobile suits.
I love money, for sure.
Even so, I don't feel like
profiting off killing machines.
At the end of the day,
you're just another spoiled kid.
Oh, yeah?!
E-Everyone!
We can't fight like this!
She's right. Calm down.
What about you, Nika?
Huh?
If Spacians do as they please
with the mobile suits we build,
could you handle it?
I...
The one who decides...
should be the president.
What?
Ms. Miorine...
Who cares if we sell weapons?
If you don't like it, you're free to go.
N-No way! We're all in this together!
Huh? It's my company, you know.
If that's how it is,
you're the one who should leave.
What are you...?
Fine.
Ms. Miorine!
Martin!
Y-Yes?
I'll leave the details of the
registration papers to you.
Lilique, you'll open the company's
bank account.
And help Martin with the rest.
Yes, ma'am.
Right.
Is anyone here a decent artist?
Design us a company logo. Make it stylish.
Suletta... and the rest...
Don't lump us together!
Make a PR video that will
rid Gundams of their bad image.
You've got two weeks.
Two weeks?!
Nail down everything before
my lousy father changes his mind.
Don't slack off!
That bossy little Spacian turd!
Oh, sorry.
I thought this was a garbage dump.
Come on.
You're not making this fun.
Picking up litter?
How noble.
I'll pick up where you left off.
Sure...
Sorry for the trouble.
Come to our House.
You can shower there.
I won't lick the boots of a wimp
who was afraid to duel me.
I only avoided it because
I thought I could leave it to you.
What?
Call me if you change your mind.
I happen to be...
quite fond of you.
I don't need anyone's pity!
Yes?
I sent you some Beguir-Pentes
and a Michaelis.
They're bringing anti-Gundam weapons too.
I've no intention of seizing it in a duel.
Do it whatever way you like.
But don't forget.
The Gundams must be erased
from this world.
Yes, Father.
He's far too narrow.
In his vision...
and his ideas.
And our Cathedra shall deny all Gundams.
Gundam...
A mobile suit that kills its pilot.
The GUND Format...
I have to know more.
As soon as your company is ready,
Peil's development team and the Pharact
will be officially transferred to you.
I look forward to working with you,
Ms. Belmeria Winston.
Now, then...
What brings you here today?
I want to learn more about Gundams.
Mobile suits called Gundams that
cripple their pilots' minds and bodies...
the Vanadis Institute that created them...
and the people we call witches
are all to be abhorred.
That's what the public believes.
If they were defective,
they could have been improved.
So why did they reject that...
and try to eliminate them
by concocting that agreement?
And why did the witches
create the Gundams in the first place?
Don't.
Don't call them "witches."
Does that mean you're a witch too?
I was merely...
enthralled by the GUND's ideals...
and have simply
been imitating what they did.
The GUND's ideals...?
Can you tell me more about that?
So you can't help hanging
around this place after all.
Did you know about
the ideals behind GUND technology?
My father told me most of it.
He trusts you, then.
I worked hard to earn it.
And? Who are you groveling to today?
I came to grovel to you.
There are customers who want Gundams.
If you can develop a machine
equal in strength to the Aerial
that outperformed
Jeturk's and Peil's mobile suits,
many buyers would want to obtain it
even without Cathedra's approval.
And I'm sure you're aware of
our monetary situation.
Why don't we work together?
Not only can I give you financial
support until you're on your feet,
I can lend you any personnel you need.
Doesn't sound too bad, right?
And what's in it for you?
Gundams are a game changer that will
revitalize the stagnant weapons industry.
The group will never grow
further if it misses this chance.
Isn't your Daddy allergic to Gundams?
I'll bring him around.
I regard it as my filial duty.
Back in the day,
we submitted a project plan together
in a business competition.
A secret from everyone...
I don't remember a thing.
The plan was accepted,
but our fathers found out and scolded us.
Still, I haven't forgotten that day.
If you and I work together,
I believe we can bring about
a better future than our fathers.
Miorine.
There. You can clearly see
where it's been edited.
Mr. Martin, there are mistakes here.
Aw, man...
Come on, you two!
Hurry up and bury the hatchet!
And where's the Princess, huh?
The two weeks are up.
I'll bet she got fed up
and ran away to Earth.
M-Ms. Miorine wouldn't...
She wouldn't do that!
You haven't known her
long enough to say for sure.
Looking for me?
Ms. Miorine!
I-I believed in you...
Ms. Miorine--
You're annoying.
And?
Have you decided?
How we're going to sell the Gundams.
There are two ways to earn revenue.
The first is to sell Gundams as weapons.
In that case, we'll ask no
questions about who we sell to.
And the other option...
Good afternoon, Spacians.
We are the staff of Vanadis,
an institute for Permet research.
Almost a century has passed
What the hell is this video?
since we expanded our biosphere into space.
Who is she?
And we humans...
The one who created the Gundams.
...have always struggled to
survive the harsh space environment.
Weightlessness, vacuum,
atmospheric composition,
space radiation...
Even with expensive
vaccines and implant apps,
we can barely suppress
the disorders themselves.
Which is why the GUND medical technology
that we're proposing
could be a technology of hope
for supplementing the fragility
of the human body.
GUND medical technology?
GUND technology has the potential
not only to expand the biosphere,
but also to reconcile
the divisions and disparities
between the people of Earth and space.
We hope you will join us in
grasping hold of this ray of light
that could lead to a better
future for all humanity.
This is the other way.
Pursuing the true ideals behind the Gundam...
we'll complete the GUND medical
technology and send it out into the world.
But that means...
Using Gundams to save lives?
A mobile suit...
that saves lives...
I don't know if the world
will accept it or not. However...
it's worth a try.
First of all, it's great to take
a different path from my lousy father.
I'll take on all responsibility.
Any objections?
GUND-ARM... GUND-ARM...
A ray of hope
Forward to the future
It's safe... to pilot!
It's reliable... to use!
It can fly! It can dance! Aerial!
GUND-ARM, Inc.
is dedicated to the medical use
of GUND technology.
We've finished drafting the business plan
for investors and streaming the PR video.
The articles of incorporation
and various applications are done.
Once the school accepts
our application for a student startup,
the company will be officially established.
Thank you all for your hard work!
I'm really tired.
All we did was help with the video, though.
A medical company
that handles GUND technology.
It's better than being complicit in war.
There's no good or evil
when it comes to saving lives.
Right?
I guess.
Thank you, Chuchu.
In my hometown...
there are lots of people who lost
their arms and legs in mining accidents.
If I can make money and be useful
to my family, there's nothing better.
And so...
has the food
for the launch party arrived yet?
Thank you very much, Ms. Miorine.
For what?
You worked out a plan
acceptable to everyone, didn't you?
I just couldn't afford to lose them.
To tell the truth... this is kind of fun.
It's like joining a club,
just like my wish list.
Idiot. This isn't for amusement.
Stop here!
Huh?
Ms. Miorine?
What the hell is this?!
As directed, I've added new regulations.
Article 53, paragraph 3 of the Student
Business Startup Regulations...
"Safety verification of new technology
used in student businesses."
Miorine can't start her company now.
The Gundam will revert
to being group property.
Now Mr. Sarius just has to dispose of it.
I feel kind of sorry for Miss Miorine.
Don't worry.
We can all help cheer her up.
I won't let him dispose of it.
The Gundam will eventually be needed
by myself and the group.
I'll be taking over Miorine's company.
And if she refuses?
There's only one solution, right?
Though I doubt that's what Shaddiq wants.
But we're prepared for what comes next.
We'll simply seize the Gundam...
from Miorine's hands.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"If I Could Take One Step Toward You."