Fighting is currently escalating
in the eastern part of the city,
as Benerit Group mobile suits
open fire on housing complexes...
Spacian bastards...
You take from me again...!
It's all my fault.
I...
did this.
Hurry, dammit!
That jerk...
We're gonna arrest Shaddiq!
Calm down!
Just as President Miorine said,
the first step is to reach Asticassia
and secure President Sarius!
We still have no evidence that
Shaddiq Zenelli is the ringleader.
You mustn't get ahead of yourself!
Shaddiq...
I'll never forgive you for this.
Henao, contact the Space Assembly League.
It's time to move my father.
Roger.
I told you we should make the first move!
Renee! Don't misunderstand our objectives.
You were so close to making it.
I've gotta hand it to Miss Miorine.
No, this wasn't Miorine.
Shaddiq, are you angry?
Guel...
Where are you now?
What's the Aerial doing on Earth?
Who's piloting it?
From this image data, it looks like
GUND-Bits are controlling nearby machines,
but the Aerial's GUND-Bits themselves--
D-Don't ask me!
We're as surprised as you!
You're useless. Why are you here then?
I-I'd like to report...
I patched things up with everyone.
Please answer my questions.
How many complaints do we have now?
I've lost count.
Our mobile suit wreaked havoc while
we claim to be a medical company...
It's no wonder.
Well, if we can't see,
we can't reply to them.
Leave it to the President!
I don't care anymore!
Even Lilique is mad...
What happens to the company now?
Should we be good and go to class?
Like her...
It cannot be denied that concern
for pilot life support was extremely low
in the early years of space development.
In the view of historians,
humanity's advancement into space
was fairly hasty and aggressive.
And the loss of so many lives...
None of that was in today's lecture.
If you attend class
but don't bother to listen...
what's the point?
It's the only thing...
I can think of doing.
This is today's portion.
The Rumble Ring...
If you hadn't been there,
Mr. Lauda might have died.
If that happened... I don't know
what would become of me.
Are you in love with Mr. Lauda?
There! You always get on
everyone's nerves like that!
Brother!
Lauda! Where's the Darilbalde?
It's here with me.
But why bring a mobile suit off-campus?
And what's that other one
I saw at the company--
Permet ID codes detected.
Five of them.
Mobile suits belonging to Grassley.
What business do Cathedra forces have
at our school?
Well, you see...
we received certain information...
and we'd like you
to allow us to enter the campus.
In that case, we'll handle it for you.
Please explain the details.
Why is Shaddiq...?
Brother!
Shaddiq!
Where are you hiding President Sarius?!
Weren't you told to secure your target
before you're suspected?
It's because you're so rash...
that Miorine has...!
Come any closer, and I'll open fire!
You're the one who started this!
Did you remove the regulation program?!
Damn it...
he played right into his hands.
Let's move out!
Copy that!
We won't let you get in Shaddiq's way.
Time to show us how much better
you are than the school boys!
Shaddiq?
It's fine.
Henao...
I've secured him.
What about the other three?
Let them go.
We have no more reason to hide them.
But we'll use the witch
for as long as we can.
This is Kenanji Avery, a commander
in Cathedra's Dominicus force.
All students, stay where you are.
These tremors... is it a mobile suit?
The door opened?
That fool!
Thorn!
Norea!
Don't do it, Norea!
Why pilot a Gundam again?
It's none of your business!
If you're afraid to die, then run!
Run... and then what?
Because of you Spacians' brutality,
everyone I knew is dead!
Not even Naji... or Olcott...
and especially not you...
could ever understand...
our anger that our lives
are cheaper than Spacians'!
Sophie... let's demolish it.
The entire school... and everything else!
Reinforcements? From Grassley?
Begone... begone... begone...
All of this... disappear!
It's a Gundam?!
Gundvolvas!
Hey... aren't those...
The ones from the Open Campus...
You don't think... it's Norea?!
My Demi Tray!
The surface is dangerous...
Get underground!
Idiot! Get moving!
What are you doing? Do you want to die?
I-I'm sorry!
This is the worst...
It's all because Mr. Lauda
stood me up on our date.
Am I right?
R-Right!
An apology won't be enough.
He's gonna take me wherever I ask!
He owes me a lunch and a dinner!
I won't be able to
rest in peace, otherwise.
What about you?
What will you do if you survive?
I definitely...
want to be at his side again!
This is a message to the entire front.
Terrorist mobile suits have appeared
in the campus area!
Send backup!
You Witch Hunters are has-beens!
I've had enough of you Gundams!
Were you the one
who guided the Dawn of Fold?
Yes.
And the one who set my dad up?
And the one who blamed it all
on the Jeturk Company?!
That's right.
Your father approached us with a plan
to assassinate Delling...
and I used it to my advantage!
Factional in-fighting and intrigues...
He was a shallow man
with nothing else on his mind.
A man like that...
Don't you dare insult my father!
But weren't you the one who killed...
that father?
My brother...
killed Dad?
A Level 5 alert has been issued
for all sectors of the school front.
The lives of students and staff
are under direct threat,
and the situation is extremely dangerous.
Except for security control personnel,
act immediately as per
the emergency evacuation manual
and please prioritize
your own physical safety.
We're using the catapult at Gate 7!
Any nearby students, stay clear!
Mr. Lauda... Petra...
where have they gone?
Felsi!
That thing's configured for campus use.
Don't go out too far!
Right!
It's up to me.
Felsi Rollo... moving out!
A Level 5 alert has been issued
for all sectors of the school front...
Norea... why would you do this?
Aliya! Lilique!
Martin...
Is everyone okay?!
We haven't found Suletta yet.
Damn it! If I had my Demi Tray...
It's no good! You couldn't sortie now!
We can't hide in here forever either!
I don't want you to die, Chuchu!
Well, at this rate,
it's a bad ending for all of us.
No way...
So I guess...
we should loan you our machine.
MSJ-R122... Demi Barding.
It's Burion's new prototype.
We brought it here for testing, but...
None of us is a pilot,
so letting that Pom-Pom Head use it
gives us some chance of survival, right?
Come on. Hurry up and fine-tune it.
Fine-tune? But...
Chuchu's machine is always tuned by...
Nika?
And there she is!
Just the person we need.
Everyone...
Nika, you have to
calibrate this right away.
What?
Can we talk to each other one more time?
Right.
Come on, come on!
Come on!
The power output is different,
but the controls
should feel the same as always.
I'm sorry, Chuchu... this is all my fault.
That you have to go and fight too...
How can I forgive you?
Tell me everything from A to Z.
Otherwise, there's nothing to forgive.
Yeah...
Th-This is bad...
At this rate...
Hey, Spacian!
Y-You! Is that Pom-Pom Head?
Help me out. We're gonna smash them all!
I ain't taking orders from an Earthian!
You pathetic students!
Sabina! Go!
Help Shaddiq!
We've saved the best part for you!
Thanks.
If you'd acted more wisely,
your father wouldn't have died.
If you'd never come back...
I could have dissolved
the Group peacefully!
Despite your being with her...
you let Miorine's hands get dirty!
To hell with a traitor who
collaborated with terrorists!
And who turned me into that?
The ones who stole everything
through war partitioning...
Who forced us to survive
at the expense of others...
It was all of you!
Without power, there's no way
to break this unjust peace.
No way to even resist it....
That's why this time, I'll take the power
from you Spacians myself!
I... am ready to accept my own sins!
I've got President Sarius aboard the ship.
If you can buy 5 more minutes...
we can leave for our rendezvous point
with the Assembly League.
I see.
I know what you mean...
You and I... each have to
bear our own sins by ourselves.
But even so... you'll pay for yours here!
Shaddiq!
Charging straight in...
That's the very thing
I've always hated about you!
Sabina!
Guel Jeturk, you'll never understand.
You grew up
with a silver spoon in your mouth!
You're the one who doesn't understand.
Guel!
If all you do is take...
you'll never gain a thing!
Shaddiq!
I'll never forgive you.
But I'm not about to let you die, either.
To maintain order, the Benerit Group
sacrificed fellow Spacians at the school.
The Assembly League wouldn't act
just because of Earthian losses...
but they'll finally get off
their butts now.
Oh, my foolish son...
I'll destroy it all!
Every last thing you call yours!
Norea!
That's enough. Don't be in a rush to die!
And what do you get with all your running?
You only hold your breath
and avert your eyes!
That's no different from being dead!
Sophie was alive! You're nothing like her!
Obviously. But you're not Sophie either!
Those drawings in your sketchbook...
That's the real you!
Anxious... terrified of death...
Scribbling was your only escape!
How would you know--
Come with me!
If you don't know how to live,
I'll search for that with you.
If you're scared, I'll be at your side!
If you don't want to run,
take me to the places in your drawings!
The rest can come later!
We're allowed to live...
Let me prove it!
They stopped?
Have they turned on each other?
With you...
You say, "come with me..."
then "take me there..."
Are you stupid or something?
Norea!
Tell me later...
your...
real name--
Damn it...
Get out of my way!
Ow, that hurt...
Ms. Petra? Ms. Petra!
Episode 20
This isn't a dream, is it?
It's real. All of it.
Tiko?
Ms. Suletta!
Thank goodness. You're alright!
Suletta, I--
I'm sorry...
Can you help?
There are people stuck inside.
Still... so many...
But there may be some
who can still be saved.
Let's do it, everyone!
I'll go find a working mobile craft.
We'll need first aid too, right?
We'll split up and save them!
Right!
Next time,
Episode 21
"What We Can Do Now."
Illustration: Rolua