This is my fight!
It's mine.
Only mine!
Aerial and I won't lose!
There's still so much left on my wish list!
SULETTA MERCURY WINS
Suletta Mercury...
Will you...
marry me?
What?
Huh?
Now this is entertaining.
What are you...
Brother, what nonsense is this?
M-M-Marry you?
Wait, not like that!
No way!
What?
Heat and substances...
... hazardous to humans detected.
Turn that camera off!
Please evacuate.
This is the first time...
I've seen someone propose!
First rejection I've seen, too.
Ridiculous.
Chuchu?
So this was all a lovers' quarrel?
These Spacians must lead carefree lives.
And? Can we expect your son to recover
his status as heir to the Benerit Group?
Mr. Jeturk.
Please. It's beyond question.
Well, he has lost twice.
And to the child of a miner from Mercury!
If we don't see results soon,
we'll have to cut back on your funding.
We'll discuss that another time.
That will be all.
Damn it!
That witch...
What's with that uniform?
I-Is there something wrong with it?
Hand me your student notebook.
The Holder has a special uniform
as well as a unique pilot suit.
You should realize who you are now.
You're the reigning Holder
and my bridegroom.
Ms. Mercury!
Yes?
What are your intentions with Mr. Guel?
What?
Why did you turn down his proposal?
How long have you two been involved?
Well...
You could get into a rich family!
It's such a waste!
Yes!
Well...
You're in my way.
Move.
Excuse us!
We're so sorry!
About our duel...
I-I-I said no!
Don't be so gullible.
Huh?
Did you really think I'd fall for some
tousle-haired country bumpkin?
Wh-What?
Did you come here just to say that?
Just you wait, Mercurian wench.
Miorine Rembran, for my
boorish behavior the other day
and for damaging your greenhouse,
I hereby apologize.
Is this because of the duel?
The terms of the duel must be honored.
Those are the rules of the Asticassia School.
Guel Jeturk! Are you finished?
I'm sorry, sir. I'm leaving now.
Don't get the wrong idea.
I don't like you at all!
I don't get him!
Next! KP033, Reiko Hamlet. Start!
Optical images will be restricted
to the visible spectrum.
All other sensors are to be turned off.
Use ground-penetrating radar to
locate the simulated land mines.
Land mine 15 meters ahead.
Go around it at two o'clock!
Roger!
Exchanging weapons!
Confirming link to targeting systems.
Auto correction, all green.
Weapon exchange completed!
Next! LP041. Suletta Mercury.
Y-Yes!
Fail!
Wh-Why?
How do you intend to clear the exercise
without a mechanic or spotter?
Mecha...? Spot...?
Recruiting team members
is part of your assignment.
H-How do I...
34 degrees left...
...in two seconds.
Just ask around at your House!
LP029. Olta Shubacca. Pass.
My House?
If you understand,
then clear the starting position!
What is she doing?
Chuchu, I'm ready.
Thank you, Nika.
I'll clear it in two minutes!
Next, MP039. Chuatury Panlunch!
Start!
Alright!
Chuchu, 20 degrees to the left.
Roger, Nuno!
Three steps ahead, 15 degrees to the right.
Roger!
This is easy!
What the...
What's wrong, Chuchu?
My monitor suddenly went black!
Not good! Halt there!
Chuatury Panlunch, fail.
What a joke!
Earthians are such an eyesore.
They should just stay holed up on Earth.
Slow-acting masking spray?
Screw you all! Who did this, huh?
I'll tear them limb from limb!
The makeup exam is in three days.
Chuchu just can't keep her cool.
It's the pranksters who are to blame!
Forgive me. I don't want
to make enemies in Jeturk House.
Ms. Suletta!
Ms. Nika!
What are you doing here?
Um... I'm looking
for a mechanic and spotter.
Oh, for the makeup exam?
Ms. Nika, you're in mechanics.
C-Can I ask you?
You know we're Earthians, don't you?
That means you were born on Earth, right?
I'm not talking about what the word means...
I'm sorry. I have to help
my junior with her makeup exam.
I see...
I can't help you myself,
but I can introduce you to some people.
Bad boy, Giko.
Ms. Nika, is this who you're introducing...
Sorry! Not that way. Over here.
Everyone! Do you have a moment?
Hey, that uniform...
She's the Holder.
Nika, what is she doing here?
This is Ms. Suletta Mercury.
She's having trouble finding
staff for the exercise.
Can't you help her?
You're okay with that, Nika?
Isn't she a Spacian?
Ms. Suletta's not like the other Spacians.
She doesn't look down on us!
If you need a spotter...
Th-Thank you very much!
I'm Lilique Kadoka Lipati, first year.
My name's Martin Upmont.
I'm the House leader.
I'm Aliya.
This quiet guy is Till.
I spoke just now.
Ojelo, Nuno. You guys too.
What?
But I...
What the heck is a Spacian doing here?
Chuchu!
Oh no!
This is Earth House!
Get out!
Calm down!
Let me go!
Stop it, now!
I-I'm sorry!
Chuchu!
Don't ever come in here again!
You Spacian turd!
I'm sorry, Brother.
I hoped it would be enough
just to strip you of ace pilot status.
But he's taking away the Darilbalde too.
Don't let it bother you.
You have no choice but to obey Dad's orders.
Brother,
it's best not to anger Dad any further.
I know.
What do I do now?
I'll never pass the exam at this rate.
Fretting again?
Mr. Elan?
H-H-How did you know?
You're far too easy to read.
This exam is something I can't do on my own.
But no one will help me.
Come to our House, then.
What?
Is that a bother?
N-N-N-Not at all! I'm glad!
Are you sure it's okay?
It's not okay!
Ms. Miorine?
That man is an enemy!
Enemy?
The members of the three branches
only care about getting their hands on me.
This jerk is after me, too.
I couldn't be less interested.
Oh yeah?! I wouldn't care for
a dummy prince like you, either!
H-How could you say that?
What?
Mr. Elan invited me to his House.
H-He's gentle, kind and very...
What are you talking about?
She's recruiting team members for her exam.
In that case, forget him.
Why don't you ask me?
Come in.
Ms. Miorine, you live in a schoolroom?
This used to be the Chairman's office.
I took it over from my father.
Then what about your House?
I don't belong to one.
It's no good!
I need a mechanic and a spotter.
I can take care of both by myself.
What? Aren't you majoring
in management strategy?
I've learned enough.
Already?
Exercise support doesn't require
more than memorizing the manual.
Th-That's amazing!
W-Well then, can you teach me about this?
"Mobile Heavy Machinery Principles"?
This is just the basics.
I'd say you have more cause
for concern than I do.
I'll do my best.
We Earth residents have devoted
nearly a century's worth of taxes and labor
to the pursuit of space industry!
And yet the Spacians haven't given us...
Withdraw the AR units to the picket line.
...any economic compensation,
just poverty and a food crisis!
Mobile suit teams are authorized
to use gas shells.
Worse, they have even...
Look out!
Begin advance.
Suppress and apprehend them.
Yesterday, business administrative laws
were enforced against an illegal occupation.
Eight leading agitators were arrested
and multiple weapons were confiscated.
What the heck is wrong with
Earthians using Earthian factories?
It can't be helped.
All the major media companies
rely on Spacian capital.
They think Earthians should just shut up
and work without proper benefits.
Hey, where's Chuchu?
Chuchu!
How's everything?
Are they feeding you?
You can't all talk at once.
How's school, Chuatury?
Have those Spacians given you any trouble?
Nothing I can't handle.
Just yesterday, I fought off
a gang of them who tried to mouth off.
Oh, really?
That's our Chuchu!
But let's talk about what I saw in the news.
Don't worry about us.
Just work hard on your studies.
Show them what craft operators can do!
Thank you, everyone.
Aren't you going to sleep?
Oh, I'm sorry. It's just that
I'm behind on my studies.
Tell me something. Why do you work so hard?
I have a dream.
I want to found a school at Mercury.
A school? Doesn't Mercury have any?
There used to be some,
but there are so few people now...
Sure. These days, we can mine
for Permet on the Moon as well.
That's why I thought of the school.
To get young people to come to Mercury.
The people at Mercury
were so happy with my idea.
They said they were
counting on me and waiting.
They even gave me
good luck charms and messages.
What a drag!
Huh?
Why do you have to carry that burden?
You should live for yourself.
But this is what I want to do.
How admirable of you.
Not at all. I...
Good night.
Listen up. I'm an amateur at this
and performing two roles.
It's your job to clear the assignment.
Right!
If the Princess is helping you,
why'd you come to our House?!
Spacian turd.
Chuchu, I explained to you...
You're from Earth House?
Got a problem with that?
You call us turds,
just because we're Spacians?
Then you're no different from those
who discriminate against Earthians.
Why you...
Chuchu!
P-Please, stop!
We will now begin the makeup exam.
Students, board your Demi Trainers
and assemble at the designated point.
LP041, Suletta Mercury! Start!
Yes, sir!
Calculating soil conditions.
Ahead, 5 degrees to the right.
There appears to be
a land mine 30 meters ahead.
Yes!
NO DETECTION
MINE DETECTION MODE
Response from 18 meters ahead
at 10 degrees. Turn right.
Got it!
Stay on that course.
Be careful of changes in terrain.
Right!
What?
Hey! Why did you halt?
For some reason,
the main sight has gone pitch black!
Pitch black?
Yay!
Those girls...
Sir, we're experiencing machine trouble.
Please suspend the exam.
Absolutely not.
Advance inspection is part of the assignment.
Suletta! Use your instrument readings
to figure out the direction.
I'll guide you to the exchange area.
Y-Yes!
There's a land mine 20 meters to your left.
Proceed right.
To the right?
Time's up.
Suletta Mercury, fail.
Please allow us to retry.
Ms. Miorine?
Students can retry a makeup exam.
Don't give up!
G-Got it!
The land mines have changed position.
Find a route to the right.
Okay!
The autonomous altitude control
will balance your machine.
Don't worry unnecessarily.
Yes!
Nuno, is there nothing we can do?
That slow-acting masking spray
can't be removed easily.
You saw what happened to Chuchu.
Stop! You've gone too far!
Suletta Mercury, fail.
Please allow us to retry!
She can't pull it off when she's blind.
We're improving our time, though!
Keep going, straight ahead until you hit it!
You help, too!
What?
Get ready to exchange weapons.
Stand up and raise your right arm.
Link with targeting system confirmed.
Auto correction, all green.
Go!
Time's up.
Suletta Mercury, fail.
Suletta! Let's do it again!
Return to the starting position!
Hey, Princess!
How many times are you going to retry?
I can't even start my test.
Retries are permitted, aren't they?
Pipe down and wait your turn.
Enough... I want to go home.
Suletta?
I was actually afraid
to come to school alone.
I don't want to duel either.
I don't want to stand out!
As I am now...
I'll never graduate!
Get up, Suletta!
Aren't you gonna found a school?!
Aren't people counting on you?!
Everyone at Mercury saw you off, right?
They gave you good-luck charms!
Are you just going to give up?
But I can't do it!
This was your decision!
Go back and stand at the starting position!
Some Holder she is!
Country bumpkins should rot away at home.
You're not carrying anyone
else's hopes and dreams...
It's cheap of you to interfere!
That fool!
Hold it, Suletta! That girl
from Earth House is picking a fight.
Get off me!
So you want to play dirty, huh?
Chuchu!
Earthians should crawl on the ground
like the underlings you are!
Spacian turd!
No one wants you here!
Stop it!
And? What were the results?
Oh, well...
Another makeup exam.
But how come I have to do it too?
This is your fault, you know.
I-I'm sorry.
Still, that felt pretty good!
What?
Hey, Ms. Suletta!
Would you like to join Earth House?
Huh?
Nika!
Nika, that's...
B-B-But...
What?!
Well, I may be a first-year student.
But in House terms, I'll be your senior.
R-Right.
Um...
Her name's Chuchu.
I-I look forward to getting
to know you, Ms. Chuchu.
Speak up.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"Reflection in an Icy Eye."