All fleets are reporting...
their designation systems
via Permet links are all green.
Commence attack.
Enormous Lorentz force detected.
Unable to confirm trajectory.
Switch to guided missiles.
They've been overridden.
We can't control them!
All ships, ready missile defenses!
Contact lost with Almeida
from the second fleet.
One-third of the ships
in the third fleet are inoperable.
We'll retreat.
It'll take some time to reactivate
the Permet reactor.
Thank you, Eri...
Miorine, it's me.
I'll come back.
Episode 22
You want to borrow the Demi Barding again?
Please! I'm begging you!
Sure.
Really?!
But if you break it, it'll cost you.
W-We could never pay that!
It's for Suletta's sake! Don't wuss out!
One more thing.
Can you take Rouji with you?
I'm pretty curious...
about this.
Here. This is the list
of animal care tasks.
All this in one day?
This is longer than a mobile craft manual.
It is?
Come on! What's one more person?
Why don't you go with the Jeturk guys?
Mr. Guel said I can't come yet.
In that case--
I can't just sit around down here!
Things have livened up around here.
Is she really going to pilot it?
That Gundam called Calibarn...
I still don't like it.
Even if it's for her family's sake...
We can't leave everything
on her shoulders, can we?
Say...
Where is she, anyway?
We enhanced persons are merely
expendable parts for Gundams.
I'd say he was the lucky one.
Aren't you scared?
You should just forget all this and run.
Like she should have done.
I am... scared.
But I...
the things on my wish list...
At first, they were just things
Mom suggested I do,
and for some reason,
I went along with them.
But now...
It's not because someone
told me to... I want to do this.
I want to do this.
Ericht... and my mom...
I want to stop them.
I envy you...
Never mind.
Shall we go?
Right.
There's one more thing...
that I want to do.
The Assembly League fleets
have failed in their second wave attack.
For unclear reasons,
Quiet Zero is also inactive now.
We've done what we can to buy time, but...
Has President Miorine
come out of her room yet?
She's...
What is it?
A Space Assembly League Inspector
is requesting a meeting.
The League?
He also says a student from Asticassia
wants to see President Miorine.
I'll arrange for an option unit
from Burion.
Thank you!
You're welcome.
We'll be ready to test
the Calibarn shortly.
You'd better make it a brief talk.
Right!
Suletta Mercury!
Mr. Guel?
Mr. Guel!
This way.
She's my fianceé now.
Do you think I'll let you see her?
I want to have a straight talk with her.
With Ms. Miorine. Heart to heart.
In that case, shall we duel over it?
If you lose, you'll give up on Miorine.
What will it be?
I'll do it!
Let's...
duel!
Whoever scores the first hit wins.
Deal?
Yes.
Victory is never decided
by one's social position, alone.
Nor by one's skill, alone.
The result itself...
...is the only truth!
Fix release!
You win.
Follow me.
Th...
Thank you very much!
What a fool I am.
Ms. Miorine... It's me, Suletta.
Sorry for showing up so suddenly.
I'm going to Quiet Zero.
I'll meet with Ericht and
talk to my mom one more time.
I'll ask them to stop Quiet Zero.
But I've relied on Mom and Ericht
for everything, all this time.
Making this choice alone is...
really scary.
I can't.
Ms. Miorine?
I can't give you a convenient pep talk.
You have to decide on your own.
Because of me, so many people
were injured and killed.
Pulling you away from your mother, too...
It was all...
a mistake.
I've made mistakes, too.
I've killed people... at Plant Quetta.
And Ms. Sophie.
I told myself it was
for everyone's protection...
that it was the right thing to do...
But...
when the school was in trouble,
and we were desperately
doing recovery work...
I realized something.
Whether it was right or wrong,
what I've done can't be taken back.
Even if there's nothing to gain,
I have to move forward.
I don't want to... make any more mistakes.
I've only made it this far...
because I met you, Ms. Miorine.
Nothing about that was a mistake.
Someday...
come with me... to Earth.
I'm not strong enough to
face what I've done by myself.
But I can't turn away from it, either.
May I... open the door?
No.
I'll go on my own.
I'll open it myself.
The D-index has exceeded 90.
Recovery complete.
All systems reactivated.
Our objective is...
Plant Quetta.
I'm sorry, everyone.
We didn't come here for you.
Go on.
Your father woke up, didn't he?
Right...
It's still difficult for him to speak.
I... won't run.
Not from the company,
or from the Gundam's curse.
So I won't allow you
to give up and die, either!
You lousy father!
Plant Quetta
They seem to have beaten us to it.
In that case, let's pay a visit....
to Delling Rembran himself.
At present, Quiet Zero's data storm
deployment level is only at 60%.
That's why Prospera Mercury has to go
to Plant Quetta to recover certain units.
Once it's fully completed...
It can deploy a data storm capable
of covering the entire Earth Sphere, yes?
We've stationed a defensive fleet
around the head office front, but...
The only machines that can move
in the data storm are Gundams, right?
You've got to be kidding me.
At score 8, you'll die instantly.
The Pharact was never designed
to withstand such a high score load.
Can't we use the Schwarzette
by rewriting its specifications?
There's not enough time.
Too late...
The Demi Barding's option unit
has a switchable cockpit space.
If you add a control system
that doesn't use Permet links...
...you can operate it
without being overridden.
That's like driving a car blindfolded!
It'll never work!
It's the only option we have.
Do we have an NTPS?
I've prepared one, but...
are you serious?
Yes.
We're going to go
straight into Quiet Zero.
I have a few ideas about
the codes to shut it down.
I'll do what I can to prevent
the Assembly League from interfering.
Your job will be to draw the attention
of Aerial and the Gundnodes.
Can you do it?
Yes!
Is this really what you want?
Mr. Guel?
If Suletta operates the Gundam...
I decided on my own.
Listen up.
If we deem the situation hopeless,
we'll hand over the units immediately.
You're all students.
Let the adults take responsibility.
Thanks!
Emergency evacuation orders
from Lagrange 4
are now in effect for
all Benerit Group employees.
I barely recognize you.
Is that thanks to the Mercurian Miss?
Shaddiq... you and I
have both committed sins.
But we aren't through yet.
We have to make up for them.
Are you able to do it?
Even if I'm not, I've decided
to keep moving forward.
So why don't we make a trade?
A trade?
You won't regret it.
Believe in me!
I can do the switching test at any time.
Thank you, Rouji!
Not at all...
Chuchu! Time for final adjustments!
You got it, Nika!
I'm amazed you could find
an old museum piece like this.
Well, it helps that I'm so used
to working with junk.
You're really going?
I can't let Nika and Chuchu
face danger by themsel--
Want some motion-sickness pills?
A tomato...
You brought it here?
NR400... Anesidora.
That's...
It means "she who sends
gifts from the earth."
It was Mr. Rouji who looked it up.
And this was in the genetic code.
Words?
I'm sure your mom
embedded them into the code.
We'll grow some more of them.
Right!
Permet link established.
3... 2... 1...
Listen, Suletta.
To avoid being overridden,
you have to clear score 5.
The Calibarn doesn't have any filters
to reduce feedback from the data storm.
But it can produce and maintain a higher
score with the same amount of Permet.
Since your body is nearly identical
to Ericht's, you have strong resistance.
But unlike her,
you can't coexist with the data storm.
Promise not to push it too far.
Thank you very much, Ms. Belmeria...
for letting me do as I please.
Please begin.
Commence calling.
Roger. Commencing call.
Raising score. Internal Permet
influx values, plus five points.
Calling!
Suletta!
Keep going, please!
Raising score, plus five points.
Calling!
Score 5...
cleared.
I'm coming, Ericht!
Data storm interference waves detected.
Reactivation of Permet reactor confirmed.
It's begun.
Miorine Rembran's trying
to pull off her first feat.
Let's see what she can do.
Permet pattern detected.
Object has penetrated
boundary surface of data storm space.
The Calibarn...!
Please let me through!
So... it's Suletta, after all.
The battle has begun.
We should go too.
The Schwarzette?!
Stop it!
Who the hell is piloting it?!
Are you still obsessed
with that woman, Brother?
Lauda?
Ericht!
What are you doing here...
Suletta?
I came to stop you!
Both of you!
Next time,
Episode 23
"Unrelenting Tenderness."
Illustration: Ryosuke Takeuchi