So you're still alive.
I've always had the devil's luck.
And since when do you work
with Peil Technologies, Bel?
I had... no other choice.
So you're the one
carrying on the Vanadis legacy.
The machine called Aerial...
There's no way you built it on your own.
What are you planning to do?
Why have your own daughter pilot it?
You're much more talkative than I remember.
It's no use taking revenge
for a 21-year-old--
That Gundam pilot...
How many have there been?
Nice to see you after so long.
Until we meet again.
Yes.
The witch is under the wing of
Peil Technologies.
As expected, we smoked her out.
Worried?
Not at all. Aerial will surely win.
I trust my darling daughter.
"How you annoy me," huh?
Why would the Ice Prince speak so harshly?
He's such a creep!
Isn't he the one who invited you?
Now he's even pissed me off.
Is it because I asked about his birthday?
You did nothing wrong, Suletta.
I'd say you fall for people's
sweet words too easily.
Ms. Miorine!
Well, you can't take it back now.
Better just crush him in that duel!
What I can't accept is
that you agreed to duel him
without even consulting me.
I'm... sorry.
I won't forgive you if you lose.
The Jeturk company is hereby
cutting off all your support.
And of course,
you'll have to leave Jeturk House.
Are they really evicting Mr. Guel?
It's a direct order from the CEO.
Where am I supposed to live?
I have a message from your father.
"Consider it an act of mercy that I'm
at least paying the rest of your tuition."
That is all.
Brother...
Lauda.
Look after Jeturk House.
Both parties, deposit
your souls on Libra's scales.
The duelists are Elan Ceres
and Suletta Mercury.
The location will be
the airspace outside the front.
Outside the front?
Elan Ceres, what is your stake in this duel?
If I win,
Aerial will be mine.
Suletta Mercury, what is your stake?
I...
Shall we take it that you have
nothing to gain from this?
There's no need to rush.
Just decide by the day of the duel.
You don't mind, do you?
Whatever.
His walls are even higher than usual.
Did you do something to him?
You mean it's my fault?
Who knows.
But since you arrived, both Guel and Elan
haven't been themselves.
Even I want to know more about you now.
Mercurian Miss.
Airspace outside the front?
Do you even have a thruster unit?
No, I don't.
This is bad!
Peil House's machines
are known for their mobility!
On top of that, you're facing a new model.
You'll be at a disadvantage
with this equipment.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it!
The conditions of the duel are decided
exclusively by the Dueling Committee.
So what do we do?
This House has no money
to buy a thruster unit.
Can we borrow one from another House?
Fat chance getting Spacians
to loan one to us Earthians.
How about we make one, then?
Huh?
All clear! Bring it on down!
Shall we start by inspecting
the propulsion system?
Will this thing work?
Don't underestimate Nika.
There's no doubt she can do it.
Right?
I'll do my best.
Given our finances, this is
putting us in a huge deficit.
How are we gonna eat next month?
Man...
We're betting everything we have on you.
The odds are 2.7 to 1.
If we win, we'll cover her costs.
A-And if I lose?
Bankruptcy.
I'll... do my best.
Are you awake?
You were moaning in your sleep again.
It doesn't interfere with the tests.
How are the results?
You should have no problem
in your next battle.
You mean I won't survive the one after that.
Hi there!
It's been a while... Me.
Hello.
As gloomy as ever...
You're my surrogate, you know.
Can't you act a bit more cheerfully?
Master Elan, what are you doing here?
I came to pay my respects to you guys.
You're going to duel the Holder, right?
The company ordered me to.
It wasn't my idea.
Don't be like that.
There's something in it for you, after all.
If you get us the bride,
we'll give your face back to you.
We'll also arrange for a citizen ID number.
Wouldn't you like that?
It doesn't matter.
Then why did you accept
the role of my double?
You knew full well
that this mobile suit was a curse.
Long before that...
I was already cursed.
Next we'll try a variable thrust test.
Right.
Once you stop the engines,
reactivate immediately.
Right.
Okay. Your propulsion is stable.
The combustion control
functions are working, too.
Shall we head back, Suletta?
Right.
Tomorrow...
Yes?
Will you be ready to fight? With Mr. Elan...
Mr. Elan was only kind to me...
because that was his plan.
And yet, I was really happy.
I feel so dumb.
Exactly. It was dumb.
In fact, Elan's right about you.
You really are annoying.
Ms. Miorine...
But that's just how you are.
You annoy me by meddling in my affairs
and act on your own
without listening to me...
Move forward, gain two, right?
So how could you run away here?!
This is no time to feel sorry for yourself.
Get out there and move forward!
Right!
I'm on my way!
What?
You've already forgiven her, haven't you?
If she loses,
I'll be in trouble as her bride.
That goes for all of you as well, doesn't it?
I have faith that Suletta will win.
Whoa! What the heck is that?
M-My apologies!
Sorry to be a bother!
Hey, Mercurian girl!
What are you doing here?
The duel isn't today!
Whoa!
Um...
Is Mr. Elan there?
This is LP041, Suletta Mercury.
I came...
to talk to Mr. Elan.
Talk?
To Elan Ceres?
Good luck with that!
He hardly talks to us, his housemates.
Nobody at Peil House knows a thing
about that "Pharact" machine, either!
Please.
I really would like to talk to him.
Testing... testing...
Mr. Elan, can you hear me?
It's Suletta!
Mr. Elan!
Why did you say that to me?
Why do we have to duel?
What do you want with Aerial?
Please tell me!
Do I really annoy you?
See? We told you so.
Now go home!
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday, happy birthday...
CALL FROM ELAN
Go home.
I told you, I don't have a birthday.
That's why.
What if we made today your birthday?
Don't you feel empty without a birthday?
That's why...
You really do...
annoy me.
Open Gate No. 6!
No anomalies in
catapult superconductive storage.
No error warnings
on any components of the flight unit!
No problems with INS alignment!
Suletta?
Were you able to speak with Mr. Elan?
No. But...
I did decide what my stake is in this duel.
No obstacles in launch direction.
We're ready!
Opening hatch!
Transferring launch authorization to pilot.
Go get him!
Right!
LP041, Suletta Mercury...
Aerial, taking off!
No problems with effective exhaust velocity.
Suletta,
Peil House's academic vessel
is ahead on your course.
No hazardous objects
including interplanetary matter.
Ready to launch.
Transferring authorization to pilot.
KP002, Elan Ceres...
Pharact, launching.
Welcome. Nice to meet you.
Jeturk House's new leader,
Lauda Neill.
We can skip the formalities.
Please just start the duel.
What's this? Are you still sore
about that last duel?
Ooh, scary...
With mutual consent by both parties,
we will now begin the duel.
As always, victory will go
to the first one to break the blade
antenna of their opponent's mobile suit.
The observer shall be the leader
of Grassley House, Shaddiq Zenelli.
Both parties, face off.
Mr. Elan?
Mercurian Miss,
have you decided
what your stake is in this duel?
Yes, if I win,
I want Mr. Elan to tell me all about himself.
Huh? That sounds like...
A love confession.
She's really an annoying girl.
Well then, let's begin.
Victory is never decided
by mobile suit performance alone.
Nor by the skill of the pilot, alone.
The result itself is the only truth!
Fix release.
Ms. Nika, this is amazing. At this rate...
Machine load is within acceptable limits.
Nice work, Nika.
I... I guess...
You want to know about me?
I'm a disposable pawn created
for the Gundam's sake.
Is that enough for you?
You're more mean-spirited than I thought,
Suletta Mercury!
You have everything.
Friends, family...
A past and a future...
A wish list of things to do...
Even hope!
Mr. Elan?
Then why can't you spare me this victory?!
Otherwise...
it's just too unfair!
Aerial!
Elan...
I've never seen you so worked up.
What mobility!
It's way too fast.
This is why they chose
the airspace outside the front.
She'll never keep up
using a flight unit we threw together!
At this rate...
He'll torture her to death from out of range.
But that's...
Even if she does manage to get close,
next he'll...
Permet score,
three.
There they are!
I knew it!
If any of them touch her,
even through her armor,
her electrical systems will be blown.
Suletta, evade it!
Right!
You won't get away.
She's hit!
Shut up!
That GUND-Bit is finished.
Everyone!
She's better at controlling
GUND-Bits than me.
In a contest of speed, a Peil mobile
suit will always have the advantage.
What now?
Suletta Mercury...
I can't catch him at this rate.
Please, everyone!
Give me your strength!
The Aerial has sped up, too.
They're playing chase, huh?
Her annoying behavior
is as tough as the hardest alloys.
Permet score, four!
She's really pushing it.
She's forcing it too far.
But she's definitely getting closer.
Rouji?
They've passed the border lights.
This is bad.
The data storm has exceeded
acceptable limits.
Deploy!
Got him!
That's a hit!
Suletta!
There's damage
to the flight unit's left wing.
Belmeria Winston...
Your diagnosis missed the mark.
But even so,
I'll at least deny your worth,
Suletta Mercury!
Get out of there, Suletta!
She's trapped!
Nothing's moving. What did she do?
You're...
All right!
Yes!
She did it!
Did you get a record of that?
Permet decoding data, recording complete.
Phew...
Thank you. Good work, Aerial.
I feel like I could hear your voice
more than ever today.
Mr. Elan...
So that's it.
I never knew...
Mr. Elan?
Mr. Elan! Mr. Elan!
Mr. Elan!
Mr. Elan?
I'm really sorry.
Are you hurt?
Your stake was to learn about me, wasn't it?
I did have someone. Long ago.
Someone who would celebrate my birthday.
All this time, I thought I had nothing.
But... it wasn't true.
It wasn't true!
You've got it all wrong.
Huh?
There are people who will celebrate
your birthday. I'm one of them.
It's absolutely wrong to say
you have nothing, Mr. Elan!
That's true. I've had it wrong.
Are you okay with this?
I'm an understanding bride.
I can tolerate... some minor two-timing.
He's late!
It's not even the meeting time yet.
He should be 5 minutes early!
Ms. Miorine!
Um...
Thank you... very much.
Just obey your curfew, okay?
Please, Ms. Nugen!
Number Four is experienced!
We could always choose
to feed back the duel data--
An enhanced person who can't
carry out their orders has no future.
You should understand that.
We still have spares.
Prepare the next one promptly.
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday...
to...
Will you be here soon, Mr. Elan?
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"Shall We Gundam?"