A shield?
She blocked it?
In that case...
What just happened?
What kind of mobile suit is that?
GUND-ARM...
Gundam.
Rouji!
Yes!
Haro.
As you wish.
There's no match for Its individual Permet code,
but there's one machine that's similar.
Ochs Earth, huh?
But that's impossible. I mean...
If that's the Witch's mobile suit, then...
We can't just leave it alone.
Me?
Your groom?
My lousy father
decided without consulting me.
I'm to marry whoever the Holder is.
B-But...
Don't worry.
There's no way I'm doing that.
All I want...
is to go to Earth.
No way!
Really?
Guel lost?
I can't believe it.
Wow...
They build mobile suits like this at Mercury?
Hey look...
Jamming?!
Warning!
Cease dueling immediately!
Repeat!
The front management company?
Student ID Number LP041.
Suletta Mercury.
You and your mobile suit
are to be taken into custody
on suspicion of using a Gundam.
A Gundam?
You've got it wrong! This is Aerial!
Lower your weapons!
Your job is to manage the fronts.
This is a school!
Rules set by the President
take precedence over all others.
The President?
That lousy father of mine...
Weren't all the Gundam types disposed of?
It certainly doesn't
look like an old machine.
Don't those things take
the lives of their pilots?
Yeah, but that girl is alive, isn't she?
Suletta Mercury. Age 17.
Student ID Number LP041.
Piloting department...
Your father is deceased
and your mother
is currently assigned to Lagrange 1.
Is that correct?
I already answered you.
Yes.
Do you acknowledge that
the machine you were piloting
was a Gundam?
Her name is Aerial!
And that the use of machines
equipped with the GUND Format
has been frozen and prohibited
by the Agreement?
I don't know... what you're talking about.
Suletta Mercury.
Are you not a member of
the Vanadis Institute
that developed the Gundams?
She's a Gundam pilot?
She doesn't look like a witch.
Any links to Vanadis?
Her mobile suit is registered...
to the Shin Sei Development
Corporation of Mercury.
We're still investigating--
If she's not a witch,
then how do you explain this?
Do you think a bunch of miners
at Mercury could build their own Gundam?!
Or perhaps...
it's the ghost of Ochs Earth.
The duel results are void.
Confiscate that machine immediately
and send the pilot back to Mercury!
And then your son will reclaim
the title of Holder, won't he?
Summon Shin Sei's representative.
We will hold an inquiry.
The duel results were voided.
Well, she cheated, right?
I knew something wasn't right.
What about the transfer student?
They're probably still interrogating her.
I almost feel sorry for that Mercurian girl.
Well, she made off
with someone else's prize, after all...
Right.
Nanaura!
Yes?
This arrived
from the front management company.
That transfer student took yours, right?
I offered it to her.
She was in trouble.
The lending of student notebooks
is against school regulations.
When will that girl be back?
An Earthian like you should stay out of this.
Just concentrate on your studies.
Take care of the Dueling Committee for me.
You work awfully hard for a student.
I'm just doing it because I want to.
A witch trial at the head office?
Something like that.
That girl...
Could she really be a witch?
What's gotten into you?
Curious about someone besides yourself, Elan?
Don't tell me you're in love.
Falling in love is something I'll never do.
No matter what.
Let me help.
It was your great "ace"
who broke these, you know.
Well, my brother told me to fix them.
Does that mean he's sorry?
And where is he now?
He's absent today.
He probably got summoned
after losing that duel.
By his father, that is.
Well, it's better than a parent
who's aloof from their child!
Like father, like daughter.
You just leave that transfer student
dangling after she fought for you.
I never asked her to do that.
I'll tell her when she gets back...
not to meddle in others' affairs.
Since you don't seem to know,
we'll fill you in.
The Mercurian girl is going to be expelled.
They're going to scrap her mobile suit, too!
I heard my dad say so--
Wh-What? You got a prob--
You said it, right?
FIx it, then.
And one more thing.
If you touch my tomatoes, I'll kill you.
Here it is. Shin Sei Development Corporation.
Founded 33 years ago.
Ranked D within the group.
151st place in sales?
Isn't that the bottom of the ladder?
I'm impressed she got into this school.
Still...
What?
They made their own mobile suit.
But unless it's approved, what good is it?
If she had a bigger supporter,
it might've been a different story.
At our school, you're as good as the rank
of the company that recommended you.
I can hardly be proud of being born on Earth.
It's the Spacians who are holding us down!
Keep your voice down, Chuchu.
I don't care if they hear!
Well, I do care.
Do you mind moving?
That's our usual table.
Since when?!
It's fine.
We just finished eating.
Catch you later.
You're done eating, right?
Throw that out with the rest.
Hey! Learn some manners, Spacian!
Let's go, Chuchu.
What?
Martin, too.
Hey wait, Nika!
I'll clean up right away.
Nika, why did you...
As I said, there's a possibility
that was a forbidden machine.
I'm only asking to see the pilot!
She's my classmate!
It's not up to me.
Who's it up to, then?
President Delling.
Now, if you would please leave.
To prevent an infectious spread of "SV29"
confirmed in Front Autonomous Sector 33...
Mistress Miorine.
"Go back to class," right?
No. I have a message from your father
I don't want to read it.
Then I'll read it for you.
"Miorine,
I'm unenrolling you from the school."
What?
"I'll arrange a groom myself.
Return immediately."
What?
That's all.
Give me that!
What the hell is this?
It was you who decided
that my fiance would be
selected through duels.
Suletta's the one who won the duel!
No man chosen by that jerk
will be a husband of mine!
It's no use saying that to me.
He's always like this.
He never consults me, he never explains...
Whether it's enrolling me at this school
or forcing me to quit piano.
Or deciding who I should be friends with.
Even my own mother's funeral!
Where are you going?
To the bathroom!
Don't let Mistress Miorine out of your sight.
Die, die, die, die...
You must be Ms. Miorine Rembran.
Designated Colony Coordinate XY72Z53.
That's...
the rendezvous point for my escape!
It's nice to finally meet you in person.
You didn't show up
to meet us the other day,
so I came to check on you.
Is this some sort of after-sales care?
You did pay us, after all.
If you haven't changed your mind,
would you like to escape now?
What?
If we act now, I can send you
to Earth as you desire.
To Earth?!
But...
I can wait for 30 minutes.
Make a decision you won't regret.
I'll go.
What?
You've gotta get me out of here!
Is it really this easy?
It's all about timing.
We're lucky the spaceport controller
was a collaborator of ours,
and then you and I happened to meet.
We'll be leaving the airspace
controlled by this port in 5 minutes.
Once we do, we can't change our course.
Are you sure?
Yes.
I've made up my mind.
Mistress Miorine has disappeared again.
What about the men watching her?
She shook them off.
Shall we seal the port?
Have the immigration authorities
spread a dragnet.
I know she's bound for Earth, anyway.
More importantly,
when will the inquiry begin?
We've just confirmed the arrival
of the Shin Sei representative.
I see.
So a member of the Jeturk family
lost a duel in a Jeturk mobile suit?
Are you trying to destroy
the company's reputation?
Forgive me, Dad.
This time around, I'll arrange
to have the duel result voided.
Don't embarrass me again!
Yes.
You have a visitor, sir.
Who is it?
It's...
The representative of
the Shin Sei Development Corporation.
What?
It's been a while,
Mr. Jeturk.
We haven't seen each other for 3 years
since your appointment as president.
Lady Prospera.
That's right.
If you want me to talk to the President
on your behalf, the answer is no.
Not at all. The opposite, in fact.
What?
It's you who should ask me for a favor.
Mom...
Y-Yes?
Aren't you hungry?
My name's Elan Ceres.
Like you, I'm a student at Asticassia.
The guard here let me do his job.
Is it really okay?
Go ahead.
I-It's so nice of you.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Why would you...
You interest me.
Huh?
Suletta Mercury...
I'd like to learn more about you.
We will now begin the inquiry.
Lady Prospera, representative of
the Shin Sei Development Corporation.
Are you a witch?
No.
Do you have ties to the Vanadis Institute?
Then how did you build a Gundam?
The Aerial is not a Gundam.
It's a product of Shin Sei's
newly developed drone technology.
What?
Did she say drone?
Shaddiq.
Yes, Father.
During the duel, that machine's
Permet influx values exceeded the standards.
This is a unique characteristic
of the GUND Format,
the core system of all Gundams.
If that machine is equipped
with the GUND Format,
you should also have detected a data storm.
Well?
There was none detected.
Its control system is based on
a conventional Permet link.
I'm confident that it complies with all
of the group's technology provisions.
That alone doesn't prove it isn't a Gundam.
You can't prove that it is, either.
Lady Prospera...
You are merely using the lack
of evidence as an excuse.
Are you trying to tell us
that black is white?
We're one of the smallest, but
still a member of the Benerit Group.
We are, of course,
aware of the Cathedra Agreement.
I ask for your trust.
I can't help doubting
when you come dressed like that.
This arm,
as well as the face behind this mask,
were both claimed
by Mercury's magnetic field.
Environmental conditions
on Mercury are severe.
However, utilizing our drone technology,
we'll be able to mine for Permet
without putting anyone in danger.
Please allow us to continue
the Aerial's development.
We are in need of the group's support.
No. That thing is a Gundam.
Why is that?
Because I said so.
Any objections?
Then it's settled.
The mobile suit shall be disposed of.
We'll get rid of the student pilot.
What are you doing here?
Miorine...
I came to give you a piece of my mind.
If you made these rules yourself,
you shouldn't change them after the fact!
You hypocritical loser of a father!
Weren't you supposed to take her to Earth?
I have to honor my customers' requests.
And when it comes
to the President's daughter,
it can't hurt to be owed a favor.
As calculating as ever.
Space is in need of new rules.
The only people
permitted to stand in this room
are the powers-that-be from the
top companies of the Benerit Group.
But you are different.
You are merely a student
with no authority to speak of.
It's always the same with you.
You look down and control my life
without asking or explaining.
Neither consultation
nor explanation are necessary.
I decide.
You obey.
Did you think you could speak out
against me because you're my daughter?
What's your problem?!
You're a king?
That's right.
I am vested with power.
You have none.
The powerless shut their mouths and obey.
Those are the rules of our world.
If you move forward, you gain two...
In that case, I challenge you to a duel!
If we win,
you'll accept Suletta as my fiance.
If we lose, you can do as you please!
Were you unable to comprehend my words?
I'm saying that I'll fight
according to your rules!
At least take responsibility
for your own decisions!
You're an adult, aren't you?
May I speak?
Even if was accidentally, that machine
defeated our company's Dilanza.
Perhaps we should give it time
to see what it can do.
What do you mean?
Recently, mobile suits from
other companies have made market gains.
That machine could be
the key to recovering our market share.
I believe the school duels will be
an effective test of the Aerial's abilities.
And will you provide us with
the machine's technical data?
Of course.
Hold it right there!
Do you intend to violate
the Cathedra Agreement?
I object!
This is...
How will you announce this
to the outside world?
It could be valuable.
This is about ethics!
But...
Suletta!
Ms. Miorine!
What are you...
Let's do it. The duel...
If you lose, Aerial will be scrapped!
And you'll be expelled!
You have to win!
Permet link established.
Decision Making Extension AI
has been connected.
Confirming deployment
of combat space network.
Whenever you're ready.
Next time on Mobile Suit Gundam:
The Witch from Mercury,
"Guel's Pride".