Why, yes. We acknowledge it.
The Pharact is indeed a Gundam.
It's despicable of you
to breach the Agreement so casually.
I believe you know a thing
or two about that yourself.
Now then, what are you proposing?
We'd like Peil Technologies
to cooperate with our plan.
This is an opportunity we'll never see again.
To learn what he...
what Delling has up his sleeve.
Don't let your mind wander!
You'll hurt the tomatoes.
I-I'm sorry.
Honestly...
Are you really that worried about Elan?
He hasn't been to school since then, either.
Is he really okay?
Butting into other people's problems
and worrying without being asked...
Are you enjoying this or something?
Haven't you ever been troubled, Ms. Miorine...
about somebody else's--
Never.
I only ever think about one thing.
Getting out of this place and going to Earth.
If your mind is always elsewhere,
you'll fail the exam again.
I guess that's true, but...
An invitation?
An incubation party, huh?
There's no need to go.
Are you sure?
It's like a social party
for people among the group companies.
As far as students, only those
from the three branches will be going.
As the Holder, if you go there, they'll
force you to make a speech on stage and--
Then he'll come too, right?
What?
If the three branches are going,
then Mr. Elan will come too, right?
Look at this...
Are you sure it's okay for us to be here?
I can't help but feel nervous.
What?
There's no need for that.
Everything here is just for show.
Plus, you two...
are guests of the reigning Holder.
S-Sorry to keep you waiting!
Are you okay?
It's pretty tight in the bust...
It's my dress. Of course it's tight.
Now stand up straight!
I could've loaned you a dress too, Nika.
Are you okay in that uniform?
We came along out of curiosity, but...
we didn't really know what to expect.
An incubation party...
In other words, an event
to promote new business startups.
People who want to start
a new project within the group
announce their plans here
and solicit investment.
If they reach their target amount,
then a glorious new business is born.
Wow....
But I doubt anyone will get enough money.
Huh?
The concepts are all too old-fashioned.
No one will buy into their presentations.
You're right. No wonder you're the top
student in management strategy.
Is that sarcasm? Let's go.
We're going to go search for Elan.
I think I want to have a look at the booths.
Fine. See you later, then.
See you.
Why do I have to clean up
after that Enhanced Person?
The next test subject isn't ready yet.
We believe it's best
to leave this to the real you.
Damn him for leaving
a mess like this behind.
That girl is...
The latest groom candidate.
Then she's...
The witch they're talking about.
Oh, scary.
Everyone's staring at us.
Never mind them. Just behave confidently.
B-But...
Stand up straight!
R-Right!
Fancy meeting you two here.
Does this mean you're
interested in new business ventures?
Shaddiq?
If possible, I'd love to receive
your advice about our presentations.
Coming from the man who won
the contract for Four Card Sector 17,
I find that hard to believe.
I'd like to hear your opinion, Miorine.
What?
Are you two friends?
Please. I just can't get rid of him.
Don't be that way.
We used to see each other
a lot at these events.
Anyway, what brings you here today?
I know you didn't come to see the President.
I'm just accompanying her.
She keeps whining about wanting
to talk to Elan face-to-face!
M-M-Ms. Miorine!
You've changed, Miorine.
Th-Th-That's confidential!
Acting for another person's sake...
The Miorine I knew would never do that.
Is this more of the Mercurian Miss's magic?
I don't know what you mean.
Come on, let's go!
R-Right!
Ms. Miorine, wait for me!
You've definitely changed.
Too bad.
Oh, my! Look at you!
Mom!
You said you weren't coming!
I finished work earlier than expected.
The dress looks truly lovely on you!
Mr. Godoy, long time no see.
And this young lady is...
Oh right, I have to introduce you.
Ms. Miorine.
She's the one who loaned me this dress.
I'm Miorine Rembran.
I'm Suletta's mother,
Prospera Mercury.
I'm so pleased to meet you again.
I'm sorry you had to see me like that.
Not at all! I was quite impressed!
"Hypocritical loser of a father!"
Wasn't that it?
I'm of the opinion that we owe
Aerial's approval to you.
Thank you very much.
Mom, you've met Ms. Miorine--
Suletta?
Your mother is thirsty.
Can you bring me something to drink?
Sure, got it!
Well, in that case, I'll--
Has it always been that way...
between you and your father?
Is this really the place to ask?
Well, if you and Suletta are married,
we're going to be relatives.
Shouldn't I want to get along
with the bride's family?
The man responsible for suppressing
the Vanadis Incident 21 years ago.
And most of all, the hero
who banned the Gundams.
I'd think he'd be a splendid father.
That glory's all in the past.
Our generation knows nothing of Gundams.
You're hard to please.
What's so unforgivable about him?
He always looks down on me
and makes decisions without consulting me.
That day, didn't you think
he was being unreasonable, too?
But most of all...
No matter what,
I will never accept
a man like that as my father!
What's your problem?
Oh, please excuse me.
And now, being unveiled
for the first time,
a promotion for the new color version.
That beautiful dress...
Enjoy!
the high heels
and accessories you're wearing,
that you can live in the Chairman's
office rather than a House,
the respect you receive from others...
When I remember all of that
is because your father
is the president of the Benerit Group,
it somehow strikes me as funny.
Oh, I'm sorry if I've offended you.
But first you must throw away
that adorable pride,
dear daughter of President Delling.
Miss!
Are you okay?
I-I-I'm so sorry!
Wh-What should I do?
Pathetic.
How could my brother fall
for such an oafish woman?
It's about time. Do as I instructed.
Yes, Dad.
Wh-Wh-What am I going to...?
What do I--
Here you are.
Are you okay?
I've been waiting for you,
President Delling.
Have this one, if you like.
Oh, thank you very much!
I wasn't really sure what to do.
You're welcome.
In fact, I'm the one
who owes you thanks, Nika Nanaura.
Not at all...
What?
Here you are.
Uh... I'm very sorry!
It's fine. Don't worry
about the handkerchief.
That's not what I meant.
You didn't show up the other day,
and I couldn't contact you afterwards.
I was worried.
No, in fact...
I've been wanting
to apologize to you all this time.
Because of Peil company business,
I've been taking
a leave of absence since then.
The front I went to is affected
by strong magnetic storms.
I'm sorry to have worried you.
Then... you'll be coming back to school?
Of course. I promise!
I'm glad...
to see you smiling now.
Now then, we should get moving.
The Holder has to take the stage soon.
I'll go with you.
Nika!
What?
Have you seen Suletta?
Were you separated?
Unbelievable. Where did she wander off to?
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now turn over the stage
to the CEOs of Peil Technologies
for a special presentation.
Greetings. It is my great honor today
to present to you two students
of the Asticassia School of Technology
who represent its bright future.
Suletta?
And now, let me reintroduce the pilot
of the Pharact, the mobile suit
that is our pride and joy,
Elan Ceres.
And next to him,
the pilot who so impressively
defeated the Pharact in a recent duel.
The current Holder, Ms. Suletta Mercury.
I-I-I'm...
Stand up straight!
I'm Suletta Mercury!
As someone from Mercury,
I'm going to learn so many
new things at this school...
and every day is fulfilling!
I will continue to do my best...
in my studies!
Thank you, Ms. Suletta Mercury.
By the way, your mobile suit
is quite a unique machine.
Does its operation require complex skills?
Or could it be your own special talent?
Aerial's the amazing one!
Aerial and I have been
together since childhood.
She's a precious family member!
Family? What a lovely sentiment.
I have one more question, then.
We've heard from Elan Ceres
that he felt a strange sensation
during his recent duel with you.
For a split second,
I picked up a strange response.
Almost as if your machine
and mine had become entangled.
Didn't you feel it too?
I could hear your voice
more than ever today.
Yes. I did.
I see. Then there's no mistake.
Huh? What?
The truth is now clear.
Shin Sei Development Corporation's
mobile suit Aerial is...
a Gundam!
A Gundam?!
Allow me to explain.
Our company's mobile suit Pharact
was using the GUND Format.
This has been revealed to us
by reports from the Dueling Committee
and our internal auditor.
That phenomenon is the result of mutual
interference between GUND Formats.
Only Gundams respond to other Gundams.
Which means the Aerial is,
without a doubt, a Gundam!
W-Wait a minute!
Aerial isn't a Gundam!
You already admitted the truth, didn't you?
In your own words.
It's not true!
Building and possessing a Gundam is
against the Cathedra Agreement.
How will the Peil company
make amends for this?
As this is a grave matter, our company
promises to dispose of the machine...
...and to dissolve the development
team that produced it.
In that case, Shin Sei should
accept the same settlement.
Y-You can't!
This is absurd! They already...
Those creeps. They intend
to bury Aerial along with it.
Wait, Ms. Nugen!
She was truly unaware
that her machine is a Gundam!
It would be reasonable
to let the developer explain.
Mom!
Mom... Mom!
What was so important
that we could only discuss it outside?
It's a message from my father.
He'd like to renegotiate
your previous deal.
Aerial isn't like that!
She's not a Gundam!
So it was a Gundam, after all.
My mom, too...
This is the end for Shin Sei.
...said that Aerial...
...isn't a Gundam!
Naturally.
This is bad. At this rate, Aerial...
Aerial is...
...family to me!
The Benerit Group won't overlook a Gundam.
This is wrong!
Indeed.
Please!
Please listen to me!
Your decision, Mr. President?
I won't let you dispose of Aerial!
Aerial is a superior machine that defeated
both the Jeturk and Peil companies.
Destroying it would be a waste!
Why are you here, Mistress Miorine?
Isn't it obvious?
Because I'm that girl's bride!
Ms. Miorine?
You seem to misunderstand the issue here.
An inhuman weapon that steals the lives
of its pilots cannot be tolerated.
Suletta's alive and well!
Is denying and disposing of things
all you can possibly do?
You're saying there's an option
other than disposal?
Establish connection, please.
Based on past financial statements,
I estimate that
after disposing of the Pharact
and dissolving the
development team responsible,
Peil's loss will amount to 120 billion.
I thus propose twice that amount,
240 billion...
as the investment goal
for my new business plan.
We'll purchase Shin Sei's and Peil's
development teams through M&A,
then merge them together.
A new company will be established,
managed and operated with the protection
of life as its top priority!
M-Ms. Miorine?
Aerial isn't a Gun--
Shut up!
The name of the new company will be...
GUND-ARM!
GUND...
...ARM?
S-Stop messing around!
Everyone gathered here
wants a spark to reignite
the Benerit Group's profitability.
The company and I will be
responsible for bioethical issues
and complying with
the Agreement's restrictions.
If investment is by anonymous contract,
and it's independent from the group...
then there's no risk to anyone!
If any of you see value in this idea,
please invest in the establishment
of GUND-ARM, Inc.!
It's no good, though.
That's not enough.
Why?
There's no value in your proposal.
They're all saying that.
No matter how big and lofty you may sound,
you have absolutely
no credibility to back it up.
Naturally.
Get out.
I have no further interest
in indulging a child's pride.
Please wait!
Ms. Miorine?
I'll protect you.
Leave it to me.
But first you must throw away
that adorable pride.
It's not pride!
What now?
I want you to invest in my company.
As you say,
nobody is willing
to support my proposal as is.
That's why I want to borrow your credibility
as president of the Benerit Group!
Please!
You can't run away.
The Gundam's curse
is a heavier burden than you think.
Huh.
Well done.
The winds seem to be shifting.
Indeed.
So you accepted it, after all...
Gundam.
Ms. Miorine!
Thank you very much!
GUND-ARM, Inc...
My, things have livened up in here.
...will surely deliver results...
...that will be worthy of your trust!
Shall we continue our conversation?
Unbelievable.
Ladies and gentlemen...
It's too much, too fast.
...thank you for taking the time...
Suddenly it's a company?
...to attend today's incubation party...
Suletta?
...for the Benerit Group.
Mom?
I had some business to attend to.
We are happy to have presented to you....
Thank you for your help.
...plans with high future potential.
Ms. Miorine Rembran.
We appreciate your support.
If it's with you, I know that I'm
leaving my daughters in good hands.
Worry not.
We're looking forward to working with you.
M-Mom!
Aerial isn't a Gundam, right?
You said she wasn't--
No, she's a Gundam.
What?
I'm so sorry. The truth is out now.
Aerial...
is a Gundam.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"Their Choice."