Earth
It's completely burnt out.
That won't do.
Should we return it to this one?
Here are some cartridges.
I've got some refills.
Thanks.
Can I ask you to replenish
our stock of painkillers?
I'll let Naji know.
Come on! I said eat, Spacian!
Sedo, Seethia.
How is he?
It's no use, Olcott.
He won't eat a bite.
I'm sorry.
He keeps mumbling too.
What a weirdo.
Dad, forgive me.
I'm sorry, Dad...
When did he last eat?
Three days ago.
I'm sorry.
Sedo, give me that.
Uh, sure.
Guel Jeturk. You can be
our bargaining chip in negotiations.
Don't think you can get out of this
by dying.
We're evacuating?
We got a message from Norea.
It seems the Benerit Group
has sniffed us out.
What about the refugees?
I can't leave my family behind.
We'll find a place for them to stay.
We owe them for letting us hide here.
Gristan, prepare to launch transports.
Everyone else, prepare to take refugees
and cargo to the western airfield.
Roger!
Episode 15
It's your fault Sophie died.
Now you're putting Naji in danger too.
Along with plenty of adults and children.
All because of your silly ideals.
Now, now! Calm down!
It's not right.
Just because you hate Spacians,
you go on a rampage
for no reason and kill people...
If all you do is cause suffering,
no one will ever listen
to Earthians' voices.
What you're doing is wrong!
How dare you?!
How dare you?! How dare you?!
How dare you, you jerk?!
That's enough.
I can't let you kill this student.
Don't forget
that your freedom is in our hands.
Don't touch me, traitor!
Because of her damned ego,
dozens or hundreds of our comrades will be
killed in their so-called security operations.
So tell me, which one of us
is causing suffering?
I can pull the strings
to do anything at this school.
It was easy.
Both detaining you...
and impersonating the guards.
If all you wanted
was to inherit Grassley,
you had plenty of chances.
Is your real objective...
the Presidency of the Group?
I have a goal to accomplish.
We covertly finance the massive costs of
space development through war partitioning.
So you see, Father...
I want to break this system.
Shallow nonsense...
The vested-interest structure
of war partitioning is untouchable.
If you break it apart rashly...
The Earth will be exhausted by proxy wars
and corporations will
scramble for the shrunken pie.
Profits will likely evaporate, too.
But I have a better idea.
We merely need to sell
all the Benerit Group's assets to Earth.
To Earth?
Who knows when the next war will start.
We'll use the friction
between Earth and the corporations
to create a situation
that works as deterrence.
If we do that, no one will have
any need to start wars on Earth.
Since you're half-Earthian,
are you trying to give weapons...
to a conflict area like Earth
as a way to work off
your grudge against Spacians?
Grudges won't fill an empty stomach.
Then again,
as long as Spacians alone control
all the interests and keep exploiting us,
one can't do anything without power.
That's why...
I'll be the one who seizes...
that power.
Benerit Group's Earth Garrison Forces
No sign of targets
in EMS coverage area.
Disperse and continue searching
as individual teams.
If you meet resistance,
you're authorized to neutralize it.
Copy that!
Why aren't we Dominicus being sent out
rather than the Group's security forces?
News of the incident at the school
has already leaked to the outside.
It was the board's decision. They don't
want to owe anything to Cathedra.
Is this something
corporations should handle on their own?
I have a bad feeling about this.
Or maybe what they want is...
Huh?
I have a visitor. I'll be in touch.
Thank you for coming to see me.
What can I do for you?
There's something I'd like you to tell me.
Me?
What is Quiet Zero?
Save the stockpiles for the next one!
The sick are this way!
Bring that here!
Thank you!
Come on, Bessie!
Let me be the point man for this one!
Didn't you hear the mission brief, Jalil?
You have no experience, rookie.
I proved myself at the plant!
Meanwhile, you're acting
like a fraidy-cat.
Unlike you, I have--
Phillip!
Don't lose your cool.
Sorry.
It's just that
when I think of my family...
Where's Mr. Olcott?
Shouldn't he be packing too?
That guy doesn't have
any personal belongings.
He threw them all away long ago...
They say it's a grave for Sophie.
She was a hero to the kids, after all.
We don't have time for this
in an evacuation.
They don't want to forget.
If they do,
they'll be overwhelmed by the fear
that they could die next.
Will pleading to the dead erase that fear?
You, of all people, should understand.
I've forgotten...
We found a place for the refugees.
The first flight can leave at any time.
Understood. I'll go too.
You there!
Get in the vehicle! You'll be left behind!
The transports will take off
at 5 o'clock in the morning.
Take care of the rest.
We mobile suit pilots will stay here.
There's no telling
when the enemy could come.
You'll act as decoys?
We're all prepared.
What about the little prince?
If necessary, we'll use him
as a bargaining chip.
I'm the one who insisted
on bringing him, after all.
How honorable.
That's just like you.
You're not bringing a chain gun?
I like to keep everything lightweight.
Prodoros! Let's go!
The garrison forces could arrive
as early as tonight.
The priority is to keep them from
detecting the evacuation.
Don't attack first.
Avoid fighting if you can.
If you encounter them,
try to draw the enemy's fire
to buy time for the transports
to take off.
Roger!
12 AM
Airfield
There's about 20 percent left.
We should finish loading in three hours.
Send word when you're done.
We'll rendezvous with Bessie's team.
Damn, it's hot.
It's the middle of the night, too...
Let go!
I said let me go!
Why are you here?
Let go!
Get in the truck, now.
B-But...
Get in.
He promised...
that he'd come back from the plant.
So instead of Dad,
why'd they bring you back?!
Why...
Why me and not Dad?
If I...
If I had died...
Dad...
That's right!
If you'd died, my Dad would be...
Give him back.
Give me back my Daddy.
You're bringing him?
Yes.
Why?
What's the point? Didn't you hear?
This guy's company
is about to go bankrupt...
Even if that's true,
we can always use him as a shield.
Bankrupt...
Is that true?
Tell me!
Th-This is about my family!
The garrison forces!
They really came!
That fool! Machei!
Roger. Deploying ECM jammers.
I'll head out and assist Jalil.
Phillip!
I knew this would happen...
Damn it!
You damn Spacians!
Zulu 2 to Zulu 1!
We're under attack from the ground.
Long-range comms are useless.
Descend and wipe them out.
Roger! All units, descend and neutralize!
You can't hit me!
The school!
Olcott! Come in, Olcott!!
Damn it!
Naji!
There are four enemy mobile suits!
What about the evacuees?
Two vehicles have left!
Just keep distracting them somehow!
Jalil! Can you make the rendezvous?
Y-Yes... I'm sorry about this!
Phillip! Draw them toward the factory area!
Roger!
This way...
Follow me, you dogs!
Olcott!
Wake up, Olcott!
Say something! Olcott!
Olcott! C'mon!
Olcott!
Da...
...ddy...
Olcott!
Sedo...
Olcott! Your body...
The arm's artificial.
I won't die.
Olcott, Seethia is...
Seethia!
We can't help her now.
Join the evacuation by yourself.
But--
Give it up.
Go!
Was he crushed?
Daddy...
Machei!
Got one!
Huh?
Jalil!
You've done it now, you bastards!
Phillip, stay calm!
Don't fight them head on!
Machei!
Get some distance while you...
There was another one?
Olcott!
Still alive, huh?
Can you go on?
Yeah.
Forgive me. We lost Jalil.
I see.
Olcott!
The last vehicle is about to leave!
We're counting on you!
I hear a vehicle!
Why...
What is it you want?
I don't know.
I don't know what I want.
I...
Phillip! Don't go in too deep!
Phillip!
Please...
help the others...
Make sure...
they get out... of here alive...
Machei...
Gristan...
Olcott.
Sorry. I'm out of ammo.
Wait, Bessie!
I'll take the lead--
I'm closing range!
Cover me!
Bessie's...
Prodoros...
That's one of their...
mobile suits.
The cockpit... still has power.
Ridrick Kruger.... he's still alive?
You recognize one of the names
on the suspect list?
He's a former Dominicus member.
What?
He was an immature kid...
Unafraid of higher-ups,
he stuck to his own sense of justice.
But in the end, he was
attacked by Earthians himself.
I guess his family were collateral damage.
I threw all that away...
I don't need... those damn things!
The vehicle... Where is it?
There were still more of--
Is that Bessie?
It's too late...
She's dead.
I see.
What will you do now?
Wait a bit before I join you.
I need time to think.
I heard someone saying "Daddy."
I thought maybe she wanted him...
to save her...
Wait for me...
I'm coming... to save you...
What should I do?
I'm not your father.
As for what to do next...
You'll have to think for yourself.
Can you at least tell me
how to get to the orbital Permet lift?
What?
I don't want... to lose any more...
of the things...
that bind me to my father.
It was a modest idea at first.
As a botanical engineer,
Mistress Notrette thought
that the various survival strategies used
by plants could also be applied to humanity.
It was a dream
with no real basis,
but that was just like her.
And one of the people
who supported her vision...
was Delling Rembran.
Your father.
I always thought my lousy father
made a marriage of convenience.
He couldn't afford things like that
when he was a soldier.
The battlefield...
was so chaotic.
People abandoned their own will
and left decisions to their weapons.
Soldiers were consumed
as expendable parts.
I lost many comrades as well.
And that's why you began Gundam-hunting?
The restoration of human nature.
That's what the President desired,
even if it took drastic measures.
And yet...
even if he could control conflict
through war partitioning,
he never managed to achieve order.
That's why Mistress Notrette's vision
became a source of hope.
Until she was lost in that accident...
If he felt sad, he should have said so.
There was always some new enemy
or rebellion.
I finally get it.
I understand why my lousy father
set up that marriage game.
He thought it was safest to
marry me off to someone powerful.
And it was also
good camouflage for Quiet Zero.
The President...
intends to fulfill his vow
to Mistress Notrette
even if he has to use
the very Gundams he buried.
But you, Mistress Miorine...
Your life is yours.
You are not your father.
Please... follow your own heart.
Episode 16
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam the Witch from Mercury,
"Cycle of Sin."
Illustration: Akima