Asticassia School of Technology
We will now begin the duel.
The format will be serial battle.
If any of the challengers
should defeat the Holder,
that victor shall continue
battling subsequent challengers
and the last pilot standing
will be the new Holder.
This is an official duel,
approved by the Dueling Committee.
The witness shall be me,
the head of Peil House.
Elan Ceres at your service!
Yeah, yeah...
But why is Felsi Rollo
representing Jeturk House?
She's cramping my style.
Shut up!
Then why are you here
for Grassley House, Renee?
Isn't Ms. Sabina enough as your rep?!
Our house's roster isn't as thin as yours!
You two fangirls.
Ours is way larger!
Why don't you pipe down?
What?!
Secelia...
Please don't be rude to our observers.
Let's all play nice!
Mr. Elan has changed, hasn't he?
I'd say he's a different person.
Unlocking MS container.
KP028, Ebony Boas...
Azrawan, moving out!
Now passing Point N 138!
Entering tactical testing sector.
Fasten your seatbelts.
Hey, Nika.
Nika!
S-Sorry!
Opening hatch!
Suletta, are you ready?
Yes!
LP041, Suletta Mercury...
Aerial, moving out!
Both parties, face off.
Victory is never decided
by mobile suit performance, alone.
Nor by the skill of the pilot, alone.
The result itself is the only truth.
5th Tactical Testing Sector
Fix release.
Your bride will be mine, Mercurian wench!
Aerial!
No damage to Aerial!
Plenty of battery charge left!
You can keep fighting!
Roger. Continue to the next area.
It's a serial battle!
Rest while you can!
Right!
Second battle.
16th Tactical Testing Sector
To hell with your new look!
Everyone!
Look at that.
Can't they put up a fight?
Third battle!
8th Tactical Testing Sector
Don't let her catch her breath!
I'll at least score one hit!
Damn it!
Why does only the Mercurian...
It can't be helped.
After all, she's Mistress Holder
who crushed the three top branches.
Even so, this serial battle
is our best chance to beat her.
10th Tactical Testing Sector
Take advantage of the Holder's
dueling obligation, right, Rouji?
Watch it, you!
Haro...
As long as there are challengers,
the Holder must accept a duel
once every two weeks.
While the Aerial was being rebuilt,
five duels were postponed
by special exception.
One to go!
Enough is enough!
2nd Tactical Testing Sector
That should give
the challengers an edge, but...
I made a promise.
Until the day of Ms. Miorine's birthday...
I won't lose!
The rebuilt Aerial now surpasses
any other machine in the Benerit Group.
That mobile suit creeps me out.
No plans to challenge her again, Mr. Elan?
That's up to company policy.
I won, Ms. Miorine.
Episode 13
An Open Campus?
For three days, starting tomorrow,
prospective students will visit our school.
They'll experience mock classes
and lectures.
Current students
will organize events, too.
It'll be like a festival.
Wow!
What a joke...
They're having fun in total ignorance.
It's not their fault.
They really don't know.
All the media are reporting what happened
at Plant Quetta as an accident.
The whole thing's been hushed up.
If you talk about it,
you'll be expelled at once.
We were attacked!
We can't just let it go!
This isn't a fistfight.
But I can never forgive them!
It was terrorism!
Chuchu, keep your voice down.
But still...
How long will you two be moping around?
It's been two weeks!
Stuff it.
It was real combat...
wasn't it?
If we get... caught up in that again...
Don't worry.
Aerial and I are here with you.
Ms. Suletta?
Oh, I'd better go tend to the greenhouse.
Suletta seems in good spirits.
She went outside the plant
to help Miorine, didn't she?
Most people would freak out.
Company business is suspended, too.
When's she coming back, huh?
Benerit Group Front
Our illustrious president...
Recovery from a spinal injury
is a long-term struggle.
You'll need rest too, Mistress Miorine.
Thanks.
Just how long are you going
to sleep, you lousy father?
The crime was committed
by the Dawn of Fold.
They're an anti-Spacian group.
Is it true that Jeturk mobile suits
were used to carry out the attack?
We have evidence.
The machine is called a Desultor.
There's no mistake.
If your products are being
used for terrorism...
You must not be very
careful with your customers.
We're working to identify
the purchase route--
At the moment,
we're discussing your culpability,
Acting CEO, Lauda Neill...
Shaddiq, continue.
Besides the Desultors,
there were two machines
with unregistered Permet ID codes.
The GUND Format's parallel structure
was detected from both of them.
In other words...
Gundams.
The heinous actions of these Earthians
have left President Delling near death
and robbed us of our comrade Vim Jeturk.
They cannot be forgiven.
Discreetly but swiftly,
we must find those responsible
and settle this with our own hands.
This is a battle
for the dignity of the Benerit Group.
Now is the time to join together!
If the truth gets out,
our company's credibility will be ruined.
You really don't know where
those two Gundams came from?
I wouldn't lie to you, Father.
You're not to leave the campus
until things calm down.
You must also refrain from
taking part in duels or company business.
Shaddiq!
Was President Sarius angry?
I guess I've fallen behind
in the succession race.
You must've calculated on that.
Well, what next?
We'll drag my father into it.
Into my plan, that is...
Is that why you summoned... those two?
They'll be questioning Ms. Miorine
a little longer as a person of interest.
You won't be able
to speak to her just yet.
I can't call you
without permission either.
Do you think she's reading my emails?
Is the incident at the plant
still bothering you?
How did you know?
I'm your mother.
At that moment...
I can't help wondering
if there was a better way.
If you two hadn't gone to the rescue,
Ms. Miorine and the President
could have been killed.
You did the right thing, Suletta.
Right...
If you say so, Mom, then it must be true.
Of course. I'm sure
she'll understand eventually.
Thanks, Mom.
Have you found their source?
Nothing yet. I'll continue investigating.
Thank you, Godoy.
Ms. Nika?
Huh?
Oh, uh... s-sorry if I scared you.
Not at all. What is it?
I wanted to have a chat with Aerial.
Maybe get some life advice...
Too much has happened lately, right?
What about you, Ms. Nika? Are you okay?
Since we got back, you seem
to be lost in thought.
Like just now.
It's fine. Nothing important.
Don't you... want my advice?
I-I might not be able to help.
But Ms. Nika, you're...
a precious friend to me.
You amaze me, Suletta.
During the attack, too...
You boarded Aerial to go help Miorine.
I could never do something that scary.
I couldn't... stop shaking either.
But then, my mom was with me.
Your mom?
She always helps me move forward.
Like a gentle magician.
Run and gain one,
move forward and gain two.
It's the motto she and I share.
When you're afraid, Nika,
you too...
Thanks.
There she is!
Found you, Big Sis!
Uh... wh-who are you?
I came to meet you,
Big Sister Suletta!
You want to join our House?
Since we're Earthians, they sent us here.
Norea Du Noc and Sophie Pulone...
First-year Piloting majors.
It's odd to transfer schools
in the middle of the term.
Don't talk so freely
like you're one of us.
Now that stings.
Aren't we coworkers?
You didn't invite me
on your plant trip, though.
You sure do take things personally.
What do we do, Martin?
If they're Earthians,
they're welcome here.
What's more...
they've already moved in
with all their stuff.
This is your family?
This is my dad, this is my mom,
and these are my little sisters.
I actually wanted to bring more of them,
but Norea said it was too much.
You know...
I had no interest in going to school,
but I came here to be your friend.
H-How did you know about me?
Did you happen to see our PR video?
Well... I guess that's it.
So teach me all you know, okay?
Big Sister Suletta!
"Big Sister"?
Y-You got it!
Sophie, as your big sister,
I'll do my best to teach you!
All I know!
What's the meaning of this?
The corporation that endorsed you
is registered within the Group,
but it doesn't exist, does it?
That's right. We're just like you.
It's a dummy company
set up by the Prince.
What's your objective?
A go-between doesn't need to know.
No one in Earth House, including me,
wants to be placed in any more danger.
So please...
You talk as if
you're a victim in all of this.
We're grateful to you, at least.
Thanks to your efforts, we were able
to mount an attack on Delling Rembran.
I've heard all about you.
You wanted to become
a bridge between Earth and space.
What a lovely dream.
So let's work together
to achieve our respective goals.
That way, I guess
none of us will be exposed.
Suletta Mercury!
Today's the day
you finally go out with me.
Oh, um...
Today is...
Big Sis!
Over here!
Huh?
I wanna try that one next!
Big Sis is coming!
Better change my approach...
Sorry, I should watch where I'm going.
Shouldn't you be touring
with your friend?
I wanted to look around on my own.
What an inspiring campus you have.
Clean, well-circulated air...
A sky of vivid blue...
Lush vegetation...
Cheerful, smiling faces...
It makes me sick.
Sounds like we'll get along well.
Huh?
Some "go-between" I am...
At Plant Quetta,
you saved us all from harm.
Martin...
Even so...
As head of the House,
I'm responsible for everyone's safety.
If you're hiding something, then tell me!
It's nothing.
Nika!
I just didn't want to die,
so I sent a desperate SOS.
That's all.
Is there any point in
setting up our own booth?
We don't have many events like this.
It's a chance to promote
the company and make some money.
It might cheer up some of us too, right?
I agree!
Hey, what are you rotten
Earthians so happy about?
What do you want?
So Mistress Holder doesn't need
to worry about tomorrow's Rumble Ring?
This shoulda been a stage for Mr. Guel
to show off his super cool style!
Better be ready!
Our Jeturk House is gonna
smash you to pieces!
Screw you.
What's a Rumble Ring?
A battle royal-style mock battle
held on the last day of the Open Campus.
Current students can demonstrate their
skills and their company's mobile suits.
The Holder has to participate every year.
What?!
Didn't we tell you?
Have Nika show you
the video from last year.
Speaking of which, Nika's missing again.
I can't get hold of her either!
I'll go find her, then.
Now you mention it...
the transfer students
have disappeared too.
The Prince asked you to look into it?
This is a Gundam in a different lineage
from the Ur or Thorn.
If it'll be an obstacle,
we should destroy it now.
What about you?
Does Suletta Mercury have
what you were looking for?
She's great! Kind, too...
But even so, I don't feel
the same thrill I felt that day.
Access to the GUND Format is protected.
I can't get in.
Get away from the Pharact!
And not just that machine...
Leave our school immediately!
Did you find a record of
our communications or something?
You didn't, did you?
After all, you don't know
who we've been in contact with.
Then I'll tell them about me
and the dummy companies!
Be serious.
Now, now...
you wouldn't want to get in our way.
Step aside, Sophie,
However hard you try, you can't
change things on Earth by yourself.
And yet, you still cling
to those lofty dreams...
You're making light of the reality.
I'm not making--
Oh yes you are.
That's why you always feel
like you've been cheated.
You must have realized
that an Earthian orphan couldn't just
go off to school without paying us back.
I-I don't know what's going on,
but please don't do anything
to hurt Ms. Nika!
Oh, darn... We've been seen by Big Sis.
Is that Ms. Norea in Pharact's cockpit?
Why would you--
Hey! You can't just kill Big Sis!
K-Kill...?
The go-between may have
blabbed about our secrets.
Which means we should
get rid of these two right now.
Suletta! Run!
Ms. Miorine... forgive me.
I challenge you to a duel!
A duel?
If I win...
you won't lay a hand on Ms. Nika!
Are you stupid?
We have no reason to agree--
Yes, you do!
As long as you're students here...
then please follow the school rules!
Suletta...
Your duels are just a game
where no one dies, right?
Mobile suits are tools for killing people.
That's not true!
Gundams will be used
to save lives through medicine!
As you wish. You'll get your duel.
Sophie...
Come on, let's do it!
Our kind of duel.
We'll show Big Sis that Gundams
are just machines made for violence.
We both hate...
being confined here, don't we?
You...
What were you thinking?
Making your daughter
do something like that...
But didn't that act
save the lives of you and the President?
I'm sure Suletta was desperate.
I can't deny that she went too far...
but won't you be friends with her again
after all this questioning?
No need to tell me.
I came here today to ask you
to do me a favor.
Quiet Zero?
A secret project
that President Delling was pursuing.
Using the GUND Format's network,
we'll rewrite this into a world without war.
It's your father's greatest wish.
"Without war..."
What do you mean?
Miorine Rembran,
I'd like you
to take over the work of Quiet Zero.
Episode 14
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"What They Wish For."
Illustration: Ilya Kuvshinov