When Permet was discovered
within minerals,
its special information-sharing properties
became the basis for all these theories.
Today, it's responsible for controlling
and managing systems of every kind.
Excuse me!
Is it used in the monorail too?
Yes.
Permet links connect all the transit cars
on campus to central dispatch.
This prevents uneven data distribution...
LP041, Suletta Mercury...
Passed.
Suletta seems surprisingly cheerful.
I was worried when she lost
the title of Holder to Guel...
There's no way she's okay.
They took Aerial too, after all.
She must be hurting...
Then there's Ms. Miorine...
For things to end like that...
For today's lunch, I tried making
ramoodles with lots of toppings!
Let's eat!
Suletta, during today's class, you--
Was I cool?
Huh?
Asking a question in class in a cool way.
That was on your wish list too?
I can cross two things off today!
Going to class every day,
and eating lunch with all of you...
is so much fun!
Episode 18
Please!
Our company needs your support!
Your subsidiary merger plan...
Remind me, when it was due?
Financing is pointless
if you can't meet your goals.
Even for the son of Vim Jeturk.
It's no use.
The financiers won't say yes.
They must be thinking
I have no track record...
If you need a track record,
doesn't your company have a new
mobile suit model you haven't announced?
A new model?
A Gundam?!
Our next-generation concept model,
the Schwarzette.
I'd heard my dad
was developing something, but...
You snake!
You can't share Gundam
technology without my consent!
And you, Guel! Why didn't you tell me?!
It's news to me too, okay?!
It was before you acquired us.
He was so insistent that we go
into the drone business together.
And since Shin Sei was at the bottom
of the pecking order...
So? What are you proposing?
That machine...
Why don't you announce
it was developed jointly
between GUND-ARM, Inc. and Jeturk?
Then you can also promote
your union to the rest of the Group.
No can do.
GUND-ARM, Inc. won't be involved
in mobile suit development.
We decided that we'd use Gundam
technology for medical purposes.
To win the presidential race,
you likewise need a track record.
If you want to stick to your principles,
you should use them in your concept.
Please don't forget.
I know.
Now it's my turn to fulfill my promise.
Thank you very much.
Sure, but where are you, anyway?
At Grassley.
What?!
They were eager to chat.
And they insisted on inviting me...
Whaaaa?!
Dr. Winston...
Any progress?
Please give me a little more time
to adjust the programming.
Applying parallel distribution
is your specialty.
We'll continue to rely on you.
What in the world
is the mobile suit in this file?
It's exactly what the specs say.
A GUND-Bit in mobile suit form,
to expand Aerial's data storm network.
It's called a Gundnode.
My cooperation?
Yes.
We'd like to make Shin Sei's
GUND-ARM technology
part of the Group's core business.
Hasn't Grassley been a denier of Gundams?
If we're to quickly restore
our credibility,
we can't afford to be picky
about the means.
I hear you were unable
to recover the Gundam types
used in the attack on the Open Campus...
Yes.
It seems they had built-in
self-destruct protocols.
It's unfortunate...
If you wanted a Gundam,
wouldn't you try to obtain one
even in a damaged state?
Or could it be...
that their recovery would cause
you some inconvenience?
Shaddiq!
Why hello, Miorine.
Glad to see you looking well, Guel.
Shaddiq.
Dealing with Miorine's subsidiary
without her permission...
What are you trying to do?
Canvassing, of course.
I'm enlisting companies
to support my election as president.
You're running, too?
My marriage to you
didn't pan out, after all.
Congratulations on your engagement.
While you were all dueling,
I'd already earned Peil's support.
What?
Your opponents in the presidential race...
are two of the three branches.
The vote is in two weeks.
I'm looking forward to it.
I've checked the temperature
and adjusted sunlight patterns...
Oh wait, the fertilizer! That was close...
Suletta!
Yes?
Aren't you pissed off at Miorine?
She's succeeding the father
she hated so much,
and she threw you aside
for that Jeturk blowhard.
How selfish can she be?
Ms. Miorine did nothing wrong.
What?! But why?!
I'm the one at fault.
I broke my promise to Ms. Miorine.
It was foolish of me to think
I was ever a match for her.
How long are you going to
hang around here?
You creeps...
Both Miorine and the title of Holder
belong to my brother now.
Nobody needs you any more.
You empty Mercurian wench.
Watch your mouth!
I've no intention of fighting you.
What'd you say?!
Chuatury Panlunch.
You saved me during the Open Campus.
Thank you.
Thanks!
That's got nothing
to do with this, damn it!
Mr. Lauda is right.
Though I never had anything to begin with,
I called myself the Holder, and the groom.
It was all a mistake.
Why didn't I realize it before now?
You know that's not true.
Ms. Chuchu, what are you--
Let's go...
to see Miorine.
To the head office?!
We're going to meet with Miorine.
Martin, you hold the fort.
Feed the animals too.
W-Wait a second! All of you are going too?
Someone has to helm the ship.
You're still injured, right?
If no one stays behind,
we might get vandalized again!
Staying active takes our minds
off of things, right?
Ms. Chuchu!
I'm fine, really.
I've already accepted that Ms. Miorine--
Shut up.
Ow!
Listen!
It's wrong that you're pretending
you're okay with it!
Tell Miorine straight out
what's on your mind!
I won't accept anything less!
Right...
It's settled, then!
Let's go, Ms. Suletta!
Can't you just talk on the phone?
You've changed, Chuchu.
Huh?
You've always chosen fists
over talking things out...
What happened, huh?
I thought about what Nika would do.
When those Jeturk punks
thanked me earlier,
I think I finally understood
how Nika feels.
So, anyway... we're off.
If the bullies come back,
don't try anything crazy.
What are you drawing, eh?
Why should I tell you?
If you think I'm a threat, don't worry.
When it comes to Grassley
and the Dawn of Fold being connected...
I haven't breathed a word to anyone else.
Despite how I look,
I'm pretty tight-lipped.
Excuse me!
Huh?
You are Mr. Elan, aren't you?
You seem so different--
I'm a different person.
What?
I'm not the Elan Ceres you all knew.
You should have nominated me
as a presidential candidate.
The Peil Grade rendered its judgment.
It's not yet time
for you to take the stage.
An evaluation system?
Peil uses its own unique AI
to select the company's leaders.
The one who received the top grade...
was the real Master Elan Ceres.
But when these stupid
bride-catching games began,
he needed a backup
who could pilot a mobile suit.
In order to win duels?
There was that...
but also, we were initially guinea pigs
used to master Gundam technology.
Pilots implanted with resistance
to data storms.
That's us, the Enhanced Persons.
We still can't help dying, though...
Then, if you pilot the Pharact...
I'll die.
Anyone who pilots a Gundam will.
The odd ones here
are that Mercurian girl and her Aerial.
Tell me, what the hell are those two?
You sure know how to run your mouth.
There's no use hiding it now.
What about you? Is there any reason
for you to pilot a Gundam?
None.
Really?
I said I have none.
I see.
You're hollow inside, so you tell yourself
it's for the Earthians' sake.
Whoopsie!
I want to kill every
last one of you Spacians.
What other reason do I need?
You don't really want
to pilot a Gundam either, do you?
Shut your mouth!
Let's be honest with each other.
Since both our lives are so cheap.
All of them?
Yes.
Hurry with due diligence
on every facility on that list.
Aren't we selling these off
far too cheaply?
That's not as important as
my father's life.
The Earth companies
on the list are first priority.
The transfer of the Group's businesses
seems to be going well.
No one within the companies
suspects a thing.
I'll file a report
with the Space Assembly League.
He's way ahead of us.
It seems he's already gained
considerable support.
I expected Shaddiq would make a bold move,
but not that he'd team up with Peil.
I wonder if this will give you
any hints, but...
Though these initially looked like
protests by demonstrators,
armed Earthian groups have begun
attacking Benerit Group facilities.
The use of heavy weapons
has been confirmed...
Riots?
with both sides suffering losses.
They're protesting
the lack of corporate governance
This now appears to be a civil war.
regarding this terrorism.
It was enforcing unfair security measures
Explosions continue to be heard
and refugees line the streets.
in the name of criminal investigation.
Their anger... won't be ended by violence.
In that case, why don't we try ending it?
What?
We'll speak directly to the protesters.
If we can calm them down,
that'll be our track record.
You want to go to Earth?!
Naturally.
You'll be talking to armed people.
If you don't make a show of force,
you can't negotiate on even terms.
Then...
We'll use Aerial.
Aerial?
We'll follow school regulations
and won't bring weapons.
I won't let another Plant Quetta happen.
It will provide
a concept of our principles.
We'll demonstrate through this negotiation
that I and GUND-ARM, Inc...
that the Benerit Group of the future...
will save lives without fighting.
To Earth?
They intend to bring
the Quinharbor riots to an end.
Mr. Guel is awesome, right?
He reclaimed the title of Holder
right after re-enrolling.
Now I hear he's going to Earth...
I wish he'd been
the leader from the beginning.
When you've got it, you've got it.
And you've got nothing, right?
Shut up.
Excuse me!
I'm trying to get to my drop-off point.
Can you help me find my way?
Where are you headed?
Hangar 78.
That number is...
It's the one you at Shin Sei
always request at Plant Quetta.
Do you mind if we have a word?
I learned my friend was...
committing a crime and turned her in.
A crime is a crime.
As head of the House,
I wanted to protect everyone!
I've done nothing wrong!
I did the right thing, didn't I?
Huh?
Whoa!
You...
You're a double-crossing
little rat, aren't you?
I believe I advised you
to use your own judgment.
And we've decided.
Got a problem with that?
I'd like to have some of my men
join you for your own security.
Dominicus commander Kenanji Avery,
at your service!
Commander Kenanji?!
Yes. Something wrong?
Oh, uh... nothing.
Thank you for your assistance.
The pleasure is mine.
Well, well... you're not like
your no-nonsense father.
We told you, we want to see Miorine.
Do you have an appointment?
Why do we need an appointment
to meet with our buddy?!
Maybe we should just
turn in an application...
Suletta is here?
What should we do?
Eri?
Go get 'er!
Why does she need a normal suit, though?
Who knows...
What's Ms. Miorine doing here?
Aerial!
Why are you here?
Can I... come inside?
Everyone!
I thought I'd never see you again...
Ms. Miorine said
she didn't need me anymore.
No, it can't be helped.
I'm the one who broke our promise.
I've moved forward. Like Mom says...
But...
I don't know what to do...
I'm not the Holder anymore,
and I don't have to duel.
I study with my friends,
and we can chat together over lunch.
But even then, with Ms. Miorine gone...
it hurts not being able to see her.
"Move forward, gain two..."
Right now...
I can't believe that.
Where am I?
Mercurian year 154, day 63.
Today's game was "DiggingKing."
I won with a score of six to four.
You cried, wanting a rematch...
so Mom gave you hot cocoa
and one honey-flavored candy.
Aerial?
My heating unit was broken
from the solar storms,
so you took your half-empty mug
and held it to my cockpit.
You said it would warm me.
You're Aerial, aren't you?
Why do you look like me...?
The door has opened.
We don't need the key anymore.
Everyone? "Key"?
The key is you, Suletta.
Eri can only live inside the data storm,
so you filled in for her.
Eri has no physical form,
Eri's body, her arms and legs,
her extended consciousness...
That's us, the Children of the Coven.
What do you mean?
Filled in for her?
You're all repli-children
created from my genes.
17 years ago, when Mom...
Don't you remember?
But it's fine now.
Quiet Zero will create
a world where Eri can live!
So we don't need you anymore, Suletta!
No... You're wrong...
After all, I...
Do you understand?
At score eight,
I can move of my own free will.
I'll no longer need a pilot.
No...
And that's why
you can't cling to me anymore--
No! Stop! Wait a minute!
Not to me, or to Mom.
Aerial!
Suletta...
Mom?
It's not true, is it?
Is something wrong with Aerial?
No...
It's just as Ericht said.
Go back to the school, Suletta.
It has all you need to fill your heart.
Are you sure about this, Eri?
What if she came with us...?
You're right.
Suletta deserves to live freely,
doesn't she?
Episode 19
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam the Witch from Mercury,
"Not the Best Way."
Illustration: redjuice