I will now deliver Cathedra's response.
The request to press charges
over the use of GUND Format
in the mobile suit Aerial
has been rejected.
Why has Delling given
that mobile suit special treatment?
Why did he let it duel?
Why did he acknowledge their corporation?
Why isn't Dominicus doing its job
and hunting down the witches?
Our response won't change.
Please take your leave.
Delling's lap dog...
Didn't I tell you?
Cathedra won't get involved.
Did you come just to say that?
Two glasses of Chateau Latreille.
I'm in no mood to drink.
Consider it a pre-celebration.
Delling is going to die.
GUND-ARM... GUND-ARM...
A ray of hope
GUND-ARM...
Mercurian Miss!
Huh?
Mr. Shaddiq?
You're in a good mood.
Good news?
Well...
Ms. Miorine and Aerial will be back soon!
So that's it.
Well, once you have Aerial back,
I hope you can start dueling again.
Challenges have piled up
during its two-month absence.
I'll do my best!
Thanks for making a special
arrangement to postpone them.
Miorine's business trip was a long one.
Two weeks, wasn't it?
16 days and 12 hours!
And you're tending the greenhouse
until she's back?
Yes!
I told you, I'm relying on you.
Huh?
I can't look after them while I'm away.
Do it for me.
Are you sure?
Aren't they important to--
Who else can I ask?
Don't let me down.
You are one of a kind.
Go ahead.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Suletta!
Ms. Chuchu?!
Where did you wander off to?!
Did you forget about
the GUND prosthetic leg test?
That's right.
Our bodies aren't fully capable
of living in space.
Our company's GUND medical technology...
Martin.
The budget numbers are wrong.
can address those deficiencies!
What?
Yes!
That's right!
These are last month's!
Sorry I'm late!
What kept you?
Sit down here.
Sit here. I'll connect the legs.
Right!
Connection confirmed.
I'm releasing the unit lock!
Okay, Suletta. Try and stand up.
Whoa!
Watch it!
Are you okay?
Yes.
Then...
let's begin.
Now recording. Start whenever you like.
Are you ready?
Yes!
3... 2... 1...
Start!
Ankle joint articulation range looks fine.
What about knee axis load?
Within acceptable range.
Okay!
Stair zone, cleared.
Tilting tables, cleared!
Balance beam, cleared!
Last course!
Don't lose focus!
Right!
All right!
We did it!
You cleared the Class A standard test.
Is that good enough
to enter the medical industry?
It just means you're qualified for review.
And you'll have to deal with
safety standards and licensing.
Even so, if the use of GUND is authorized,
it can be applied to any kind of prosthetics.
When I first heard about a Gundam company,
I thought she was out of her mind.
Turns out our president's pretty good!
Ms. Miorine's always been really good!
All that's left is advertising.
We have to let the world know.
That's why we're making
a new PR video, right?
Suletta, did you get
permission for the shooting location?
Ah!
"Ah?"
Suletta... forgetta.
Was it funny?
"Tell a joke and make everyone laugh."
Whoa! Ms. Nika!
You checked another item off your list.
What's next?
This!
Keychains?
I've always wanted
to share matching accessories.
It makes me feel like we're close friends.
I see.
It's a present for Miorine.
Ms. Miorine would use it, right?
Huh? I-I'm sure she'll love it.
They're really cute.
Aren't they?
The moment I found them
at the school store, I fell in love.
I thought it'd look good on Ms. Miorine!
Good luck, groom.
Fundraising has gone well.
Financing through convertible bonds
was especially smooth.
Did you consider the risk of stock value
dropping at the time of conversion?
N-No...
Your plan could send
share prices plummeting.
Don't take people's trust lightly.
Right.
Reconsider diluting your shareholder ratio.
Think of other ways to procure funds.
Right.
A capital investment plan?
Yes.
For a two-month-old company,
you've done well calculating the cost-
effectiveness of your investment thus far.
Estimate the payback period
and continue investing.
You must be tired.
You're not kidding!
But then again...
Huh?
Never mind. Anyway...
Is this the ship?
It's been refurbished,
so the coloring is different.
I'm just happy to save on painting costs.
Now we just need navigation staff
to take it to the school.
You mean the destination...
isn't Earth this time?
I didn't think I'd meet you again.
We work a lot of jobs to make a living.
If you like, I can still take you to Earth.
I'll pass.
Too bad. But then, you do seem busy.
Well, I did start a company and everything.
Which means I constantly have to report
to my lousy father.
I'm hardly ever in class thanks to these
business trips, and I have to train employees too.
It's all such a hassle.
Sounds like you're doing well.
Not at all.
And? Just who are you people, anyway?
I thought your eyes were
on my rotten father,
but you've come to me now because
I started a Gundam company?
Is it Gundams you're after?
Or are you among those
who don't want them around?
If you guess correctly, I'll tell you more.
The Space Assembly League.
Oh my, bull's eye!
So the League can't leave
the Gundams alone, either.
We're still in the investigation stage.
I'm not your enemy.
Then how about being my ally?
He's going to kill President Delling?
The man is an oaf.
Someone like Jeturk could never
pull off anything that bold.
Father...
Why don't we get on board with this?
When the President is gone,
if someone from the three branches is Holder,
their stock plus Miorine's
will give them majority ownership.
But the Shin Sei Development Company
to which Suletta Mercury belongs
doesn't have enough for a majority,
even with Miorine's shares.
In other words...
Duels won't determine the next president.
A student like you should stick
to the dueling game.
If you fail, you'll lose
your position within Grassley.
I haven't forgotten my debt to you
for adopting an orphan like me.
I'll win. This time, for sure.
We're just asking to shoot a video!
You let Grassley House
use the roof, didn't you?
Rules are rules!
You won't give us permission
because we're Earthians!
What do we do now?
It's hard to film prosthetic legs
without a spacious-enough location.
Excuse me...
What is it?
What if we use the Dueling Committee Lounge?
Huh?
Wait... if she's the Holder...
She has the right to use it!
Great idea, Suletta!
You're the best!
Let's do it!
If the Mercurian wench hadn't come...
Three cheers for Suletta!
Mr. Guel would still be the Holder.
Suletta!
Things happen.
Let's go, Petra.
Is Mr. Guel still missing?
Yay, Suletta!
Where you have gone, Brother?
Hey, Bob!
Haven't you finished
cleaning the underside yet?
Sorry! I need a little more time!
Get a move on! Departure's in five days!
Departure?
We have to carry in some cargo.
You're going too!
It's at Plant Quetta, some kind of
big Benerit Group factory.
Benerit?
That a problem?
No...
It's got nothing to do with me.
GUND-ARM... GUND-ARM...
A ray of hope
GUND-ARM...
Sophie!
Norea.
Take a look at this.
Asticassia... A mobile suit?
That thing's a Gundam.
Is this... a witch?
"GUND-ARM, Inc." they're calling it.
They're making a joke of it.
"It can fly! It can dance! Aerial!"
Sophie, where's Naji?
In his garden, I'll bet.
Naji!
Call from the Asticassia School!
The Prince wants to talk directly.
Directly?
Contacting me without the go-between?
Where's your usual caution?
That should tell you how vital this is.
What is it?
We want you to attack Delling Rembran.
You're asking us to kill your head honcho?
In five days...
Delling will arrive at Plant Quetta.
Go into space and attack one of
Benerit's greatest development bases...
Isn't that too hard a job for Earthians?
The patrol fleet defending the base
is under the Jeturk company's control.
They've agreed to soften security.
I want you to prepare something for us first.
The flight route and a ride for us.
I'll be in touch once I've seen the details.
Thanks for setting this up.
Your father figure says hello.
Right...
Why are these dorks
from Earth House in the lounge?
Hey, Rouji!
Rouji!
It sure is pretty.
Patent application number
AST876754...
Excuse me, we're filming right now.
One strength of GUND
treatment is that it can extract...
...the user's intentions from...
Ms. Miorine is so cool!
...comprehensive biological data.
She even does interviews!
Thanks to this strength, we believe...
Yeah, Ms. Miorine is amazing!
...we can enable you to...
She suddenly seems way beyond us.
...physically adapt to...
She was never really close.
...the space environment.
Yeah, yeah.
She’s a thoroughbred and we're weeds.
So she's grazing on us?
Exactly!
She'll overwork us and consume us
for her own nourishment!
It's nothing to laugh about.
Huh?
She'll grow beyond you too.
That's not true!
Oh! How do you know?!
She has the confidence of a lawful wife!
I'm not the wife! I'm the groom.
Suletta!
An outsider like me
shouldn't be handling this,
but since Ms. Nanaura isn't here...
Ms. Belmeria...
Yes?
Um...
Thank you very much.
You work for Peil, and yet
you've been helping us.
I originally aspired
to become a medical engineer.
So I'm very happy to take part
in your business efforts.
It's a win-win, then!
That's right.
About your recent duel with Grassley House...
Back then, you--
Excuse me!
It's time for the water temperature check.
It must be hard having so much to do.
No! Not at all!
I'm off!
Take care!
Suletta Mercury?
Mr. Elan?
Long time no see.
Um, is it okay for you to be here?
Yes. I've finished my errands for Peil.
I'll be returning to school from today.
I'm glad to hear it!
I saw your company's video.
You looked very cute.
I mean it.
U-Um, Mr. Elan...
Have you changed somehow?
I have indeed. Thanks to you.
Oh, um...
Why don't we go on a date?
A date?!
You don't want to?
No, that's not...
That's not it, but...
But?
I, uh...
What about Ms. Miorine?
I see.
But that's all a lie, isn't it?
Everyone's gossiping about it.
You're being used as a shield so
Miorine can avoid getting married.
You two may end up married in name,
but her heart won't be in it.
So I'm sure...
she'll forgive you.
I-I'm really sorry!
She ran away, huh?
Still, a little push is all it will take...
to win her over.
All we want is that Aerial mobile suit.
We've no need to challenge it
in the open like Grassley or Jeturk.
That new enhanced person...
why did you choose him?
Because he has a personality
as wicked as yours.
He startled me.
What happened to Mr. Elan?
He was kind of frightening.
You can't!
You can't be here! Please leave!
You can't trespass in the greenhouse!
I'm the one who was asked
to take care of them all!
Hold it, we were--
Ms. Miorine told me herself!
She had no one else to ask! That's why--
Suletta?
Huh?
Ms. Miorine?
What the heck are you doing?
You've already gotten back?
I bought a spaceship.
Since I didn't have to take
a public flight, I got home sooner.
As per our estimate,
it's going to cost this much.
Send the invoice to the company.
Ms. Miorine, those men...
I hired some farm workers
to take care of my plants.
I'm only going to have more business trips.
That's one less chore for you, right?
I thought this was important to you...
and you were relying on me...
Thanks for that.
You did a good job.
By the way, did you run into Elan?
Huh? D-Don't worry!
You're my only--
What are you talking about?
Mr. Elan asked me on a date.
But I made sure to say no!
It's fine. Go on a date.
Huh?
He's going to be your colleague,
so try to get along.
Oh, and no more duels with him.
My colleague?
Since he has experience as a Gundam pilot,
I decided to hire him.
It's nuts for the company to have
only one tester, right?
Now I won't have to ask you for everything.
I don't need to be here?
I guess not.
Right...
That makes sense.
I've been getting wrong ideas all on my own.
That's right... about Aerial.
I'm going to pick her up at Plant Quetta.
You should come too. I bet you're excited.
You're going to see Aerial again.
I've been waiting for you,
Delling Rembran.
Here's your food!
You kept us waiting, Bob!
I'm sorry.
What about you? Have you eaten?
No... not yet.
Do it before we arrive!
Your body will need it.
Thank you very much.
Objects detected by navigation surveillance!
Confirming Permet ID codes.
They're mobile suits!
From Plant Quetta?
No response on intercommunication channels.
They're heading straight for us.
Sound the alarm.
That's...
They should be making contact about now...
I guess.
You sound indifferent.
Are you sure this is
the right time to be making waves?
We've never given much priority
to the dueling game, anyway.
Shaddiq always intended to do this.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
We're going to break up the Benerit Group.
I won't hesitate...
any longer.
This ship is now under
the control of the Dawn of Fold.
We demand that all of you
cooperate immediately.
Or feel free to resist...
if you want to die.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"The Witches from Earth."