You have to win this duel,
so you won't be expelled
and I won't be forced to marry.
I don't want to.
What?
It only makes sense for us
to fight together now!
My list...
I made a list of things
I wanted to do when I went to school.
Make friends,
call them by nicknames,
study in the library,
eat lunch on the roof,
and...
go on dates.
What's that?
I want to go on dates!
You're sex-crazed.
I-I can't go on dates once I'm married!
Whyever not?
Cheating is wrong!
Calm down!
It's not going to happen right away.
The legal age for marriage is 17.
Which means it won't happen
until my birthday, at least.
R-Really?
I'm going to escape here and
go to Earth, no matter what.
You just have to play my groom until then.
Let's make a deal.
Welcome back, young master.
How did you like the Darilbalde?
What the heck did you do
to this mobile suit?
We added a 5th-generation
Decision Making Extension AI.
It's still a beta version,
but it makes composite Bayesian
predictions from previous combat data--
Am I not skilled enough to win?
Dad...
I gathered these staff members
as well as the Darilbalde
just to make you win.
There's no room here for childish pride!
If you want to be treated like an adult,
then win and reclaim the title of Holder!
Yes, sir.
Say, Mom. What's a Gundam?
What's this all of a sudden?
People from the Benerit Group
say that Aerial's a Gundam.
And they even call me a witch.
Is it true?
I don't recall raising you as a witch.
Neither do I.
Of course, I know about that past
incident, and about Gundams.
But you and Aerial
aren't like that, Suletta.
You're my precious daughters.
Your mom will vouch for you.
Now, don't you have to leave yet?
Oh, no! Well, good luck at work, Mom!
Thank you. Good luck to you too.
Suletta.
Look, there she is.
The Mercurian girl.
I heard the duel's being redone.
The one who cheated?
Ms. Suletta Mercury!
Good morning!
Th-Thank you for your--
I was watching it!
Your mobile suit was amazing!
What?
What kind of layer structure
is it using for its swarm control?
Is it a conventional one?
Or is it based on
a simultaneous spatial concept?
My mom said something about
"using successive spaces concurrently..."
So that's it! Now I understand
the concept-synthesizing schema.
It enables it to clear the friction--
Hey! Mercurian wench!
Our last duel was voided.
Now we'll settle things for real.
Ms. Suletta?
W-Well, if that's the case, then...
My opponent will be...
Me.
That's a relief.
A relief?!
W-Well, you know, I already won once...
Don't get carried away, you bumpkin!
W-Well then, I'll be going!
What?
Ms. Suletta!
Your help in the inquiry was invaluable.
Thank you very much.
You blackmailed me. Don't be sarcastic.
Let's not meddle in each other's
business from now on.
How did you know
about the assassination attempt?
Call it a trade secret.
Why didn't Delling object
to Shin Sei's request?
Vim Jeturk's defending them
bothers me, too.
Prospera Mercury, representative
of the Shin Sei Development Corporation.
She belonged to the Mercury Development
Group, married in the field,
and gave birth to Suletta Mercury.
Injuries to half her body
from a resource mining accident...
So that explains
the headgear and right arm.
She's officially in charge
of development, too.
How would she find funds
and infrastructure in that backwater?
There's no record of her
registry as a mobile suit engineer.
In that case, who could have
built that machine?
Shaddiq.
You look into the daughter.
Yes, Father.
Things are getting interesting.
All done.
I'll leave the fertilizer here.
Bring it to me.
You don't mind if I come in?
Go ahead.
Does this mean we're best friends?
-Huh?
-
Sorry!
Well, whatever we are,
if you lose that duel,
it's over for both of us.
I'm sorry.
Suletta Mercury.
Mr. Elan, right?
Th-Thank you for...
I came here to summon you
to a Dueling Committee meeting.
A committee?
This guy's a member
of the Dueling Committee.
I didn't know how to reach you.
May we exchange contacts?
Number 12 on my list came true.
Your list?
Exchanging contact info with someone.
It was something I wanted
to try when I got to school.
What else is on your list?
Making friends,
calling them by nicknames...
Going on dates.
Ms. Miorine!
I hope...
you'll fulfill many wishes on your list.
Welcome to the Dueling Committee Lounge.
My name is Shaddiq Zenelli.
Nice to meet you, Mercurian Miss.
Nice to m-meet...
Shall we begin?
What?
The oath.
For the duel.
Both parties,
deposit your souls on Libra's scales.
The duelists are Guel Jeturk
and Suletta Mercury.
The location will be the
7th tactical testing sector.
The one-on-one code will apply.
Any objections?
None.
Suletta Mercury,
what is your stake in this duel?
Our duels require you each
to place something on the line.
Money, an apology, a woman...
You're the only one who'd bet women.
I'm not as bad as you think.
And I know they'll always
demand I give the girls back.
Suletta Mercury.
Oh, right!
Um... please apologize to Ms. Miorine.
Guel Jeturk,
what is your stake in this duel?
Same as last time.
Alea jacta est.
The duel is approved.
How nice for you, Mr. Guel.
When you have powerful parents,
you can even undo the results of a duel.
You'll have no excuse
if you lose this time.
If I were you, I'd reconsider.
If you want to duel me,
just say so, Secelia!
I'm giving you advice.
I don't want to see
your market value drop any lower.
Or has it already bottomed out?
Stop it! No!
Mercurian Miss?
L-Laughing at someone
who doesn't run away is...
It's wrong!
Why would you say something like that?
Don't you want to laugh at me, too?
It's because "If you run, you gain one."
F-For example, if you're facing
a strong enemy,
by running away,
you'd gain safety and security.
I wouldn't run.
But if you fight, you might lose!
I wouldn't lose!
The last time was a fluke.
It wasn't a fluke.
If I hadn't let my guard down,
I would have won.
Which is another way
of saying you lost, right?
But either way, it's okay.
What? What's okay?
If you move forward without running,
you gain confidence in yourself,
or experience, or recognition.
You gain a lot more
than you would by running.
That's why "If you run, you gain one."
And, "If you move forward, you gain two."
That's quite a philosophy.
My mother taught it to me.
My mother is always strong and kind.
A good parent, huh?
Yes. My life's goal is to be like...
I don't get him.
Mr. Guel!
Your machine is ready!
Please give that bumpkin
a beating she won't forget!
Brother.
This isn't a duel just for yourself.
You haven't given up on
being the ace pilot of Dominicus, right?
I haven't. And I'm going to win at any cost.
Permet link established.
Armament, all green. I ate properly, too.
Suletta?
M-Ms. Miorine!
I registered myself in your contacts.
How could you just...
Look, don't you get it?
Your future and mine depend totally
on this duel's outcome.
Don't forget the deal we made.
Right.
Dad, only students are allowed
to be involved in duels.
This is company business.
Anyway, did you make the arrangement?
Yes, but...
But what?
My brother doesn't need
tricks like that to win.
Have they started?
Any minute now.
I wonder who'll win.
It's got to be Mr. Guel!
Once Jeturk House gets serious,
there's no stopping them.
With mutual consent by both parties,
we will now begin the duel.
As always, victory will go
to the first one to break the blade
antenna of their opponent's mobile suit.
The observer
shall be Elan Ceres from Peil House.
You can come out of your MS container.
State your name and student ID number.
Right! LP041.
Suletta Mercury, Aerial, launching!
Both parties, face off.
Suletta Mercury...
Y-Yes?
Please recite the duel vow.
The vow?
I taught it to you just now!
Um...
Victory is never decided
by mobile suit performance alone.
Nor by the skill of the pilot, alone.
The result itself is the only truth.
Fix release.
I'm going to win
and I'll stay at this school
with Ms. Miorine!
That's a diversion. The drone-like things
are coming from three o'clock...?
What the...
What just happened?
I'll be hit!
He deflected it?
This thing...
It's not a Dilanza?
Understand that an outdated Gundam
is no match for our company's Darilbalde.
Is that a different mobile suit from before?
That just means they're serious.
Don't lower your guard!
She got behind him!
No way!
Are you saying...
you don't need my will at all?
It dissipated.
Is this water?
Is it the heat management system?
Yes.
Abnormal heat detected within front.
With that much water being dispersed...
beam weapons will inevitably be degraded.
Emergency water cooling in progress.
Take a good look!
My plan was right on the money!
Too bad for you.
Lady Luck is on my side this time!
There's no way the system would start
spraying water without an anomaly.
Those Jeturk House thugs.
They'd really go this far?
Stop the duel immediately!
You should only resume after
you've corrected the system error!
Duels are never held on equal terms.
What are you saying?
It's up to students' patrons
which mobile suits and which
support staff they can access.
Even if this accident were set up on purpose,
that would still be part of his strength.
In that case, you'll allow me to be
part of Suletta's strength, won't you?
Suletta, do you read me?
Ms. Miorine?
I'll stop the squall!
Just hang on until then!
But how?
Just don't let him beat you!
My lousy father...
This time, I won't let things
turn out as he pleases!
A mobile craft?
"Hanging on" is easier said than done...
Suletta Mercury,
if you really are a witch,
you can survive this situation.
I've got to hang on. I've got to hang on.
I will hang on!
She's safe!
But it's still only a matter of time.
It looks like the game is over.
In the end,
the winner is always
the one with the stronger backing.
Darn! That was so close!
Heck, she dodged again. What?
I knew it would be you two.
Miorine?
Using a mobile craft isn't fair!
Look who's talking!
I mean, never mind!
It stopped?
Hey! What's going on?
Suletta?
All that's left now is for you to win.
Thanks, Ms. Miorine!
Aerial...
Now it's our turn!
Go! It's 8.6-to-1 odds!
Blow the Spacian away!
She's not from Earth either.
You fool! Don't stop!
No way you'd be tricked
by a decoy that cheap!
Guel!
What are you doing? Finish her off!
Dad?
How did you...
Was that heat management thing your doing?
Dad! Why won't you believe in me?
If you want me to believe,
then crush that Gundam!
Do you think I can't win if I play fair?
That's the child in you talking.
The result is all that matters!
Brother, just focus on the battle for now!
You're only saying that for Dad's sake!
Why don't you understand
this duel is bigger than just you?
Children should do as their parents say!
Shut up!
The Decision Making Extension AI
has been disabled.
That fool!
An error? But...
This is my fight!
It's mine.
Only mine!
His moves are different from before!
This guy is strong...
But Aerial and I won't lose!
After all...
Guel Jeturk cannot lose!
There's still so much left
on my wish list!
SULETTA MERCURY WINS
Ms. Suletta, you're really amazing.
Ms. Miorine!
M-My screen is filled with words!
So many words!
So many words, many words!
Why did you release all messages?
So many words!
I said, only from registered contacts.
You won. We won.
Right.
Now you won't be expelled!
Then Aerial and you are both... safe?
That's right!
Take that, you louse of a father!
G-Good news, right, Mio-Mio?
Excuse me?
I'm sorry!
What the heck is "Mio-Mio"?
Calling a friend by a nickname
was near the top of my list, so...
It's cute, isn't it?
Rejected. It's super lame.
Th-Then how about--
Rejected!
I didn't even say it yet!
E-Excuse me...
I-I'm sorry!
I underestimated you.
Well, you were, you know, really strong.
Suletta Mercury...
Will you...
marry me?
What?
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"Unseen Trap."