Shall we begin deceleration thruster control?
Doesn't checking for hazards
on the docking course come first?
Does it?
I'll check the operations sheet.
You're right.
Can we really make it to Plant Quetta?
It's the perfect distance
for a practice flight.
Whoa! Now what?!
Aliya, there's an emergency
call from Room 11.
Tiko and the others...
I-I'll go check on them!
Huh? But...
You can rely on me!
Thanks!
Ms. Suletta sure is wound up.
She's probably excited to see Aerial again.
You think that's it?
Gotta work hard.
Gotta work hard!
Gotta work hard... Gotta work hard!
Otherwise, I'll...
I'm really counting on you.
In fact, I want you to lead
our next project, Nika.
Not Ms. Belmeria?
I'll ask her for support.
But I want you to surpass her.
Thanks for overestimating me.
Unbelievable...
I... had to hide.
Sensor post 098.
Detailed observation to airspace area 08.
Respond to administrative bureau...
A nearby ship...
...for pre-docking inspection.
…has reported an unidentified object.
Halt your ship in the specified area.
It may be a tool dropped...
Wait for an inspector to board.
...by a worker outside the plant.
At the customs clearance platform...
A recovery team is on standby.
…submit in the designated format...
If necessary...
...names of hazardous cargo...
We're here!
We somehow managed it.
Maybe we should have more confidence?
We practiced ship navigation in class, right?
Could someone take this cargo for me?
I'll do it!
Thank you. I owe you one.
I'll do my best!
Thanks again.
Gotta work hard. Gotta work hard.
Gotta work hard.
Useless.
Huh?
I-I'm sorry!
Just look at this app.
It's beyond useless!
Don't complain.
We went for price over performance.
Ms. Suletta!
Are you okay?
It seems Quiet Zero is coming along well.
You brought a Gundam here
just so you could confirm that.
Didn't you, Lady Prospera?
Call me Elnora Samaya...
if you prefer.
In that last duel with Grassley,
Aerial's permet score reached six.
GUND-ARM, Inc. has also
served as good camouflage--
Show me your right hand
this instant, Lady Prospera.
Even though it's been more than 20 years,
are you still afraid of witches?
Rajan...
This reflects Aerial's
network architecture pattern.
With this data, Quiet Zero
can proceed to its final stage.
Right now, it's still my project.
But of course.
Mr. Olcott.
Transfer of additional
armament will be finished soon.
Install Beltablads
for me, Bessie, and Gristan.
Norea!
Where's Sophie?
The bridge.
She's with Naji.
We won't take any lives.
We simply want to discuss
the disparities between Earth and space.
Let's discuss, shall we?
Why are you guys piloting Desultors?
Bob?
Those are Jeturk mobile suits.
They may be outdated,
but they're not something
terrorists like you could easily obtain.
Bob, cut it out!
This is the real thing.
You were watching me just now, weren't you?
Let me give you a closer look.
Stop it, Sophie.
Whatever.
Are you okay?
Don't do anything crazy!
If you want the ship, you can have it.
But let my employees go.
No.
We'll be needing your cooperation.
Settings complete.
It's nothing much.
Just go about your work as usual.
While keeping quiet about us…
Do your work as usual.
Everyone!
Lunch is ready!
Thank you!
Boy, I'm hungry!
I bought a lot. Take what you like.
For me...
Sounds good!
Chicken over...
What'll it be?
Oh, my bad.
G-Go ahead!
It's fine. You were first, Suletta.
Go ahead!
Yeah, but...
Please!
If you say so... thanks.
Suletta!
What did you choose?
Are you going to eat all that yourself?
Idiot. I'm taking these to the bridge.
For Miorine and Nika.
For Ms. Miorine?
Want to come with me?
Oh, uh... no, I'm fine here.
Suit yourself. Well, I'm off.
What?
There's none... left...
Hey, don't talk with your mouth full!
What do you care?
You're talking too, aren't you?
Nuno!
I brought one for you.
Eh?
I have one already.
Huh? Wait a minute.
I guess this is lunch.
It's no one's fault.
I must have miscounted.
In that case, we'll use
Hatch 3 to load Aerial.
I'll take a video. Let Suletta know.
Can't you tell her yourself?
Why?
What happened between you and Suletta?
Don't say it like I did wrong
Not everyone can be like you, Miorine.
What's that supposed to mean?
The request Sarius made to press
charges for GUND Format use...
I hear it was rejected.
Was that on your orders, Mr. President?
It was Cathedra's decision.
That may be the case.
However, Sarius won't give up that easily.
Eventually, he'll try to crush
your daughter's company.
Grassley should be sanctioned
for stirring unrest.
And of course, I'll gladly cooperate.
For the future of the Benerit Group.
I'm told your eldest son, Guel Jeturk,
has yet to be found.
Rather than my daughter,
perhaps you should worry about your own--
There it is!
That's the reason I've never liked you!
Some ex-soldier butting in
from outside and claiming everything!
Mr. Jeturk!
If it was stolen from you,
you were merely too weak.
Then I'll steal it back!
And when that happens,
you'd better not complain!
Please take your leave for today.
So he won't take the bait...
I planted a transmitter on Delling's guard.
I'm now leaving Plant Quetta.
Begin the operation in two hours.
Right. Two hours from now.
It must be tough being adopted.
Do your best to win Daddy's love.
That old man has some nerve. What a jerk.
He gives me the creeps.
Sabina!
Send the signal to the Dawn of Fold.
Tell them to begin immediately.
Roger that.
Huh?
What about the two hours?
We've received the go-ahead code
through the secure line.
The Prince has given us the green light.
Let's begin.
I'll wait in the cockpit.
Sophie?
Norea!
This girl is amazing!
Look. She fought six-on-one!
How long are you
going to watch these videos?
Let's go.
Gundam!
It can fly! It can dance!
Aerial!
Suletta Mercury...
I'd love to meet her.
I wonder if I ever will.
The Captain?
It's true! They say he was an ace pilot.
He couldn't even fit
in the seat with that belly.
I was thinner back then.
Captain KenanjI!
Dominicus was created to correct injustice.
That includes talking behind
people's backs.
W-We're sorry!
What is it?
Captain...
We've detected a fleet ID code
on a standard course to the Moon.
It's a Jeturk ship.
Its name is Wormblood.
From the plant patrol fleet?
Why would it be there?
Where's Suletta?
Huh? Now that you mention it...
With Aerial, maybe?
Yeah, that makes sense.
Unbelievable...
Where did she disappear to now?
Ma'am.
You're here too, Bel?
I came to retrieve Aerial.
I was informed of that.
How nice that GUND medical treatment
may finally become a reality.
It's thanks to Suletta and her friends.
My daughter does me proud.
Mom?
We've arrived at the plant.
I heard. Bel was just here.
I see...
Suletta, is something wrong?
Huh?
You didn't call me
just because you're here?
Well, um...
I'm kind of scared.
Of what?
Of everyone.
Oh my, I thought you said
you were making friends.
That was a misunderstanding.
I was just carried away.
Actually, no one trusts me with anything.
They don't need me at all.
Is that what they told you?
Not exactly...
But… when I started to think
that's how they see me...
Everything I thought was fun...
The things I enjoyed...
They all turned against me.
And now...
they're scary.
Suletta...
Are you crying?
It's weird, right?
I didn't mean to...
You're caught up in your worries.
C Block, Hangar 78.
Huh?
Your mother and Aerial
are waiting for you there.
Come say hello.
Yes! I'm coming! Right now!
Uh, I'll call you again when I get there!
I-I-I'm on my way!
I heard everything.
What are you doing, sulking in here?!
S-S-sorry!
Just tell me if you have a problem!
Ms. Miorine!
It wasn't on purpose!
Get back here!
Quit running away!
B-But...
If you have something to say,
then say it to my face!
There's nothing!
There's nothing I want to say!
Liar!
Wait! Stay put, already!
You...
and your… freakish stamina!
Ms. Miorine?
Are you okay?
Gotcha!
Th-That's a dirty trick!
It's called cunning, stupid!
Is it because I'm stupid…
that you won't rely on me?
Huh?
I...
I'm useless,
a weed to be eaten,
and you use me as a shield.
When I couldn't eat
a chicken over rice lunch,
I didn't have the courage to say
there were no lunches left.
What are you talking about?
If this is how it is,
I never should have come to the school.
Why are you putting yourself down?
What happened to your motto?
Move forward, gain two, right?
I can't...
Why the heck not?!
I can't do it all the time.
Moving forward is always... scary...
That's why I say it... to push myself.
Someone like you, Ms. Miorine...
would never get that.
Never--
You are so stupid!
Y-You called me stupid again!
Don't tell me you know what I was like!
I was sick of all of it!
The duels and my lousy father!
That's why I wanted to run!
I wanted to go to Earth!
What are you talking about?
It's because you became my groom!
You and your stupid
"move forward, gain two!"
Now I have to run a company,
listen to my father's infuriating criticism,
and bow my head!
I-I'm sorry!
You're the one who doesn't get it!
Don't you see I'm happy like this?!
It's because of you that I don't
have to run away anymore!
So...
Don't run from me.
If you have something to say, say it!
Annoy me like always and move forward!
Ms. Miorine...
Say you want me to rely on you.
Is that... okay?
You'll do that?
Say it!
Um...
Okay.
Please... rely on me.
Stay at my side forever.
Right. I'll stay.
And don't lose any duels.
I won't lose. Ever.
And give the tomatoes more compost!
Sorry?
Use the Andes model for the sunlight pattern.
Clean my room twice a week!
And email me three times a day!
Ms. Miorine, are you crying?
Don't look!
But...
You don't believe what I'm saying?
I believe it.
Because...
I'm your groom.
Plant Quetta to shipping vessel Kashtanka.
Your ship is now entering
plant security airspace.
Please maintain docking course.
This is Kashtanka. Roger.
Awaiting pre-docking security inspection.
Olcott!
We're within range
for the comms jamming pods.
The time lag for the cloaking
program is five seconds.
It should be fine
from this distance, right?
Roger, Bridge.
Olcott, Desultor, send me out!
Bridge, we're now beginning the operation.
Bessie, Gristan, let's move.
Copy that!
Mobile suits detected within
the front's restricted airspace.
There are three of them.
Permet ID codes?
No corresponding codes found.
They're unregistered machines.
Contact the front management company.
This is Front Control.
Attention, mobile suit pilots.
You are not authorized to use
mobile suits in restricted airspace.
Repeat.
You are not authorized to use
mobile suits in restricted--
Comms jamming pods deployed.
To the outside, it'll look
like a signal failure.
Switch to hopping transmission.
Sophie! Norea!
On it!
Sophie Pulone, Lfrith Ur...
Norea Du Noc, Lfrith Thorn.
Beginning operation.
Lame.
Huh? Don't you think it's cute?
Not at all...
But, whatever.
It just looks like a gift from you.
Are you sure about this?
You know, don't you?
Miorine is inside Plant Quetta.
Our only target is Delling.
If luck is with her, she'll survive.
Emergency warning B-1 issued.
I can't get a signal.
Please evacuate...
...to the indicated shelter.
What's happening?
We may be under attack by hostile forces.
Repeat...
"Hostile?"
Emergency warning B-1 issued.
Who the hell would attack here?
How am I supposed to know?!
Emergency warning B-1 issued.
They could be terrorists.
Please hurry.
You must take shelter.
We should evacuate, too.
No.
Prepare Aerial for activation.
Don't worry.
I won't leave you behind.
Norea! Before we deployed the pods,
we detected the target signal in C Block.
Let's do it.
Roger.
Time for some carving!
Sophie?
Follow my timing.
You follow mine! I'm going first!
That damned adoptee double-crossed me!
How was that?
Bridge.
C Block has been disconnected.
Confirmed.
Norea, you rendevous with Olcott's team.
We'll disable all the ports.
Copy that!
Sophie, you provide a diversion as planned.
No way!
Sophie!
We just have to kill that Delling guy, right?
So let me take the lead!
That fool...
Ms. Miorine!
Suletta...?
Ms. Miorine? Ms. Miorine!
Wh-What do I do? What do I do?
A mobile suit?
What the heck?
What in the world? What the heck is that?!
Suletta Mercury?
I get to meet you already!
How cool is that?
Nice to meet you, Ms. Witch from Mercury.
I'm Sophie Pulone,
a witch from Earth.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"Keep Marching on Instead of Running Off."