Guel's dueling again?
How many is that this month?
Five, maybe?
Defending his position
as the groom can't be easy.
Still, in Guel's case...
he gets into a lot of dumb fights.
Why's Shaddiq just sitting on the sidelines?
Shaddiq gets as cautious
as a hedgehog around Miorine.
I hear you failed another escape attempt.
These stupid duels...
What a bunch of creeps.
Am I company property or something?
Screw them all!
I'm different, you know.
So you have no intention
of becoming the Holder?
No. The whole thing's a bore.
Good.
I don't want to marry anyone
from the group, anyway.
I swear, before I turn 17...
I'm getting out of this place.
This is a new low!
Are you kidding me?
They change the rules just
to stop us starting a company?
Is it because we're Earthians?
Who cares about the rules?
Let's do it anyway!
But if we do that,
we could all be expelled!
What do you think
they're talking about in there?
This is quite good.
It's tea from Ms. Aliya's hometown...
or so I'm told.
Earth-grown, huh? No wonder.
So?
What did you want to say?
Why don't you seriously consider
what we discussed in private the other day?
P-Private?
You mean joining forces with you?
Here's the business transfer agreement.
You'll remain president of the company.
Your team will still handle
management and operations.
The rules only apply to new startups.
An already-existing company
can get away with it.
For you, Miorine, it means
maintaining the President's trust.
And you, Mercurian Miss,
get to protect the Aerial.
I'm satisfied as long as I get
a piece of the Gundam business.
Not bad, right?
May I ask one question?
Of course.
Are you the one who rewrote the rules?
Why would you think that?
It's all too convenient. For the both of us.
I know that's the way
Shaddiq Zenelli does things.
And what of it?
Do you have a better proposal?
Who else will come to your rescue?
There is one thing I can do.
Something unique to this school...
could provide a simple solution.
Don't do it.
Shaddiq Zenelli...
I challenge you...
to a duel!
For real?
Both parties, deposit your souls
on Libra's scales.
The duelists are Miorine Rembran
and Shaddiq Zenelli.
The location will be
the 4th tactical testing sector.
Six-member team battle rules will apply.
A team battle?!
Our House doesn't even
have that many mobile suits!
Making arrangements is part
of your dueling prep.
My brother never refused a duel,
no matter what the conditions.
You have a Gundam. That should be enough.
Lauda's making this personal.
Brotherly love can be such a burden.
My stomach is churning.
I have one condition.
This duel must be transmitted
by live streaming outside the Benerit Group.
Outside?
Our company's pilot and mobile suit
will have crushed all three branches.
What better advertisement could there be?
Shaddiq, what do you think?
Fine with me.
Then it's accepted.
Miorine Rembran,
what is your stake in this duel?
Change the startup regulations back.
Shaddiq Zenelli,
what is your stake in this duel?
The ownership transfer of GUND-ARM, Inc.
Alea jacta est.
The duel is approved.
Lilique Kadoka Lipati!
Yes?
I want you to join the duel.
It's time you learned
which one of us is better.
Lilique, did you do something to her?
Beats me.
Whoever thought people
would be gambling on us?
Grassley House has never
lost a team battle.
Even I'd bet everything on them.
We don't have enough mobile suits, do we?
I'll ask Ms. Belmeria for help.
We'll borrow the Pharact or something.
What about pilots?
We only have Suletta and Chuchu.
You do it, Martin. You're the House leader.
No way! Gundams kill their pilots!
Th-They do not!
I was asked to join, so I guess I will!
You never hesitate, do you?!
Why, thank you.
That wasn't a compliment!
The meeting is adjourned!
I'm going to think of a strategy.
If you know anyone who could be
a support pilot, then ask them.
Yes, ma'am.
Where the heck did Nika
go off to at a time like this?
You're disgusting.
Everyone was motivated
to do their best for the company.
I never wanted to duel.
Then why--
That doesn't concern a go-between.
Forgive me.
I'll try to persist in talking a bit more.
Support... support... support... support...
Mr. Elan!
Oh...
He isn't back yet.
Watch where you're going...
country bumpkin.
Oh, I-I'm so sorry!
I was lost in thought.
About the duel with Shaddiq?
How did you know?
This school loves to gossip.
Oh, um...
E-Excuse me!
What?
P-Please... help us with the duel!
We...
We don't have enough pilots.
So we're looking for support...
I can't.
What?
My father...
has forbidden me to duel.
Your father...
He's important to you, isn't he?
I understand.
You love him... right?
I love my mother too.
We'll do the best we can!
Sorry to bother you.
Support... support... support... support...
There's still time to call off the duel.
I find it hard to believe
you care about Gundams that much.
Your words...
just don't sit well with me.
After transferring the company...
I'll remain the president...
You say it all with a smile
like you're helping me.
But in reality...
You only want me to be
the symbol of the company.
That way, the rest
of the group can't interfere.
Just like my lousy father
and the others.
You only see me as an ornament.
That's not true!
Stay out!
I can't trust you.
Huh?
are you coming from
Ms. Miorine's greenhouse?
Talk some sense into your bride.
What?
The only one who can protect
Miorine now is you, her groom.
Don't let her fight a battle she can't win.
If I'm her groom...
I'll believe in my bride.
In that case, I won't hold back any longer.
Suletta Mercury.
Your Gundam and your bride...
I'll take them both.
Forgive me.
Four Zoworts is all I could send you.
The Pharact is still under maintenance.
Not at all. Thank you for
talking to Peil's management.
Good luck.
There's no way you can
give them the Pharact.
If they found out about us,
there'd really be an uproar.
I also have a message from the old ladies.
If you insist on helping them,
you'd better bring back results.
I know.
Maisie...
you don't think
I'll get in the way, do you?
Ireesha's such a scaredy-cat. Look!
It's true!
Her hands are shaking already!
...a victory party?
All together?
That's a promise!
Renee, no calls before a duel.
Don't make me repeat myself.
Where's Shaddiq?
Giving the Michaelis a final tune-up.
Conducting sensor integration
data processing check.
No problems with link to control system.
Shall we begin?
All units approved for launch.
A team battle?
It's Grassley!
That means Mr. Shaddiq!
Mistress Sabina!
Miss Maisie!
Ms. Ireesha!
Mistress Henao!
And everyone's favorite...
Miss Renee!
Arrived at designated point.
No objects in vicinity.
All units cleared for launch.
Roger. I'm opening the MS containers.
Okay!
I'm ready for this!
Let's do our best!
Why me?
I never wanted to be a pilot.
No dangerous objects in vicinity.
You're cleared for launch.
Roger.
KP014, Sabina Fardin...
LP012, Ireesha Plano...
LP011, Maisie May!
LP013, Renee Costa...
KP015, Henao Jazz...
KP003, Shaddiq Zenelli...
Heading out.
With mutual consent by both parties,
we will now begin the duel.
The observer shall be
the leader of Jeturk House,
Lauda Neill.
Six-member team battle rules will apply.
Victory will be determined by breaking
the blade antenna of a team leader.
Both parties, face off.
Victory is never decided
by mobile suit performance, alone.
Nor by the skill of the pilot, alone.
The result itself is the only truth.
Fix release.
Ms. Miorine.
Are you sure you want me
in the vanguard?
Our opponents are the
top guns in the piloting department.
Without you on
offense and defense up front,
we have no hope of winning.
If things get hot,
use Martin and the rest as shields.
Got it!
You people are devils!
Chuchu, support everyone from the rear!
Yeah, yeah. I get it!
What?!
First, take out the sidekick.
She's stopped moving! Renee, Henao, Maisie!
Copy that!
They got past me?
Don't be mad at me, okay?
They're coming our way?
Help!
If you play with fire,
you get burned!
Two down!
Lilique Kadoka Lipati!
I'll show you what happens when
you lay hands on another girl's man!
Wh-What are you talking about?!
John Van Simmons!
Number 12 on my list of backup boyfriends!
Umm...
Oh, if you mean
the lunch invitation, I said no.
Where do you get off embarrassing my man?!
What?!
That was close!
Mr. Till!
Lilique, run!
For a mechanic, you've got
good instincts. However...
Three down.
Mr. Till!
That's four! How's it feel?
They didn't last a second.
How are Martin and the others?
They're fine.
But all four machines are disabled.
Their weapons were taken out, too.
Why am I...
Dad?
Dad! I...
Guel...
I've made arrangements
for your withdrawal.
Huh?
A position awaits you
at one of our subsidiaries.
You'll learn how I do business from there.
Wait a minute, please! What about the duels?
Do I just give up on Miorine?
I can't have faith in you
after three losses.
I have a backup plan.
Don't be so presumptuous
as to question my decisions.
Your swarm weapons will never work!
Huh? Your...
Where did your right arm go?!
Ms. Chuchu!
Better stay put, Gundam!
Don't underestimate Earth House!
Forgive me.
That's five.
Chuchu!
This is your last chance.
Accept your defeat.
Miorine's recklessness has
endangered your precious family.
Will you risk its destruction?
How could you say that?
Don't you have feelings for Ms. Miorine?
Well, I believe in her!
Miorine, you chose wrong.
The Mercurian Miss is a sweet, honest girl.
She never tells lies.
But...
she doesn't have the power to protect
you. Or the vision to support you.
She's just clinging to you
like a mere child.
I've cornered her. Take her down!
Roger!
Huh?
Suletta?!
Antidote?
Anti-GUND Format protection...?
Who knew they still had it?
Grassley is so persistent.
Aerial?
Everyone...?
What's wrong?
I have to do it alone?
But I can't! Not on my own!
Without the GUND Format,
she's nothing special.
Down you go! Mercurian wench!
Ms. Suletta!
Lilique...
Huh?
Mr. Till?
I'm sorry, Aerial.
You're angry, aren't you?
I always rely on you for everything.
But this time...
I want to give it a try.
For the sake of the company
Ms. Miorine made for us...
I want to do my part!
It's not on my wish list...
and I don't know what I can do, but...
Is that selfish?
I'm glad.
You're still there.
The Antidote...
has been overridden?
The constraints aren't working.
You're just a broken piece of junk!
Do it together?
No. It's fine.
This time, I know I can do it.
Suletta?
Let's help Ms. Miorine together, shall we?
Seeing our moves?
Where next? Here?
What is this?
You're...
some kind of freak!
Wow.
So you're a Gundam?
Shaddiq!
Get away from that machine!
You'll never get Shaddiq!
Sabina!
Maisie! Ireesha!
Draw away the GUND-Bits!
I won't let you...
get in our way!
End of the line, Suletta Mercury.
I'm the one who will stand at Miorine's side!
Now!
Huh?
Everyone!
I told you not to underestimate Earth House.
Dumbass.
I thought you'd try to finish
the battle with your own hands.
You tell me to trust you...
when you don't trust anyone yourself.
G-Gundam!
It can fly! It can dance!
Aerial!
This is incredible!
Our views are skyrocketing!
It's thanks to the live stream.
Save the details for later!
To the official founding of GUND-ARM, Inc...
Congratulations!
I'm sorry, Aerial.
For always doing this to you.
All signed.
I pledge I won't cause any harm
to your company from now on.
Right. Bye, then.
I should have dueled for it
from the beginning.
No amount of whining
will get you this company now.
Not for that... but for your hand.
"I'll become the Holder
and protect you myself."
If I'd only said those words,
maybe you'd have let me in.
Fool...
Too little, too late.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"Circling Thoughts."