Wumei! Osh! Synchronize your timing!
Roger!
Osh! Above you!
Now this is something.
You don't often see Elan accept a duel.
I wonder if a certain someone's
bad habits are contagious.
Three against one...
Just how conceited is he?
Show some pride, Daigo House!
Are you gambling on this again?
I bet 200,000 that Elan loses.
Just try and shake them off!
Osh! Wumei!
Damn it...
Looks like he won.
My 200,000...
How lame. Losing three against one...
You've got it wrong.
They played right into Elan's hands.
It's burning, you know. Extinguish it!
Biological data for
Enhanced Person Number 4
is all within normal range.
With these results, we can
move on to the next phase.
And what about the other witch?
Even in her previous duel with Jeturk,
we couldn't identify
a GUND Format data storm.
It's possible that machine has cleared
the greatest issue with Gundams...
the bioethical concerns involving pilots.
I wonder whether it's the
mobile suit itself that cleared it, or...
It seems we'll have to
investigate directly, after all.
Let's have Enhanced Person
Number Four act on our behalf.
He must be able to figure out
whether or not that thing is a Gundam.
Isn't this what we prepared him for?
Wow!
I never knew you could
optimize frame action this way.
It's too complicated.
I can't make heads or tails of it.
Nuno! What are the systems like?
The level of integration is
worthy of the gods themselves.
How many first-class engineers
worked on this thing?
I can't believe they had that kind of budget.
You really are thrillingly mysterious.
This stone is your mother.
It's really big.
Right...
I don't see any sign of your father.
My father... well...
I'm told that he died when I was very young.
I apologize if I hit a sore spot.
Not at all!
Is this stone... a brother, maybe?
I don't have any.
Hmm...
What could it be, then?
Can you also read fortunes
for people who aren't here?
Their birthday.
Just tell me the person's birthday.
I don't know it.
Mr. Elan?!
H-H-H-Hello?
Oh, yes. That sounds fine.
Right. Yes.
What?
In that case, uh...
What's wrong?
H-He, uh...
He wants me to go out with him.
On a date?
N-No! That's not it!
He just asked if I'd like
to go somewhere on our next day off.
That's what a date is, dummy.
Ms. Suletta!
Did you turn down that other proposal...
because you're really after Mr. Elan?
N-N-No!
That's not it!
Both of them are really popular.
But who'd have thought
the Ice Prince would make a move.
Ice Prince?
Elan.
He never shows any emotion, does he?
Be it anger or a smile, nobody's
ever seen it on his face.
But a lot of girls are
into cool guys like that!
Sounds suffocating.
If I were you, I'd kick him to the curb.
Well, Suletta's the one he asked.
He never smiles?
What's wrong? Calling at a time like this...
It's just...
I might go out on my next day off.
And, uh...
I...
Sound like you're making progress
on your wish list.
You're going with a friend, right?
Actually, it's...
someone I don't know all that well.
And yet you're going out together?
It's weird, right?
Not at all.
You want to learn about
someone you hardly know?
Is that what it is?
You've made your mother happy.
Isn't this what I taught you?
Move forward, gain two.
Right.
Go have fun.
Thanks, Mom.
Was that your daughter?
She seems to be enjoying school.
Do you need something?
Peil Technologies is making its move.
It's sooner than we expected.
True synergy of man and machine, is that it?
The balance trajectory graph
doesn't correspond
to any attitude control patterns.
And its reactivity is far too organic
for the drive system it's using.
So you think it's body-augmentation control?
The ideal form of the GUND Format.
Normally, a task level this heavy
would instantly kill the pilot
with a massive Permet influx.
Which means that Suletta Mercury
must be an enhanced person.
A human created
for the sole purpose of piloting a Gundam.
Just like me.
This is no time for your grievances.
Is her face borrowed from another, too?
Wait... Are you happy about this?
You're the ones
who asked me to look into her.
If the physical examination is done,
I'm going back to class.
Before you try battling the Aerial,
I'd like to test the Pharact.
We'll need you to arrange another duel.
I'll just follow your orders.
All right! Set it down just like that!
It's ready!
Ms... Chuchu!
You're really going dressed like that?
Mr. Elan said to bring Aerial too.
A chaperoned date, huh?
Suletta! The container can go
whenever you're ready.
Thank you very much!
On behalf of Aerial,
I can't thank you all enough
for the repairs...
Suletta!
What the heck are you thinking?
A date with Elan?
Oh, no!
Ms. Miorine!
Hurry aboard, Ms. Suletta.
I told you the three branches
are our enemies, didn't I?!
Now, now...
Have fun on your date!
Make sure to ask about his birthday!
Let go!
I-I'm off!
This is between me and Suletta!
Suletta!
Don't you dare go
all Romeo and Juliet on me!
Hey,
what's Mr. Elan doing here?
I wonder...
Go ask him.
No way!
G-Good morning!
I see you came on time.
Let's go, then.
Right!
Mr. Guel!
You won't believe this!
What is it?
The Mercurian girl is going
on a date with the Ice Prince!
With Elan? Don't make me laugh.
It's true! Somehow, they've...
Felsi.
Where did they go?
I'm sorry about this.
My Zowort... is under repair
after the last duel.
Not at all!
If I... can be of help...
I'm happy!
Inspecting the testing sector is also
the job of the Dueling Committee.
Can you go around in this order?
You got it!
Impressive piloting skills.
Not at all. I just...
How long with this machine?
What?
I'd like to know more about you.
I've always been with her.
Since I was a child.
Always?
Did you ever struggle or suffer?
While piloting, I mean.
There wasn't any suffering...
I rather felt at ease.
We've always been together,
from childhood onwards.
To me, Aerial is like a good friend.
Or even family.
That sounds weird, right?
Uh... Mr. Elan!
P-P-Please tell me when your birthday is!
Can you do me a favor?
Huh? Sure...
I'd like to pilot Aerial by myself.
What?
I won't be rough with one of your family.
So...
Maybe he did this...
to avoid talking about his birthday.
I can expose the truth.
Whether or not you're a Gundam.
Permet score...
Two.
I knew it.
This is the GUND Format.
No, wait...
It lacks that sensation.
Like a hand reaching
so roughly into my brain.
The Permet isn't responding.
Which means, the one
who has lifted the curse is...
Suletta Mercury...
You're nothing like me!
Mr. Elan!
I-I'm sorry!
You didn't want to tell me your birthday?
That's something...
I've never had.
Do you mean...
your mom never told you?
How you annoy me.
Your mobile suit is like family?
These things are nothing but a curse to me.
I thought we were alike,
but you and I are...
Elan!
You bastard, what did...
what did you do to her?
Depending on your answer...
You'll ask for a duel?
What?
Perfect timing, Guel Jeturk.
I challenge you...
to a duel.
Both parties,
deposit your souls on Libra's scales.
The duelists are Guel Jeturk and Elan Ceres.
The location will be
the 11th tactical testing sector.
The one-on-one code will apply.
Any objections?
None.
No objections.
It's been a while since we've seen
a duel among the three branches.
Guel Jeturk.
What is your stake in this duel?
That this jerk stays away
from Suletta Mercury.
I see.
H-Hey, that's... none of your business!
Don't you get it?
This guy is your enemy.
He's from the three branches!
Doesn't that go for you too?
I...
Heck.
Mercurian Miss.
This duel is between Guel and Elan.
It's not your place to interfere.
Yeah, but...
If you're unhappy with the result,
then fight another duel yourself.
Those are the rules that govern this school.
Elan Ceres, what is your stake in this duel?
I...
Suletta Mercury.
If I win, I will fight a duel with you.
Very well.
Alea jacta est.
The duel is approved.
Hey! Stop right there!
Who the hell just boarded Lauda's Dilanza?
Actually, it's...
Brother!
You're forbidden to duel!
If Dad finds out about this...
If I win, Dad will have nothing
to complain about.
Why the heck are Elan and Guel dueling?
It's perfectly obvious!
Right, Ms. Suletta?
That's...
That's not it.
This is a good development.
Let them destroy each other.
You really are mean-spirited.
KP001, Guel Jeturk.
Dilanza... let's go!
This won't end well.
If the CEO finds out...
Please abort the duel!
My brother is not permitted to fight.
The duel is invalid!
We already gave Mr. Guel authorization.
Forgive me, Lauda.
I too want to see this duel.
What?
A black Zowort?
I don't think so.
That one is...
KP002, Elan Ceres.
Pharact, going out.
Peil House has a new model, too?
Damn rich kids.
Both parties, face off.
Victory is never decided by
mobile suit performance alone.
Nor by the skill of the pilot, alone.
The result itself is the only truth!
Fix release.
The new model flies too, huh?
Even so!
In low gravity, the Dilanza can do that too!
Whoa!
Look at them...
Go! Odds are 1.4-to-1!
I can't believe you bet on that guy.
He's fighting too violently.
Look at all the clouds of sand
charged with static electricity!
Regolith...
Damn it.
You'll be my assistant
in testing the Pharact.
What?
A Gundam?
Permet score...
three.
What the...
D-Damage!
No, it's not that.
Functions are restored?
That looks like...
An electromagnetic stun beam.
So this one uses drones too!
Those are no drones.
They're...
The GUND Format.
It's been so long...
Old friend.
So there was another witch all along.
Damn it... in that case!
As long as they don't touch me,
this is nothing!
You wish.
I'll make it through!
I did it!
He fell into Elan's trap.
Elan used the conductivity
of the electromagnetic beams
to give the regolith an electrostatic charge.
When the dust adhered
to the joint drive parts,
it created an overload.
The key factor was actually caused
by Mr. Guel himself.
Stop...
The only way to defeat a Gundam...
I said stop!
...is with a Gundam.
I tripled my wager!
I can't believe this.
All right!
H-Hello?
Mr. Elan, you...
I won. Suletta Mercury.
As promised, you will now fight me.
Promised?
Suletta, did you...
The stakes of our duel will be...
the Aerial.
If I win,
your Gundam will be mine.
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury,
"A Gloomy Song."