Yes... Take it to the
Benerit Group's head office front.
I have an idea for a pilot.
How many days has it been?
I could use a shower.
How long are they going to keep us here?
Until they let us relocate...
It's not like we did anything wrong...
I'm so sick of this.
Does everyone have enough blankets?
If you need one, speak up!
I'll take one.
Sure!
Why are you doing all this, huh?
Because I can move around!
Hey! Could we have some, too?
Oh, right!
Mercurian Miss...
Have you changed?
I guess so.
Episode 21
How's Petra?
They say she's still at risk.
They're going to save her, aren't they?
She'll be okay, right?
I can't get hold of Mr. Lauda, either.
I'll try contacting him myself.
You guys get some rest.
Damn it...
This is an analysis of that machine...
There's no doubt
it's the same Gundam as before.
I couldn't find anything that would
let us identify the pilot.
That we didn't notice
Shaddiq Zenelli was harboring them...
was a failure on our part.
I guess the Space Assembly League
will make its move now.
Having learned that
Miorine Rembran has been chosen to be ...
At a time like this...
next president of the Benerit Group...
Where's Miorine? Is she back?
Yes.
But she has yet to...
I heard what happened at Quinharbor.
Where did I go wrong?
The town was destroyed...
and so many people...
Don't shoulder everything yourself.
It's not your fau--
It was me.
The people on Earth...
and the school...
it's all...
Right now, Rajan is speaking
to the board members.
We have to set
the Group's direction.
Also...
We have Shaddiq in custody.
I hear you're going to be president.
My condolences.
Is that all you have to say?
How are Sabina and the others?
They're all unhurt.
It was all my plan.
I'd like you to go easy on them.
It was too dazzling.
Your ideal of putting Earth
and space on equal terms.
That's why you did it the wrong way.
Still, someone has to do it.
Even if it's just so there won't be
more people like us.
When did you involve
the Assembly League?
I made contact long ago.
But I suppose
I decided to cross the line when...
What a fool.
Do you think I'm despicable
for using even cowardly means?
No.
I'm just as guilty.
I can't eat this stuff anymore.
Isn't there anything better?
Not likely, in this state.
I want something different!
Here you are!
Huh?
What are these?
They're tomatoes!
I can tell that by looking at them, but...
Please, just take a bite.
Bite in!
Y-Yummy...
Huh? Seriously?
It's good!
Right?
Yeah!
I should've listened to my mom...
and gone home sooner.
Here.
Thanks.
Don't thank me...
Thank Suletta.
Hey, Suletta...
Yes?
Wasn't the greenhouse crushed too?
Well, the truth is...
I was refrigerating
the ones we hadn't eaten.
Whoa! This is awesome!
That's quite a lot.
What should we do with them?
Since the power is still unstable,
maybe we should hand them all out.
Sounds good. Let's do it.
Don't you have to ask Miorine?
I'm sure Ms. Miorine would say,
"Just hurry up and do it."
Yeah, sounds like her.
Thank goodness we had all these carts!
We'll carry everything to the tents!
Let's go back and get ready
to hand things out.
I'll help!
Nika!
I've been thinking...
we need to talk one more time.
Um...
I...
Once the recovery work
is done, I'm dropping out.
Oh, but that doesn't mean
I've given up on school.
First I have to turn myself in
and make amends...
then I can return to school
in my own right.
I still don't want to give up on the dream
of bridging Earth and space.
I'm so sorry.
It's not like I wanted
to punish you, but...
What was I supposed to do?
If I'd been alone, I'd have given up.
But since I met you all...
Because you opened my eyes, Martin...
I can keep trying.
If you're ever in trouble,
you can always tell me.
I'm the head of the House!
Thank you.
Have some!
Thank you very much.
LP041, Suletta Mercury...
I guess that's about everyone.
Right...
Suletta!
Ms. Belmeria and...
Are you Prospera Mercury's daughter?
Yes.
I'm Guston Parche, an inspector
of the Space Assembly League.
Assembly... League?
An administrative body that mediates
political problems among the fronts.
What does a bureaucrat like you
want with us?
There's something we'd like to ask of you.
The combat actions at the school front
that endangered civilian students...
The Space Assembly League Front
The abduction of Grassley's CEO...
These were all crimes committed
within the Group.
And the armed suppression of
anti-Spacian demonstrations on Earth
has resulted in many casualties.
Furthermore, we've confirmed
they were secretly developing Quiet Zero,
a weapon of mass destruction.
At present,
the Benerit Group can only be called
a threat to peace among the fronts.
The courageous whistleblowing
of Peil Technologies is to be commended.
For the peace and tranquility of
the fronts, the Space Assembly League
hereby proposes a forcible intervention
against the Benerit Group for the
purpose of dissolving the conglomerate.
By the unanimous consent
of all members,
and under the authority of
Article 7 of the League Charter,
the forcible intervention
against the Benerit Group...
is hereby approved.
According to their joint statement,
the League will act to resolve
the unrest within the Benerit Group...
Peil chose now to jump ship...
Haven't you been able to
track down Prospera Mercury yet?
We searched Shin Sei's terminals,
but all data about Quiet Zero
had already been erased.
What about the Mobile Suit
Development Council and Cathedra?
They've decided to second
the Assembly League.
It's from President Sarius.
I'm glad to see you're well, Mr. President.
Never mind the pleasantries.
This is about the Assembly League.
The situation is frustrating.
Cathedra can no longer hold them back...
You should have learned
more from Delling.
You must cut off me and Grassley.
Huh?
Pin all the responsibility on us
and minimize the damage.
But that means...
You must think of the Group's
continued existence first...
Miorine Rembran.
I can't do that.
I never want to sacrifice...
anyone else.
Quiet Zero?
It's a system that establishes and extends
a data storm network deployed by Aerial
and mobile suit-type GUND-Bits.
All systems that use Permet
will be under its influence.
Data storm...?
Is there anything that
doesn't use Permet?!
No. At least not in the fronts.
But doesn't that mean this whatsit
will take over everything?!
Prospera Mercury plans to use Quiet Zero
to create a gigantic data storm network
within the Earth Sphere.
If control of the fronts is lost,
at worst, there could be
massive loss of life.
We must stop her before Benerit
and the League come into conflict.
I ask for your cooperation, too.
Reasoning with Mom...
is probably impossible.
That can't be true.
Surely you, her daughter...
I'm not her real daughter.
Huh?
Wait, wh-what are you...
You're adopted?
Oh, uh... well,
we're genetically related, but...
Suletta--
It's fine.
I want everyone to hear.
About my mom, me, and...
about Aerial.
To my mom, there's only one
real daughter... that's Aerial.
Or rather, Ericht.
Oh, and Ericht is...
sort of my big sister, or...
I guess I'm what they call a repli-child,
made from Ericht's genes.
Long ago, Mom was researching
GUND technology.
But when the Vanadis Incident
happened 21 years ago...
she fled to Mercury with Ericht.
Ericht's body was weakened,
and she was about to die.
That's when Mom used GUND technology
to transfer Ericht's
biometric code to Aerial.
That means Aerial is now... Ericht's body.
But it seems Ericht can only live
inside this data storm thing.
So Mom's trying to create a place
where she can live freely.
They said I was just a key
to get to that point.
I loved my mom dearly.
I still do.
Thanks to Mom, I was able to go to school
and meet all of you.
But what's most precious to Mom...
is Ericht.
No matter what I say,
I don't think she'll listen.
I'm sorry I can't be of more use.
If there's another option
than reasoning with her...
Huh?
There's a machine the Assembly League
confiscated during the Vanadis Incident.
It's a Gundam
they nicknamed a "monster"...
We'd like you to pilot that Gundam.
Hold it!
You mean the Calibarn?
That machine has no filter
against data storms!
When she operates it, she'll...
If persuasion's out of the question,
it's our only option.
Would you just back off, Ms. Belmeria?
Nika?
At Peil, how many pilots did you
sacrifice in your Gundam experiments?!
Like Elan Ceres...
Now you're making Suletta expendable?
No. That's not what I--
Then why?
I don't know.
Huh?
Shameful, isn't it?
For an adult my age...
On that day, 21 years ago...
If only I'd died with the others...
I've had that thought again and again...
But still, I...
Forgive me.
I'm so sorry!
You're too selfish.
Suletta, you can't pilot that thing!
Why didn't I realize until now?
Huh?
I've never been under
the Gundam's curse...
because Ericht was taking it on herself.
It must be...
Only Ericht... was able to
fully synchronize with the data storm.
That's why you were never affected.
I...
want to talk to Ericht.
And with my mom, one more time.
Suletta!
Wait a minute!
Do you really have to do it?
You might die!
Ms. Ericht won't protect you this time!
When I was handing out the tomatoes...
I realized something.
Even if I don't gain anything,
I have to do what I can.
Take me there.
To the Gundam.
Aerial and Quiet Zero
have established interconnection.
Are you ready, Madam President?
Yes.
Let's go.
Attention all ships! Go to Level 4 alert!
We're entering the fleet's
combined search area.
Permet ID codes detected
near Lagrange 2 satellite cloud!
Are they Benerit vessels?
No...
Something bigger than that.
Don't tell me... that's...
Quiet Zero?!
What do we do?
We'll capture it, as planned.
It'll be good evidence
for our accusation of Benerit.
Fleet-scale Permet ID codes detected.
All belong to the Assembly League fleet.
Eri...
Please.
Objects from Quiet Zero!
They appear to be mobile suits.
Cargores...
Launch.
Are these things unmanned?
Assume anti-drone formation!
No use! They're too maneuv--
Quiet Zero receiving
multi-layer calls from all elements.
Beginning creation of data storm space.
We've lost control of our Permet links!
The fleet command system is inoperable!
We've been overridden.
What?
Come on! Move, damn it!
Move!
You damned witches!
Override of all Assembly League vessel
and mobile suit systems complete.
Well done.
Thank you, Eri.
It's finally begun.
The world I'm creating for you!
The Assembly League fleet...
that easily...
Announce a state of emergency
to all of Lagrange 4.
Evacuate from this sector...
Not again... More lives...
We'll arrange it at once!
I...
The entire fleet was destroyed?
What? No way!
Is this Quiet Zero thing that crazy?
At least we've pinpointed their location.
We'll approach via
the head office front--
Hold it, old man!
Take us with you, too.
You can let us leave this front,
can't you?
"Old man..."?
Ms. Chuchu, a minute ago, you...
Of course, I'm still opposed to it!
But that's why we can't
let you go alone, Suletta.
I...
Huh?
...will never again...
abandon one of my housemates!
How nice.
Take me with you, too.
Mr... Elan...?
Why... are you here?
With security this tight,
there's no way I could escape alone.
There's somewhere I want to go.
If you'll let me walk away,
I'll lend you a hand.
Though I refuse to pilot a Gundam.
Has he changed personalities again?
Yeah!
I'm sorry for messing with you
all those times.
My apologies.
Will you tell me about
the Mr. Elan I knew?
As much as I know myself.
Thank you very much.
I really hate... being an adult.
It's her fault.
Petra... the school...
and how my brother changed...
Miorine!
Next time,
Episode 22
"The Woven Path."
Illustration: LAM