Ms. Miorine!
Suletta...?
Ms. Miorine? Ms. Miorine!
What in the world? What the heck is that?!
Suletta Mercury?
I get to meet you already!
How cool is that?
I'm Sophie Pulone,
a witch from Earth.
That mobile suit...
Tell me, Ms. Witch from Mercury...
Where's the Aerial?
It must be here. Show it to me.
Oh, I see.
You can't hear me.
In that case...
Hurry up, now!
You'd better get in the Aerial quick!
Or else you'll die!
Suletta!
Madam President?
They're close.
Ma'am...
are you really sending Aerial into battle?
Isn't rescuing Suletta
and the others more--
The girl will come to us.
After all...
Aerial is here.
Emergency warning...
...B1 issued.
This isn't a drill, is it?
Of course not! It's a B-1 warning!
Then that means...
This is...
It's war.
Check on damage to the propulsion units!
Send out the Dilanzas!
Mr. Jeturk! We're glad you're safe.
I'll pilot one! Prepare it now.
Right. But sir, that's--
I won't let that Grassley brat
make a monkey of me anymore!
The President is supposed
to evacuate to Shelter 51.
You must protect him.
Commander Rajan.
We're ready when you are.
To the President's rescue.
Hurry.
Norea Du Noc, reporting for rendezvous.
Right on time.
Olcott!
We've detected four
mobile suit ID codes in D Block.
It's Dominicus.
Roger, Bridge.
Sophie!
Suletta Mercury!
Huh?
The girl from the video! I met her!
She's here in this plant!
Is it fate?
The Asticassia girl?
Sure feels like it!
Sophie!
The Witch Hunters are coming.
As planned, you keep them occupied!
What?!
Aren't we all going together?
Scared to go alone?
If you need any help, don't hesitate to ask.
You're joking!
Olcott! A plant garrison
force is approaching.
There's eight of them.
We'll intercept.
Shoot them all down!
Copy that!
I'm sure I can open the bulkhead
from the control center!
Don't move!
Mistress Miorine?
What are you doing here?
Why are you dressed like that?
What?
You have to wear
a normal suit when evacuating.
Why not worry about your daughter first?!
All units, we will now
enter the plant's interior.
An enemy?
Just one. Don't let them escape.
Fan out!
Here they come, here they come!
I'll blow them all to bits!
Permet score... two!
I'm gonna pick you off... one by one!
The GUND Format?!
That thing's a Gundam?!
We'll use Antidote.
Surround it and take it down.
Take this, witch!
Down you go, Gundam!
Permet score... four.
My heart's hurting so badly.
I can't... breathe.
I might throw up the snacks I just ate.
But...
I'm still alive!
The Antidote isn't working!
That thing only works up to score three!
The use of physical ammunition
is forbidden by treaty!
You bastards are polluting space!
You Spacians polluted Earth and ran.
You're one to talk.
Damn terrorists!
What a bother.
Bridge, the enemy forces
have been neutralized.
We'll proceed to securing the sub-gates.
More garrison forces will come soon.
Keep your guard up.
Tell the standby team in the rear.
We need to finish the job before
the front's communications are restored.
Move out.
It stopped.
I have to help Ms. Miorine.
But...
How?
Hangar 78...
If I have Aerial with me...
I can rescue Ms. Miorine!
Dad!
You have to... run.
Don't you dare!
You can't just die on me!
Choose the option with...
the best odds of survival.
That's what...
Notrette would do.
Why bring up my mother now?
We decided together.
If anything happened...
at least one of us...
should...
I don't want your excuses.
Why didn't you both escape?
Coward...
You could have just told me!
Machei, Jalil...
We're splitting up three ways.
Copy that!
Let's go.
It's no use. No signal...
What the hell is going on?
Bridge, we've lost target's tracer
and can't confirm location.
We'll continue forcing our way in.
How could they...
How could anyone do this?!
We have to run. It's dangerous here.
Run where?!
Suletta and Miorine aren't back yet.
Everyone, hurry!
I don't want to die!
Physical ammunition?
Don't tell me...
they're Earthians?
Any means of escape must be destroyed.
Is that our call sign?
An ally of the Prince?
Nika...
What did you... just do?
Sir, we've detected a ship
in the security airspace.
It's the one we sent
a warning to just before the attack.
Send the patrol fleet this way, immediately!
Good luck, sir.
Dilanza Sol... moving out!
Don't forget that
I worked my way up the ladder...
by personally claiming
my rivals' heads!
Four enemy mobile suits incoming
at starboard point F13.
They still have more?
Evade!
I'll make you regret ever crossing me!
Hey, the door!
Let's get out of here!
Wait, no!
Did you hear?
There's a Gundam in that plant.
From Asticassia, right? Sophie reported it.
What the heck is a Gundam?
Beats me...
Bob!
Hey, Bob!
Suletta Mercury...
Are you here?
In this plant?
What?!
Desultors?!
How dare you use my company's
mobile suits like this!
Hurry up with the refitting!
Hey, you!
What are you doing?!
Got to get to Plant Quetta!
Wait!
Stop! I'm not the enemy!
It's me, Guel Jeturk!
I can't die here.
I don't want to die!
Not when I...
I haven't moved forward
after Suletta Mercury!
I did it.
I did it!
It's me!
Vim Jeturk's son! Guel Jeturk!
I'm on your side--
Is that... Guel?
So you... were okay...
I've been... searching...
Dad...
Dad!
Eject, Dad!
I'll be right there!
Hangar 78...
This is it.
Bridge...
We've discovered what looks like a Gundam.
C Block, Hangar 78...
That's the Aerial! I'm going!
Sophie! This again?
That machine... Can you secure it?
Roger. We'll go ahead and--
Suletta?
Mom?
Are you okay?
Sorry about that.
You must have been scared.
Th-They... They're--
They're dead.
Nothing to worry about.
That's not what I...
You killed them!
If I hadn't...
They'd have killed you.
But that's...
If you run, gain one. Move forward, gain two.
Huh?
If I'd hidden behind the door,
I could have gained by not killing them.
But by fighting, I've kept you alive.
And one other thing...
If you fight together with Aerial, Suletta...
I can't.
It would mean...
That's right.
What's happening now is not a duel.
It's scary, right?
You don't want to get hurt, do you?
But...
If you and Aerial work together,
then Mom...
and Suletta...
and Ms. Miorine...
Everyone can be saved.
Saved?
Only the two of you can save them now.
Suletta, I know you're ready to move forward.
Right?
Yeah...
I can move forward.
I have moved forward.
If you run, gain one.
Move forward, gain two!
Hi there!
I've arrived...
Suletta Mercury!
The Aerial is here too, right?
Come on out!
Or are we playing hide and seek?
The Aerial...
Found you!
GUND-Bits?
Didn't your mother ever teach you?
You can't...
behave like that!
I knew it. You're the Aerial!
That's a scary face you've got.
If you ask me... I liked you better before!
Is she a Gundam too?
Hey, GUND-Bits again?
No fair!
Earth House... our ship... they're okay?
Thank goodness.
Norea, don't interfere!
I have to unless you stop fooling around!
Now's our chance. Everyone!
Olcott! Back off!
It's not meant for combat...
but it's still that powerful?
Incredible!
You've pierced right through my heart!
Oh my.
Only my bad feelings hit the mark.
We've reached our time limit.
Everyone back to the ship. We're leaving.
Huh?!
I'm not done having fun!
Do you want to mess with
the gung-ho Witch Hunters?
Is your life that precious, Norea?
That's not what I said.
Whatever.
I'll come visit you again...
Big Sister Suletta.
We've received a message
from the Dawn of Fold.
The operation failed.
Earthian Gundams, huh?
We'd better not get involved.
It's over....?
Right. It must be.
Found her!
I'm on my way...
Ms. Miorine!
I'll save you, no matter what.
So I can curse you all night
while you're in a hospital bed!
Found you, Delling Rembran.
Even if I can't get back to Earth,
I'm taking you down with me!
Ms. Miorine!
Damn it!
Oh no you don't!
I'm such a klutz.
I came to rescue you, Ms. Miorine!
How...
How can you smile like that?
Huh?
Murderer!