Ericht! Please! Don't do this!
Then don't get in Mom's way.
This is all for Ericht's sake...
so why did you come here?
Go back to the school with your friends.
This is a matter for those of us
who can only live inside the data storm.
So, Suletta...
You must give up.
No!
I can't turn a blind eye to you guys!
You're so stubborn, Suletta.
Stop it, Lauda!
Why are you trying to attack that ship?!
What about you, Brother...
Why are you by that woman's side?
Lauda?
If Miorine hadn't brought Gundams
back into the world,
Petra wouldn't have...!
Why the heck is Lauda attacking us?!
How should I know?!
Ms. Felsi!
We'll be caught up in the mess.
Nika! Chuchu!
Roger!
Let's go, Demi Barding!
Permet communications will be useless
within data storm space.
Change to optical wireless communications.
Right... Demi Barding,
now terminating Permet link.
We're gonna die!
We're all gonna die!
Mommy!
S-Sorry, everybody!
Is piloting without Permet
really this hard?!
Is this... the data storm?
This sensation is so unpleasant.
Hurry up and get us to Quiet Zero!
Who put you in charge, loudmouth!
Episode 23
Don't!
The Schwarzette...
the Gundam will take your life!
Then why don't you stop me by killing me?
Just like Dad?!
Answer me, Brother!
Why didn't you tell me about Dad?
Was it out of guilt?
Or did you think
I couldn't bear the burden?
Am I really that undependable?
That's not it.
What happened to Dad was my sin alone.
I'm the one who should bear it all!
That's what's wrong with you, Brother...
That's how Miorine takes advantage
of you, and why you cling to her!
That righteousness... That arrogance...
That's your sin!
A small craft is approaching.
It has a Benerit Group registration code.
It's emitting a communication signal.
It's alone?
I'll talk to them.
This is Guston Parche,
a Space Assembly League inspector.
I'd like to speak to operation HQ.
What can an inspector do
in this situation?
The corporate governance
is still intact with our group.
Delling Rembran?
In accordance with the League Charter,
we request the convening
of an emergency special session.
A special session?
Have all members
send their representatives
and reconsider if it was justifiable
to intervene in our group's affairs.
Mr. President...
I'm grateful... for your cooperation.
Stand down, Suletta.
I don't want to hurt you.
Neither... do I!
Then don't stop us.
Mom wants Eri to...
have a place in the world.
Is it okay to gobble up
all these fronts for that goal?
To take lives?!
Eri wouldn't do that.
But if they get in our way,
Mom won't hesitate!
That's why I want to stop her!
I don't want Mom...
to become some evil magician!
Please, Suletta...
Forget about us.
No!
I...
I care about you!
And Mom, too!
When Mom cries,
I want to be there to hug her!
I want to be by her side!
There's no way...
I could ever forget!
What a pity.
We're surrounded.
Ms. Miorine! Everyone!
If you don't understand, Suletta...
than I won't hesitate, either.
Ericht!
Please!
Stop it, Ericht!
The mobile suits...
...stopped?
What just happened?
Chuchu! Nika!
Okay!
Why?
Why do you interfere?
The data storm can make
our wishes come true!
Huh?
What caused it?
Data interference is occurring.
The data storm's information density
is degrading.
Where are you going?
To do pest control.
Captain, Assembly League HQ
is calling on a secure line.
Lagrange 1 has an interplanetary
laser power transmission system.
We'd like you to use it.
What about the special session
that Delling requested?
We've received no such request.
An interplanetary weapon
developed under the guise
of a power transmission system...
L1 Interplanetary Laser Transmission System
"ILTS"
I wonder, what if it were
to be mistakenly activated?
If we use that thing,
it'll devastate not just Benerit
but all of Lagrange 4.
Who'll take responsibility?
We will, of course.
To make up for
the Assembly League's blunder,
I imagine Lagrange 1's sovereign
government and corporate volunteers
will lead the rebuilding efforts.
And when the arbitration is over,
you promise that our company
will be in control of the Group.
Let's go. Follow me.
The data storm seems calmer in here.
Thank goodness!
Take this.
You've had training, haven't you?
I could never--
I can't very well hand it to a student.
Okay! Let's go punch in
that shutdown code.
W-Wait, Chuchu!
A Haro?
Intruders will be eliminated.
So this is...
a Gundam?
With this, I'm a match for my brother!
I can stop him!
I can stop the witches...
and Miorine!
Lauda! Why don't you quit this?!
Any further, and--
It's you who should wake up, Brother!
The crime of killing our father,
the crime of wounding Petra...
If you won't make that woman pay for it...
You're wrong! Listen to me, Lauda!
I will defend the honor
of the Jeturk name!
In place of my brother,
who is in thrall to a witch,
I will shoulder all of their sins!
I will... Lauda Jeturk will...!
You're Lauda?
I'm Guel.
Now I have a little brother!
I'm super happy.
Brother...?
You're right.
About Dad...
If everyone...
If you...
can't forgive me, I...
Brother! Run!
I'll... never run again.
From Dad or from you.
So at least...
Don't go piloting a Gundam anymore.
I'm sorry, Brother...
I'm sorry!
Just how stupid are you two?!
Felsi?!
Dying in a sibling spat?!
If that's a joke, it's not funny!
You said it...
It really wouldn't... be that funny.
Idiot! Lower your head!
Where the hell did you get that?
Hell, who cares?
Ms. Winston, take President Miorine
to the core block!
But...
Go, Miorine!
Go and finish the job!
As quickly as possible, please!
Let's go.
Let me take care of them.
Nobody will get killed this time.
Always rubbing it in...
In here.
Hurry up and shut it down.
I know, okay?
Let me try.
Why?
If that's the emergency shutdown code,
I took the liberty of changing it.
Did you think I was so careless?
Miorine is with Mom now.
If it's to gain one, Mom will...
No!
Then don't take away the place
where Mom and I can live freely.
Ma'am! Please stop this now!
Why?
Eri is the child blessed
by Vanadis's ideals.
Yet there's no place for her
in this world.
So I'll have to make one.
A place where Eri can be happy.
Eri, Eri...
Don't you care about Suletta at all?
I do love her.
But now she has friends like you.
Can you imagine how Suletta feels
aboard the Calibarn?
She was trembling with fear
that she might die.
But even so,
because she cares for you both...
because she loves you...
If you're a mother,
then love your daughters equally!
That's none of your business...
Hey! Are you trying to
reprogram it or something?
If I can get around the admin rights...
Now, be a good girl
and hand over those units--
I can't... keep running any longer...
I...
Hurry! Quick!
Shut up! I know, already!
There was an unknown message
in the genetic code.
When we converted it to text,
it turned out to be words.
I'll always...
love you too.
All for the love of my precious child.
A mother can be very strong, young lady.
Mom!
We have a signal!
Permet link established.
Commence calling.
Roger.
Now infiltrating
Quiet Zero's internal systems.
Mom!
Route everything to security!
It's no use. There's too much.
It stopped?
The data storm has dissipated.
Everyone is okay!
Yes!
Mission accomplished!
You're not so good at killing people.
Next time, try helping them instead.
"Move forward, gain two."
Those were your words, right?
Then do as you say and move forward.
You, Suletta, Ericht...
All of us... will be family, after all.
Quiet Zero has shut down.
Now if you could please leave us...
I'm afraid not.
You and your companies
have grown far too big.
Moving power transmission
preparation to Phase 5.
Array setup within error range.
Phase control systems, all green.
Targeting data,
trajectory prediction complete.
Interplanetary laser transmission system,
commencing test firing at high output.
No!
Eri! Stop that!
Everyone...?
Eri!
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam the Witch from Mercury,
Mobile Suit Gundam the Witch from Mercury
the final episode.
Illustration: Yana Toboso