Miorine Rembran,
I would like you
to take over the work of Quiet Zero.
Hell no! I won't be
a substitute for my lousy father.
Even if the originator was
Notrette Rembran?
My mother...?
How much do you know about data storms?
That's the source
of the Gundam's curse, isn't it?
For humans, at least.
But one aspect of the phenomenon
is that it can form
a hyper-dense information system
different from existing networks.
Hyper-dense...?
You've seen it with your own eyes.
Time and again, you saw Aerial
override her opponents during duels...
thanks to the same phenomenon.
So then Quiet Zero is...
A radical new network concept
that can use data storms
to control any system via Permet links.
Aerial is the trigger
that will activate it.
What the heck is that?
Does my lousy father want
to become a god or something?
Indeed. A most arrogant god.
However, I sympathized with his aims.
A world without the sadness
of conflict or loss.
I decided to give
the President my assistance.
That's why I sent Suletta to your school
and let her participate in duels.
I knew it! You're using Suletta for--
The child dreamed of going to school.
As a parent, I've made
every effort to realize that.
And as long as she fights in duels,
there's no worry she'll be killed.
The Asticassia School was the best
environment for Aerial's optimization.
Things were going smoothly.
Until the plant was attacked, that is.
Unless the President awakens,
we cannot proceed with Quiet Zero.
Worse, if the Group finds out,
the plan could even be shelved.
Aren't you afraid
I might leak all this?
I'm confident you wouldn't
since you haven't tried to escape here.
We can't allow your father's
greatest wish to be thwarted.
Can we?
Episode 14
GUND medical treatment?
How about some nutritious goat's milk?
I told you goat's milk wouldn't sell.
They don't know what they're missing.
Done!
Is it for her wounds?
She'll at least let us
do first aid, right?
She should've just told us
she had an accident working on Pharact.
Nika's always kept things from us.
She's told us nothing about herself.
Do you mind if I ask...
what happened between you,
Ms. Sophie, and Ms. Norea?
If I tell you,
I'll only bring more trouble on you.
I've brought it on you, too.
Trouble...
That's why...
I'm an orphan like them.
I don't know my own parents
or where I was born.
Stuck in a tiny room, I spent every day
assembling different components.
I'd always longed to go to school.
So when they told me
I could go to Asticassia,
I was really happy.
It felt like my dream had come true.
When you told me
it was your first time attending school,
I thought you were just like me.
I was just projecting myself onto you,
Suletta.
That's all.
Ms. Nika...
It's fine.
I'll take care of everything myself.
Suletta, you have to...
continue enjoying school.
Suletta!
Mr. Elan?
It's finally just the two of us.
I-I have to go
help with the event booth...
Don't worry about that.
More importantly...
I have to find out why you're avoiding me.
You're the one who changed
my solitary life,
and you also said
you wanted to know more about me.
So...
now I'd like you to give me a real sign
of your affection.
Big Sis!
Let's go there next!
M-Ms. Sophie, wait!
No way!
Too bad. You couldn't win her over.
Well, there's always next time.
Can a Gundam pilot
really count on a "next time"?
Peil Technologies has you on a leash,
idling your life away in a toy garden.
It's hard not to laugh.
Those eyes of yours...
They remind me of someone I used to know.
A pitiful guy who couldn't even
choose whether he'd live or die.
I heard he ended up dying all alone.
You're an irritating fellow.
You're pretty annoying yourself!
He was bothering you, wasn't he?
That guy grosses me out.
Mr. Elan isn't gross...
I've decided.
My stake in the duel...
If I win, you'll become
my real big sister.
"Real"?
That's right.
We'll become a real family.
Do that, and I'll refrain
from killing her, too.
I'm sorry, but... I have a bride.
A bride?
I made a promise to Ms. Miorine.
I'll stay at her side
and I'll never lose a duel.
So I have no choice... but to win.
Miorine... Miorine Rembran?
Delling's daughter,
and the president of GUND-ARM, Inc.
I get it. Miorine's the one
who keeps you confined.
If I kill Miorine, can I once again
see you like you were before?
What do you mean...?
This is the Dueling Committee.
Students participating
in the Rumble Ring...
I look forward to our duel.
...report to the 9th tactical testing sector.
Wait! The dueling vow!
All students participating
in the Rumble Ring...
We will now begin
our Open Campus special event,
the Rumble Ring!
The format will be
a battle royal-style duel.
The time limit is 30 minutes.
When a contestant's blade antenna
is broken, they're eliminated,
and the last pilot standing
will be the victor.
Participation is open to all.
It's an exhibition, after all...
so you won't be dishonored if you lose!
As of tomorrow, I'll officially become
CEO of Jeturk Heavy Industries.
My campus life ends here.
But before that happens...
we'll crush the Mercurian wench
who humiliated us and my brother!
Yeah!
Let's do it!
I've made sure your Dilanza
is in perfect condition, sir.
You can fight with all its strength!
Thank you, Petra.
Huh?
Pilots, board your mobile suits...
Renee, don't go off on your own.
Who do you think I am?
What about Nika and the transfer students?
There's no time.
Focus on the task at hand.
Container launch preparations complete!
Here we go!
We're counting on you, Elan!
This is a chance
to publicize GUND-ARM, Inc.!
Give it all you've got!
I could die
from giving it my all, you know...
What did she mean by "like I was before"?
And about killing Ms. Miorine?
Right.
If I win, I can save Ms. Nika.
And then I can talk to Ms. Sophie, too.
As witness, we are joined
by the CEO of Grassley Defense Systems,
President Sarius Zenelli.
Who ever thought...
I'd be Delling's surrogate?
KP014, Sabina Fardin.
LP013, Renee Costa.
Heindree... let's go!
LP017, Felsi Rollo.
KP013, Lauda Neill.
Dilanza... moving out!
MP039, Chuatury Panlunch. Demi Trainer.
KP002, Elan Ceres. Pharact.
LP041, Suletta Mercury...
Aerial, taking off!
What did you want to discuss, Bel?
Where did Ms. Sophie...
Suletta!
The mock battle's starting.
R-Right!
Let the Rumble Ring... start!
9th Tactical Testing Sector
Fight together until the Holder falls!
Right!
No double-crossing!
Mr. Elan?
I'll exterminate
these pesky insects for you.
How about a little reward,
like some private time for the two of us?
Our priority is taking out
the Aerial and Pharact!
Copy that!
How scary.
Back me up, please.
Huh?! Whoa!
You're in my way! Move!
Damn you!
Time to pay you back
for busting up my Demi Tray!
Is Chuchu feeling okay?
Get ready for our revenge match, Gundam!
Lauda Neill!
Who said you could butt in?!
You're mine!
You think you can keep up with me?
Everything's gone wrong
since you showed up.
Everything...
Every last bit of it!
Do you understand
what you've done, Mercurian wench?!
Mr. Lauda!
That mobile suit...
Lfrith Ur, Lfrith Thorn...
Beginning operation.
Those are...
The mobile suits from Plant Quetta.
Why are those terrorists here?!
Don't tell me... Nika!
Is this the front management company?
I have a confession to make.
I've...
That won't do.
You can't act selfishly
behind Shaddiq's back.
Ms. Sophie?
Now then, let's have our duel...
Big Sis.
Sir! Mr. Lauda!
Ms. Sophie... pilots that Gundam?
Sophie?
Looks like the other is Norea Du Noc...
Come on, let's finish
what we started then.
Each of us in our violent machines!
Huh? What the...
The outer wall is...
Haro?
Beam output beyond legal limit.
Front's protection mechanisms
cannot counteract.
You bastard!
How dare you butt in so rudely?!
And what about you?
How could an Earthian be so sloppy?!
Why would you aim for the cockpit?!
Those two don't have the campus
regulation program installed.
They're prepared for real combat.
Huh?
The front management
company hasn't come yet. Why not?
This is an emergency announcement.
The Rumble Ring is hereby canceled!
Everyone in tactical testing sector,
evacuate immediately!
What's going on?
How should I know?!
All you Spacians... are going to die!
No!
Suletta! Chuchu! Run!
Now!
Look at you, showing off...
We don't have much time. Let's move.
I'll use two of them for the duel.
Permet score... three!
Permet score three.
Reinforcements?
This time, I brought GUND-Bits of my own.
Let 'er rip, Gundvolvas!
No lifeform readings. Unmanned machines?
No one told me about those things!
Confirming launch
of GUND-Bits. Let's begin.
I'm terrible at acting, though!
Why haven't we evacuated?
This vehicle was damaged
in that last attack.
President Sarius!
We're arranging a backup vehicle.
Please be patient a little longer.
Pretending to be losing like this
is stressing me out.
Come on, now.
You wanted a duel, didn't you?
Fire at me some more!
Stop this, please! Everyone will die!
If you pilot a mobile suit,
people will die!
Didn't they teach you that at school?
Why use Gundams so wickedly?!
Because there are things I want!
Things you want?
Meals big enough to fill my stomach...
A fluffy bed to sleep on, warm showers!
There's still more!
Comics, video games, and also...
a family who will always love me!
This is wrong!
You can't kill others for...
I'll never forgive you.
If that's how you want it,
I'll just have to...
...kill you all myself!
Someone!
He's dying!
Mr. Lauda's going to die!
Go whine somewhere else,
you damn Spacian!
Raise your Permet score,
or you'll die next, Elen Ceres!
You must be kidding.
I changed my face just to stay alive.
There's no way I'm dying in vain.
If you're afraid to die,
ditch your Gundam!
You took too long!
Get the President to a secure... location.
What are you...?
Forgive us, sir. We have to detain you.
Shaddiq is waiting to see you,
Mr. President!
What's the meaning of all this?
Shaddiq!
Thank you for taking me
under your wing, Sarius Zenelli.
The operation is over.
Let's get out of here, Sophie.
Damn it...
She backed off? Why?
I see...
You must have them too,
Big Sister Suletta!
Things you want!
Things you'll fight to win!
Is it that bride of yours?
That woman Miorine?
You pilot that tool of murder for her?
Aerial is not a tool of murder!
Then why does Aerial have those weapons?
Who made it such a violent machine?
A-Aerial was built by my mom to...
By my mom to...
To do what?
I'll win the duel!
I'll crush Miorine, the school,
and everything else...
and then I'll let you
be my family, Big Sis!
Sophie!
Norea, stay back!
I can't control them.
She's taken over the Gundvolvas?
Now I see.
So that's it...
Sophie, you can't go any further!
I hear it.
I can feel it! The thrill from that day!
That beautiful voice
calling out to kill me!
Aerial's true nature?
With its eleven GUND-Bits,
Aerial's been controlling space itself
using the data storm.
And yet Suletta
is unaffected by the data storm.
Almost as if someone else
were controlling the GUND-Bits.
Why don't you just say it?
You had another daughter.
Where is Ericht Samaya now?
She's there.
Right at Suletta's side.
No! Aerial, stop!
Suletta! It wasn't you!
The one I wanted...
Stop it!
Beyond the data storm...
she's there waiting for us.
It can't be...
you turned a human into a mobile suit...
She's gained a new body.
Be glad for her.
Eri herself is the future of GUND
that we've been searching for.
Quiet Zero?
A project conceived by Delling Rembran.
We'll use the GUND Format
to eliminate war and conflict.
Lovely, isn't it?
Please tell me your true intentions.
You wouldn't need a Permet score that high
just to realize the President's plan.
I want to rewrite the world.
For what purpose?
So that Eri can be happy.
Ms. Sophie!
It's nothing to fret about.
Sophie died
before you could kill her.
I, too, will one day be killed
by the Gundam's curse.
And yet you weren't killed by it.
What the hell are you?
This is your last chance to surrender!
No kidding!
Visibly disarm yourself...
Sophie and Norea were...?!
...follow our instructions...
Where is Nika Nanaura?
...and exit your cockpit.
She's being arrested as a terrorist!
You Earth House students are coming too.
What?
What Ms. Sophie said must be wrong.
Gundams are supposed
to be mobile suits that save lives.
That's right.
I protected Ms. Nika,
Ms. Miorine, and the campus, too.
You and the others
helped me along, Aerial.
Move forward, gain two...
Just like Mom says!
Episode 15
Next time on
Mobile Suit Gundam: The Witch from Mercury
"Father and Child."
Illustration: lack