Shimamura is just Shimamura.
And she'll always probably
just be Shimamura in my heart.
I don't really get it,
but there's just a peace of mind.
Something that just gets my guard down.
It's a wonderful thing.
Shukoh... Shukoh...
Ah, so you did show up again today.
And who might this be?
She is the Shimamura.
What does that even mean?
Oho... So you're...
So, uh... What's your name?
Unlike my foolish compatriot,
I have come prepared with a name!
Please call me Yashiro Chikama.
I've come to Earth in search of my compatriot.
Compatriot...?
Compatriot? Oh, compatriot. Like a friend?
Wait, there's more of you?
Or rather, did you just say "Earth"?
My compatriot came to this planet on a mission,
but they haven't been back ever since.
So I had no choice but to search for them,
but it appears that I have landed
in the wrong location.
Alrighty, Shimamura.
You go ahead and enjoy talking
about the unknown with them.
What?!
Aha! I sense some fishies over there!
Hey!
Sneaky, sneaky, sneak.
Curse you, Hino. So the real reason
you invited me fishing was...
So I hear that your name is Shimamura.
Huh? Uh... yeah.
I hear that you're so popular that all
the locals come in droves to see you.
Yeah, I'm definitely not that Shimamura.
Ah, such modesty.
Oh, I have come from the future,
so I am not a local.
Just so we're clear.
Sure, and I've come from the past.
Nice to meet you.
You seem to be a typical earthling.
Yeah, I guess.
Why don't you take that thing off?
My face is not quite ready,
so I do ask for your patience.
What? Is your face going to be delivered
from the bread factory or something?
Shouldn't you be looking for your friend,
or rather, your compatriot?
Well, I'm hungry...
Is this something philosophical?
I have already confirmed
that my compatriot is safe,
so I figured I would take it easy.
So they contacted you?
Well, something like that.
If you're able to contact each other,
you can probably find each other...
And there is a reason that we cannot!
Shukoh... Shukoh...
I-I see.
Plop.
I can't seem to get a bite.
It's important that you realize that first...
Uh-huh...
You can't seem to get a bite.
Things aren't going as planned.
But that basically means
that you've started something.
You just felt like doing that?
Fishy!
Heck yeah!
All we can do from here
is wish for a bright future,
and cast our lines.
So, yeah... That happened.
Huh.
Was I that boring?
Not exactly.
Could you not say it like that?
Sorry, my bad.
Are you tired?
Well, I was pretty busy
at work yesterday.
Wait, you have a part-time job
somewhere? Where?
I'm not telling you.
Why, though?
Because you'd probably show up if I did.
Well, yeah.
No, it's embarrassing.
But it's not.
The fact that you're working is admirable.
Adachi once said that I was like a cat.
The fact that I keep my distance from others
makes me cat-like, apparently.
Though there is a part of me
that doesn't want to open up to people.
But Adachi's basically the same.
Adachi dozing off with her head on my lap
definitely reminded me of a cat.
What is it?
I think this is better.
Oh, really?
Because if I lay down this way,
I can smell you.
What?! Wait, do I have bad BO?
That's not what I meant.
Fine, I won't.
I think you lack elegance, Shimamura.
Elegance... Hm... Elegance, eh?
I don't think anyone's told me that before.
Say, Adachi.
Wanna actually go to class
with me this afternoon?
What brought that up?
Well, you know, attendance and such...
What I'm saying is, it'd be more fun if we both
made it as second-years together.
Together...
I guess it wouldn't hurt once in a while.
Okay!
Then, hey... Let's go somewhere
once classes are over.
Did you have other plans?
Not today...
Actually, I never really do.
I see.
Maybe I'll actually get a bite today.
School is its very own, unique society,
and if you brought that outside,
it confused things.
So I'm sure that some people would just
prefer to live out their lives at school.
That aside, I want to catch a bright future.
And for that to happen, I've got to
cast my line, or nothing will begin.
How were your classes?
Japanese history was fine, but I definitely
don't understand math anymore.
I've been to more classes than you and yet,
neither makes sense to me,
so where does that put me?
You seemed to get a lot of attention, Shimamura.
No, I'm pretty sure you did.
No, it was you.
It's probably because you're so pretty.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Well, this is the first time
anyone's ever called me pretty, so...
Really? Your boy... friend
doesn't call you that?
I've never had one.
Huh... I guess everyone must be blind.
Huh? Wait, where's your bike?
It's out for repairs.
Huh... So you actually
walked to school. Good job.
Well, I thought you'd be here, so...
Oh, right...
It's so sweet!
Are you going to classes tomorrow, Shimamura?
Well, I'm going to at least do my best
to go for more than three days.
I see.
What do you say, Miss Adachi?
Why don't we put in a little effort together?
I guess... I can try a little harder.
Want a bite?
Sure. Ah...
Right back at you.
Adachi? Oh, I see.
Here, there's some cream.
This is what you were waiting for, right?
Oh, uh, sure...
Where should we go after we eat?
Being with other people
seems to bring a little bit of pain.
Not understanding something.
Something being a pain.
Trying to mend relationships.
Putting in effort to find solutions.
But...
Sometimes a bit of happiness is rolling
around in between all that negativity.
Just like when you're a kid and you find
a tiny ball that you thought you'd lost,
I want to believe that
the fact that I met Adachi
is going to bring me a brighter future.
Um...
If it's awkward, I'll let go! Like right away!
It wasn't awkward. You just startled me.
Should I not then?
No, it's fine. Let's go.
Do you like being coddled, Adachi?
No...
"Pedestrian-Vehicle Separated Signal"
Well, I'm not...
...that surprised...
Shukoh... Shukoh...
Hello.
Oh, uh, hey...
I saw you here, so I thought I would say hi.
You really just walk around
in front of the station in that...
Well, this is my finest outfit.
I smell something exquisitely sweet
from your fingers.
Yes, this is quite nice. What is it?
Probably donuts, since I just ate some.
Donuts?
What are you doing?
Though I saw that coming...
There was a blip on my radar!
There're donuts in there, aren't there?
Yeah, but don't grab at it.
If you give me one of those d-donuts,
I shall reveal one of
the secrets of the universe!
Huh? This is for my little sister.
If they eat a donut, they'll take off
their helmet, and I can see their face.
Poik.
Okay, fine. You can have one.
Let's see... You can have this one.
Ah, so this is a donut.
Squeak, squeak, squeak, squeak...
Pshuu.
Munchy, munchy, munchy, munchy, munchy...
You're not taking off your helmet?!
Munchy... Gulp.
Plop.
Yes, this was nice.
It's very sweet!
- It's oh so sweet!
You've never heard of donuts before?
What kind of dance is that?
Do you have any more sweets?
Buy some yourself.
I have no money.
How do you survive?
Shimamura.
I'm going to get my bike.
Huh?
Later.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Wait, was she mad?
Would you like me to tell you what just happened
instead of one of the universe's secrets?
Sure...
She's mad because she didn't get a donut!
Go home.
I have no idea if this self-proclaimed person
from the future is going to
greatly change my life.
It's not like things usually change your life.
Because no one knows what the future holds.
You can't change it.
Man, relationships are hard...
I totally understand.
Understand what?
Apparently, Shimamura thinks
I'm prettier for some reason.
But she is greatly mistaken.
I'd say that Shimamura is way cuter.
Her dreamy eyes, the way
she modestly moves her lips...
My eyes keep looking at her face,
especially her lips.
I had a dream where I kissed Shimamura.
It's not like I'm into that.
I think I just want to be closer
with Shimamura...
But it's definitely not like that.
There's no deep meaning behind that kiss.
Nope! None!
I'm not saying I'd never kiss her...
But I'm not saying I absolutely want to, either?
If there was no one else within
a 5-kilometer radius from Shimamura,
and she was in a deep sleep and an all-knowing
deity just happened to reassure me
that she wasn't going to wake up
in the next 24 hours,
maybe I'd get bored
after 23 hours and I might
kiss her once to relieve some boredom...
Huh? Wait...
But I'm definitely not that.
I just want Shimamura to put me first.
I want Shimamura to think of me first
when she hears the word "friend."
I know that may sound a bit possessive...
To be quite honest, I've been wondering
how much of a friend
Shimamura actually sees me as.
Am I just like her other friends?
Or does she have other feelings for me?
"Sunday"
Welcom--
Huh?
Ah...
I told you it was embarrassing.
It's fine. It suits you.
Ah, a friend.
I don't see them much anymore at our house
since she entered high school.
Ah...
Really, don't worry about it.
Oho... Are you two in the same class?
Seriously.
Oh, come on.
Let's just order already.
I'll have tantanmen.
Then I'll have...
Apparently, Shimamura
doesn't really understand me,
but I could say the same about her.
She doesn't push me away when I rely on her,
but she doesn't try to rely on anyone herself.
That was how I saw Shimamura.
I thought you were finally shaping up,
and now look at you.
Who's that supposed to be?
Our teacher. They were asking me
where you were like I'd be able to answer.
What?
I was just thinking about how cute
you looked yesterday.
Huh? B-But you're cute, too, Shimamura...
Huh? It's not like I did anything.
Maybe I'll go there to eat again.
Don't. Please don't.
I'm kidding. I'm not sure if I want
to go again with my family...
It is sort of embarrassing
when you're with family--
Hey, it's Shimamura!
Huh? Oh, so you did come.
Can I sit next to you?
Uh, sure...
Um... You're... Right?
It's Adachi! Adachi.
You forgot her name but somehow
really thought whispering would work?
So, Adachi.
Good morning.
G-Good morning.
It's rare for you to eat school lunch.
I guess I don't hate this.
Well my dear maman slept in today.
Their noisiness isn't bad.
It reminded me of lunchtime in
grade school and was a bit nostalgic.
But it also felt like they were cutting
into my time alone with Shimamura.
I can't deny that I felt
that this didn't feel right.
Adachi, what are you going
to do about the afternoon?
Um... I plan to go to class... I think.
I see.
Shimamura...
I was wondering if I...
...could go to your house today.
This way.
Okay...
Welcome home, Big... Sis.
Hi...
Thanks. Oh, this is my friend. From yesterday.
Yeah...
Sorry...
Oh, don't worry.
She's a bit shy.
So your room's on the first floor.
Yeah.
You can sit wherever.
There we go.
So, what should we do?
Y-Yeah...
Say, Shimamura...
Hm?
Don't say it, don't say it, don't say it...
Um, do you mind if I sit...?
Huh?
Like... Between your legs...
What did I just say?!
Oh, my God. I'm a complete weirdo.
Sure.
Wait, it's okay?!
Wait, huh? I...
It's okay?
Is this a dream? Is it?
So it's okay?
Shimamura's legs...
What are you doing?
Well, I mean...
Huh?
There!
Huh? Hello?! What?!
Hm? Well, my little sister likes
to sit like this. Isn't this normal?
Y-Yeah, sure...
It's weird. It's super weird! My clavicle hurts!
Um...
What's up?
Do you have a boyfriend?
Usually, people feel pain in their chest,
but I'm feeling it in my bones.
Do you think I have one?
No...
You're right. Actually,
I told you that the other day.
My bones start grinding so much
that it feels like they're out in the open.
Did you?
Do you have one, Adachi?
I just want to relax...
I don't...
I see.
And I immediately figured out
how to do that.
I like... you, I think...
Wait, what?! What did I just try to say?
Did I say it? Wait, did I?!
I think... I like you, Shimamura.
Nope, I'm done for.
I can't... I'm an idiot.
This is... This is... This is...
I-I think I like you... Possibly, maybe...
You know, like... really like...
I'm a complete moron...
Um... You okay? Are you breathing?
Your face is like bright red...
What the efffffff...
What the efffffff?!
Ow! Ow, ow... My neck hurts. It hurts.
"Episode 2: Adachi Question"
Even if the sun were to set and rise again,
would tomorrow even come for me?
"Next Time: 'Isosceles Triangle'"
Adashimapedia: Aliens!
We are aliens.
Isn't it weird for aliens
to call themselves "aliens"?
That's actually a good point.
They should be more specific, like,
"We are boobliens. Let us fondle your ti--"
Time to force you aliens outta here.
We've been defeated...